<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<cards>
	<card>
		<headword>电子邮件</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4zi3 you2jian4"/>
		<defn>computing email</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>西餐</headword>
		<pron tones="xi1can1"/>
		<defn>Western Food</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>中餐</headword>
		<pron tones="zhong1can1"/>
		<defn>Chinese Food</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>西方人</headword>
		<pron tones="Xi1fang1ren2"/>
		<defn>1 Westerner 2 Occidental</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>东方人</headword>
		<pron tones="dong1fang1ren2"/>
		<defn>Orientales</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>早餐</headword>
		<pron tones="zao3can1"/>
		<defn>breakfast</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>午餐</headword>
		<pron tones="wu3can1"/>
		<defn>midday meal; lunch</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>晚餐</headword>
		<pron tones="wan3can1"/>
		<defn>supper; dinner</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>早饭</headword>
		<pron tones="zao3fan4"/>
		<defn>breakfast</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>午饭</headword>
		<pron tones="wu3fan4"/>
		<defn>midday meal; lunch</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>晚饭</headword>
		<pron tones="wan3fan4"/>
		<defn>supper; dinner</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>快餐</headword>
		<pron tones="kuai4can1"/>
		<defn>quick meal; fast food; snack 快餐部 kuàicānbù quick-lunch counter; snack counter</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>同学</headword>
		<pron tones="tong2xue2"/>
		<defn>1 be in the same school; be a schoolmate of sb. 我和他同过三年学。 Wǒ hé tā tóng guò sān nián xué. I studied in the same school with him for three years. 2 fellow student; schoolmate 3 a form of address used in speaking to a student</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>同事</headword>
		<pron tones="tong2shi4"/>
		<defn>1 work in the same place; work together 我们同事已经多年。 Wǒmen tóngshì yǐjing duō nián. We've worked together for years. 我和他同过事。 Wǒ hé tā tóng guò shì. He and I have been colleagues before. 2 colleague; fellow worker 老同事 Lǎo tóngshì an old colleague</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>同意</headword>
		<pron tones="tong2yi4"/>
		<defn>agree; consent; approve 我的意见你同意吗？ Wǒ de yìjian nǐ tóngyì ma？ Do you agree with me? 他同意这项建议。 Tā tóngyì zhè xiàng jiànyì. He consented to the proposal. 父母不同意我的婚事。 Fùmǔ bù tóngyì wǒ de hūnshì. My parents don't approve of my marriage. 征求对大使提名的同意 Zhēngqiú duì dàshǐ tímíng de tóngyì request for agreement to the nomination of an ambassador 表示同意前一位发言人的意见 biǎoshì tóngyì qián yī wèi fāyánrén de yìjian express agreement with the previous speaker</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>同岁</headword>
		<pron tones="tong2sui4"/>
		<defn>1 of the same age 我们两人同岁。 Wǒmen liǎng rén tóng suì. We two are the same age. 2 same as 同年 tóngnián</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>教练</headword>
		<pron tones="jiao4lian4"/>
		<defn>1 train; drill; coach 持枪教练 chíqiāng jiàoliàn drill with weapons 徒手教练 túshǒu jiàoliàn drill without weapons 2 coach; instructor; trainer 足球教练 zúqiú jiàoliàn football coach 教练兼队员 jiàoliàn jiān duìyuán playing coach 主教练 zhǔjiàoliàn head coach</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>开</headword>
		<pron tones="kai1"/>
		<defn>to open, to start</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>关</headword>
		<pron tones="guan1"/>
		<defn>1 shut; close 把门关上。 Bǎmén guānshang. Shut the door. 这扇窗户关不上。 Zhè shàn chuānghu guān bù shàng. This window won't shut. 2 turn off 关收音机 Guān shōuyīnjī turn (or switch) off the radio 关电灯 guān diàndēng turn off the light 3 shut in; lock up 别把孩子们整天关在屋里。 Bié bǎ háizi men zhěngtiān guān zài wū lǐ. Don't keep the children inside all day. 他昨天一天都关在书房里。 Tā zuótiān yī tiān dōu guān zài shūfáng lǐ. He was cooped up in his study all day yesterday. 关进监狱 Guān jìn jiānyù lock up (in prison); put behind bars 4 (of a business) close down 镇上关了好几家店铺。 Zhèn shàng guān le hǎojǐ jiā diànpù. Quite a few shops in the town closed down. 5 mountain pass; a guarded passage 玉门关 Yù mén guān the Yumen Pass 6 customs house ▶ 海关 hǎiguān 7 barrier; a critical juncture 大考是一关。 Dàkǎo shì yī guān. The final exam is a barrier to be passed. 只要突破这一关, 就好办了。 Zhǐyào tūpò zhè yī guān, jiù hǎo bàn le. Once we have got over this difficulty, it will be plain sailing. 8 a key factor ▶ 关键 guānjiàn 9 concern; involve 这不关他的事。 Zhè bù guān tā de shì. That doesn't concern him. 这些见解至关重要。 Zhèxiē jiànjiě zhì guān zhòngyào. These views are of extreme importance. 10 old give out or draw (pay) 关饷 guānxiǎng (of soldiers, policemen, etc.) get paid 11 (Guān) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>船</headword>
		<pron tones="chuan2"/>
		<defn>boat; ship</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>洗澡</headword>
		<pron tones="xi3zao3"/>
		<defn>have (or take) a bath; bathe 我刚洗完澡。 Wǒ gāng xǐ wán zǎo. I've just had a bath.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>走路</headword>
		<pron tones="zou3lu4"/>
		<defn>1 walk; go on foot 孩子已经学会走路了。 Háizi yǐjing xuéhuì zǒulù le. The baby has learned to walk. 你们是坐车去还是走路去？ Nǐmen shì zuò chē qù hái shì zǒulù qù？ Will you go there by bus or on foot? 过去打运动战, 走路的时间常多于作战的时间。 Guòqu dǎ yùndòngzhàn, zǒulù de shíjiān cháng duōyú zuòzhàn de shíjiān. In mobile warfare, we used to spend more time in moving than in fighting. 2 leave; go away</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>乘</headword>
		<pron tones="cheng2"/>
		<defn>to ride</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>摩托车</headword>
		<pron tones="mo2tuo1che1"/>
		<defn>motorcycle; motor bicycle; motorbike</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>巴士</headword>
		<pron tones="ba1shi4"/>
		<defn>bus (a transliteration)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>汉语水平考试</headword>
		<pron tones="Han4yu3 Shui3ping2 Kao3shi4"/>
		<defn>HSK (Chinese Proficiency Test)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>以前</headword>
		<pron tones="yi3qian2"/>
		<defn>before; formerly; previously</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>以后</headword>
		<pron tones="yi3hou4"/>
		<defn>after; afterwards; later; hereafter 全国解放以后 Quánguó jiěfàng yǐhòu after (or following) the liberation of the whole country 从今(那)以后 cóngjīn(nà)yǐhòu from now (then) on 至于以后怎么样, 我就不知道了。 Zhìyú yǐhòu zěnmeyàng, wǒ jiù bù zhīdao le. I don't know what happened later on. 会议今天开始, 大概一星期以后结束。 Huìyì jīntiān kāishǐ, dàgài yī xīngqī yǐhòu jiéshù. The conference begins today and will probably close in a week's time. 别着急, 以后你会有机会去的。 Bié zháojí, yǐhòu nǐ huì yǒu jīhuì qù de. Don't worry. You'll have a chance to go.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>季节</headword>
		<pron tones="ji4jie2"/>
		<defn>season 农忙季节 Nóngmáng jìjié a busy farming season 收获季节 shōuhuò jìjié harvest season; harvest time 旅游季节 lǚyóu jìjié tourist season</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>春</headword>
		<pron tones="chun1"/>
		<defn>spring</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>暖和</headword>
		<pron tones="nuan3huo5"/>
		<defn>warm</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>夏</headword>
		<pron tones="xia4"/>
		<defn>summer  1 the Xia Dynasty (c. 21st－c. 16th century B.C.) 2 an ancient name for China ▶ 华夏 Huáxià 3 a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>热</headword>
		<pron tones="re4"/>
		<defn>hot</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>秋</headword>
		<pron tones="qiu1"/>
		<defn>1 autumn 一九八五年秋 yī jiǔ bā wǔ nián qiū Autumn, 1985 秋雨 qiūyǔ autumn rain 2 harvest time ▶ 麦秋 màiqiū 3 year ▶ 千秋万代 qiānqiū-wàndài 4 a period of (usu. troubled) time ▶ 多事之秋 duō shì zhī qiū 5 (Qiū) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>凉快</headword>
		<pron tones="liang2kuai5"/>
		<defn>1 nice and cool; pleasantly cool 这里凉快, 坐下来歇会儿。 Zhèlǐ liángkuai, zuò xiàlai xiē huìr. It's nice and cool here. Let's sit down and have a rest. 2 cool oneself; cool off 咱们到树荫下面去凉快一下吧! Zánmen dào shùyīn xià miàn qù liángkuai yīxià ba! Let's sit in the shade and cool off a bit.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>冬</headword>
		<pron tones="dong1"/>
		<defn>winter 冬寒 Dōng hán winter cold  onomatope the sound of beating a drum, knocking at a door, etc.; rub-a-dub; rat-tat; rat-a-tat</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>冷</headword>
		<pron tones="leng3"/>
		<defn>cold  天气很~</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>公园</headword>
		<pron tones="gong1yuan2"/>
		<defn>park</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>游泳</headword>
		<pron tones="you2yong3"/>
		<defn>to swim</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>爬上</headword>
		<pron tones="pa2shang4"/>
		<defn>to climb up</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>滑冰</headword>
		<pron tones="hua2bing1"/>
		<defn>ice-skating; skating</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>雪</headword>
		<pron tones="xue3"/>
		<defn>snow</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>卫生间</headword>
		<pron tones="wei4sheng1jian1"/>
		<defn>toilet (room)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>洗澡间</headword>
		<pron tones="xi3zao3jian1"/>
		<defn>bathroom</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>厕所</headword>
		<pron tones="ce4suo3"/>
		<defn>lavatory; toilet; W.C.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>卧室</headword>
		<pron tones="wo4shi4"/>
		<defn>bedroom</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>教室</headword>
		<pron tones="jiao4shi4"/>
		<defn>classroom; schoolroom</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>阳台</headword>
		<pron tones="yang2tai2"/>
		<defn>balcony</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>客厅</headword>
		<pron tones="ke4ting1"/>
		<defn>drawing room; parlour; living room; sitting room</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>厨房</headword>
		<pron tones="chu2fang2"/>
		<defn>kitchen 厨房用具 chúfáng yòngjù kitchen (or cooking) utensils</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>房间</headword>
		<pron tones="fang2jian1"/>
		<defn>room 一套房间 yī tào fángjiān a suite; an apartment; a flat</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>太阳</headword>
		<pron tones="tai4yang2"/>
		<defn>1 the sun 太阳光 tàiyángguāng the sun's rays; sunshine; sunlight 2 the sun's rays; sunshine; sunlight 晒太阳 shài tàiyáng bask in the sun 今天太阳很好。 Jīntiān tàiyáng hěn hǎo. It's a lovely sunny day.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>月亮</headword>
		<pron tones="yue4liang5"/>
		<defn>moon</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>星星</headword>
		<pron tones="xing1xing5"/>
		<defn>informal star</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>远</headword>
		<pron tones="yuan3"/>
		<defn>far</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>近</headword>
		<pron tones="jin4"/>
		<defn>near; close</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>越来越…</headword>
		<pron tones="yue4lai2yue4…"/>
		<defn>more and more 越来越好 yuèláiyuèhǎo get better and better 发挥越来越大的作用 fāhuī yuèláiyuè dà de zuòyòng play an increasingly important role 天气越来越热了。 Tiānqì yuèláiyuè rè le. It's getting warmer and warmer. 越来越深入人心 Yuèláiyuè shēnrù rénxīn go deeper and deeper into the hearts of the people; become more and more popular</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>车站</headword>
		<pron tones="che1zhan4"/>
		<defn>station; depot; stop</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>总站</headword>
		<pron tones="zong3zhan4"/>
		<defn>terminus</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>差不多</headword>
		<pron tones="cha4bu5duo1"/>
		<defn>about the same/almost</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>超市</headword>
		<pron tones="chao1shi4"/>
		<defn>supermarket</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>超级市场</headword>
		<pron tones="chao1ji2shi4chang3"/>
		<defn>supermarket</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>广场</headword>
		<pron tones="guang3chang3"/>
		<defn>public square; square 天安门广场 Tiān'ānmén Guǎngchǎng Tian'anmen Square</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>机场</headword>
		<pron tones="ji1chang3"/>
		<defn>airport</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>市场</headword>
		<pron tones="shi4chang3"/>
		<defn>marketplace; market; bazaar 国内外市场 guónèiwài shìchǎng domestic and foreign markets 市场供应充足。 Shìchǎng gōngyìng chōngzú. There is an ample supply of commodities. 市场繁荣。 Shìchǎng fánróng. The market is brisk. 市场混乱。 Shìchǎng hùnluàn. The market is in a chaotic state. 市场价格 shìchǎng jiàgé market price 市场行情 shìchǎng hángqíng market quotation 市场机制 shìchǎng jīzhì market mechanism 市场经济 shìchǎng jīngjì market-oriented economy 市场调节 shìchǎng tiáojié regulation by market forces 市场业务 shìchǎng yèwù marketing functions 市场竞争日益加剧 shìchǎng jìngzhēng rìyì jiājù increasingly intense market competition 这种错误理论在群众中的市场越来越小。 Zhèzhǒng cuòwù lǐlùn zài qúnzhòng zhōng de shìchǎng yuèláiyuè xiǎo. This erroneous theory finds less and less support among the people.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>菜场</headword>
		<pron tones="cai4chang3"/>
		<defn>food market</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>植物</headword>
		<pron tones="zhi2wu4"/>
		<defn>plant</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>动物</headword>
		<pron tones="dong4wu4"/>
		<defn>animal 动物界 dòngwùjiè the animal kingdom</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>停车场</headword>
		<pron tones="ting2che1chang3"/>
		<defn>car park; parking lot; parking area</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>酒店</headword>
		<pron tones="jiu3dian4"/>
		<defn>1 wineshop; public house 2 hotel (used in names of hotels)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>金</headword>
		<pron tones="jin1"/>
		<defn>1 metals ▶ 五金 wǔjīn 2 money ▶ 现金 xiànjīn 3 ancient metal percussion instruments ▶ 鸣金收兵 míngjīn shōubīng 4 chemistry gold (Au) 5 golden 红底金字 hóngdǐ jīnzì golden characters on a red background 6 highly respected; precious ▶ 金口玉言 jīnkǒu yùyán 7 (Jīn ) a surname  the Jin Dynasty (1115-1234)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>五金店</headword>
		<pron tones="wu3jin1dian4"/>
		<defn>1 hardware store 2 ironmonger's store</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>食</headword>
		<pron tones="shi2"/>
		<defn>to eat</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>出生日期</headword>
		<pron tones="chu1sheng1ri4qi1"/>
		<defn>date of birth</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>前天</headword>
		<pron tones="qian2tian1"/>
		<defn>day before yesterday 前天晚上 Qiántiān wǎnshang the night before last</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>昨天</headword>
		<pron tones="zuo2tian1"/>
		<defn>yesterday  ~上午,  ~下午</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>今天</headword>
		<pron tones="jin1tian1"/>
		<defn>today</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>明天</headword>
		<pron tones="ming2tian1"/>
		<defn>tomorrow</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>后天</headword>
		<pron tones="hou4tian1"/>
		<defn>day after tomorrow  postnatal; acquired 知识是后天获得的, 不是先天就有的。 Zhīshi shì hòutiān huòdé de, bù shì xiān tiān jiù yǒu de. Knowledge is acquired, not innate.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>上个星期</headword>
		<pron tones="shang4ge4xing1qi1"/>
		<defn>last week</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>这个星期</headword>
		<pron tones="zhe4ge5xing1qi1"/>
		<defn>Esta semana</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>下个星期</headword>
		<pron tones="xia4ge4xing1qi1"/>
		<defn>next week</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>前年</headword>
		<pron tones="qian2nian2"/>
		<defn>the year before last year</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>去年</headword>
		<pron tones="qu4nian2"/>
		<defn>last year</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>今年</headword>
		<pron tones="jin1nian2"/>
		<defn>this year</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>明年</headword>
		<pron tones="ming2nian2"/>
		<defn>next year</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>后年</headword>
		<pron tones="hou4nian2"/>
		<defn>the year after next</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>上个月</headword>
		<pron tones="shang4ge4yue4"/>
		<defn>last month</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>这个月</headword>
		<pron tones="zhe4ge5yue4"/>
		<defn>Este mes</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>下个月</headword>
		<pron tones="xia4ge4yue4"/>
		<defn>next month</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>上</headword>
		<pron tones="shang4"/>
		<defn>to ascend; to go to  ~汉语课,  ~文化课</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>下</headword>
		<pron tones="xia4"/>
		<defn>below; next  ~星期,  ~星期三,  ~个月</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>前</headword>
		<pron tones="qian2"/>
		<defn>front; ahead; forward</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>后</headword>
		<pron tones="hou4"/>
		<defn>1 behind; back; rear 村前村后 Cūn qián cūn hòu in front of and behind the village 屋后 wū hòu behind (or at the back of) a house 2 after; afterwards; later 课后 kèhòu after class 3 last 后五名 hòu wǔ míng the last five (persons) 4 offspring ▶ 无后 wúhòu</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>左</headword>
		<pron tones="zuo3"/>
		<defn>left</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>右</headword>
		<pron tones="you4"/>
		<defn>left</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>外</headword>
		<pron tones="wai4"/>
		<defn>outside</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>里</headword>
		<pron tones="li3"/>
		<defn>dentro</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>东</headword>
		<pron tones="dong1"/>
		<defn>east</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>南</headword>
		<pron tones="nan2"/>
		<defn>south</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>西</headword>
		<pron tones="xi1"/>
		<defn>west</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>北</headword>
		<pron tones="bei3"/>
		<defn>north 城北 chéng běi north of the city 北屋 běiwū a room with a southern exposure 往北走 wǎng běi zǒu go north  formal be defeated 连战皆北 liánzhànjiēběi be defeated in one battle after another; suffer repeated defeats</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>现代</headword>
		<pron tones="xian4dai4"/>
		<defn>1 modern times; the contemporary age 2 modern; contemporary 现代交通工具 xiàndài jiāotōng gōngjù modern means of communication 现代作家 xiàndài zuòjiā modern (or contemporary) writers 现代题材 xiàndài tícái contemporary themes</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>直</headword>
		<pron tones="zhi2"/>
		<defn>1 straight 街道又宽又直。 Jiēdào yòu kuān yòu zhí. The streets are wide and straight. 把铁丝拉直 Bǎ tiěsī lā zhí straighten a piece of wire 2 straighten 直起腰来 zhí qǐ yāo lái straighten one's back; stand up straight 3 vertical; perpendicular 直行的文字 zhí xíng de wénzì characters written from top to bottom 这屋子直里有六米, 横里有三米。 Zhè wūzi zhí lǐ yǒu liù mǐ, héng lǐ yǒu sān mǐ. The room is 6 metres in length and 3 in width. 4 just; upright ▶ 正直 zhèngzhí 5 frank; straightforward 直认不讳 zhírènbùhuì admit frankly; own up readily 我就直说了。 Wǒ jiù zhíshuō le. I'll speak very frankly. 6 stiff; numb 天太冷, 手指都冻直了。 Tiān tài lěng, shǒuzhǐ dōu dòng zhí le. It was so cold that my fingers were frozen stiff. 7 vertical stroke (in Chinese characters) 8 adverb directly; straight 一直走 Yīzhí zǒu go straight ahead 直奔火车站 zhí bēn huǒchēzhàn head direct for the railway station 直通港口 zhítōng gǎngkǒu lead directly to the harbour 直飞北京 zhí fēi Běijīng fly nonstop to Beijing 9 adverb continuously 新井直往外喷油。 Xīn jǐng zhí wǎng wài pēn yóu. Oil gushed continuously from the new well. 他冻得直哆嗦。 Tā dòng de zhí duōsuo. He was so cold that he kept shivering. 这个故事逗得她直乐。 Zhège gùshi dòu dé tā zhí lè. The story tickled her fancy. 10 adverb just; simply 待他直如兄弟 Dài tā zhí rú xiōng-dì treat him just like a brother 疼得直像针扎一样 téng de zhí xiàng zhēn zhā yīyàng feel a piercing pain</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>课文</headword>
		<pron tones="ke4wen2"/>
		<defn>text (of a lesson)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>文章</headword>
		<pron tones="wen2zhang1"/>
		<defn>1 essay; article 2 literary works; writings 3 hidden meaning; implied meaning 话里有文章。 Huà lǐ yǒu wénzhāng. There is an insinuation in that remark. or That's an insinuating remark. 其中大有文章。 Qízhōng dàyǒuwénzhāng. There is a lot behind all this. See also 做文章 zuò wénzhāng</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>电院</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4yuan4"/>
		<defn>Cine</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>电影</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4ying3"/>
		<defn>film; movie; motion picture 有声(无声)电影 yǒushēng(wúshēng)diànyǐng sound (silent) film 彩色(黑白)电影 cǎisè(hēibái)diànyǐng colour (black-and-white) film 电影发行公司 diànyǐng fāxíng gōngsī film distribution corporation 电影放映队 diànyǐng fàngyìngduì film projection unit (or team) 电影放映网 diànyǐng fàngyìng wǎng film projection network 电影译制厂 diànyǐng yìzhì chǎng film dubbing studio 电影制片厂 diànyǐng zhìpiànchǎng (film) studio</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>比赛</headword>
		<pron tones="bi3sai4"/>
		<defn>match; competition 足球比赛 zúqiú bǐsài football match 自行车比赛 zìxíngchē bǐsài bicycle race 射击比赛 shèjī bǐsài shooting contest 象棋比赛 xiàngqí bǐsài chess tournament 比赛规则 bǐsài guīzé rules of a game; rules of a contest</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>事</headword>
		<pron tones="shi4"/>
		<defn>1 matter; affair; thing; business 没你的事。 Méi nǐ de shì. It's not your business. 这是怎么回事？ Zhè shì zěnme huí shì？ What's this all about? 2 trouble; accident ▶ 出事 chūshì 3 job; work 她找到事儿了。 Tā zhǎo dào shìr le. She's got a job. 4 responsibility; involvement 这件案子里还有他的事呢。 Zhè jiàn ànzi lǐ háiyǒu tā de shì ne. He was involved in the case too. 有我什么事, 干吗怪我？ Yǒu wǒ shénme shì, gànmá guài wǒ？ Why put the blame on me? It has nothing to do with me. 5 formal wait upon; serve 事父母 shì fùmǔ wait upon one's parents 6 be engaged in 不事生产 bù shì shēngchǎn lead an idle life</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>春夏秋冬</headword>
		<pron tones="chun1xia4qiu1dong1"/>
		<defn>1 the four seasons 2 spring, summer, autumn and winter</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>石头</headword>
		<pron tones="shi2tou5"/>
		<defn>stone; rock 石头砌的墙 shítou qì de qiáng a stone wall 心里好像一块石头落了地 xīnli hǎoxiàng yī kuài shítou luò le de feel as though a load has been taken off one's mind</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>往</headword>
		<pron tones="wang3"/>
		<defn>1 go 何往？ Hé wǎng？ Where are you going? 2 preposition in the direction of; towards; to 往东走去 wǎng dōng zǒu qù go in an eastward direction; go eastwards 劲往一处使 jìn wǎng yī chù shǐ all directing their efforts towards the same goal 从上海飞往香港 cóng Shànghǎi fēiwǎng Xiāng Gǎng fly from Shanghai to Hong Kong 往左拐 wǎng zuǒ guǎi turn to the left 汽艇往湖州开去了。 Qìtǐng wǎng hú zhōu kāi qù le. The motorboat is heading for Huzhou. 往前看 wǎng qián kàn look forward 3 past; previous ▶ 往事 wǎngshì</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>向</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang4"/>
		<defn>hacia</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>朝</headword>
		<pron tones="chao2"/>
		<defn>1 royal court; government ▶ 上朝 shàngcháo 2 dynasty 唐朝 Tángcháo the Tang Dynasty 3 (a sovereign's) reign 康熙朝 Kāngxī cháo the reign of Emperor Kangxi 4 an assembly held by a sovereign; court 早朝 zǎocháo a morning court held by a sovereign 5 make a pilgrimage to ▶ 朝圣 cháoshèng 6 preposition facing; towards 朝南走 cháo nán zǒu go southward 他背朝我站着。 Tā bèi cháo wǒ zhànzhe. He stood there with his back towards me. 这门是朝里开还是朝外开？ Zhè mén shì cháo lǐ kāi háishi cháowài kāi？ Does the door open inwards or outwards? See 朝zhāo</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>玩具</headword>
		<pron tones="wan2ju4"/>
		<defn>toy; plaything 玩具汽车 wánjù qìchē toy car 玩具汽枪 wánjù qì qiāng popgun 玩具店 wánjùdiàn toyshop</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>家具</headword>
		<pron tones="jia1ju5"/>
		<defn>furniture 几件家具 jǐ jiàn jiāju several pieces of furniture 一套家具 yī tào jiāju a set of furniture</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>附近</headword>
		<pron tones="fu4jin4"/>
		<defn>1 nearby; neighbouring 附近地区 fùjìn dìqū nearby regions 附近的城市 fùjìn de chéngshì neighbouring (or adjacent) towns 2 in the vicinity of; close to 住在工厂附近 zhù zài gōngchǎng fùjìn live close to the factory 附近有没有邮局？ Fùjìn yǒu méi yǒu yóujú？ Is there a post office near here? 就在附近, 几分钟就可走到。 Jiù zài fùjìn, jǐ fēnzhōng jiù kě zǒu dào. It's only a few minutes' walk from here.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>付</headword>
		<pron tones="fu4"/>
		<defn>1 hand (or turn) over to; commit to 付表决 Fù biǎojué put to the vote; take a vote on 付诸实施 fùzhū shíshī put into effect 2 pay 付房租 fù fángzū pay rent (for a house, flat or room) 付税 fù shuì pay taxes 票钱已经付了。 Piào qián yǐjing fù le. I've paid for the tickets. 
same as 副² fù</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>押金</headword>
		<pron tones="ya1jin1"/>
		<defn>cash pledge; deposit</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>暖气</headword>
		<pron tones="nuan3qi4"/>
		<defn>1 steam or water heat; central heating 2 central heating equipment 3 a warm gas; warm air</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>空调</headword>
		<pron tones="kong1tiao2"/>
		<defn>short for 空气调节 kōngqì tiáojié or 空气调节器 kōngqì tiáojiéqì</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>衣柜</headword>
		<pron tones="yi1gui4"/>
		<defn>wardrobe</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>电视</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4shi4"/>
		<defn>television; TV 看电视 kàn diànshì watch television 彩色(黑白, 立体)电视 cǎisè(hēibái, lìtǐ)diànshì colour (black-and-white, stereoscopic) television</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>冰箱</headword>
		<pron tones="bing1xiang1"/>
		<defn>icebox; refrigerator; freezer</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>沙发</headword>
		<pron tones="sha1fa1"/>
		<defn>sofa; settee 单人沙发 Dānrén shāfā (upholstered) armchair 三人沙发 sān rén shāfā three-seater settee</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>洗衣机</headword>
		<pron tones="xi3yi1ji1"/>
		<defn>washing machine</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>床</headword>
		<pron tones="chuang2"/>
		<defn>1 bed 小孩床 xiǎoháichuáng child's cot; baby's crib 躺在床上 tǎng zài chuáng shàng lie in bed 卧病在床 wòbìngzàichuáng take to one's bed; be laid up 2 sth. shaped like a bed ▶ 车床 chēchuáng , 河床 héchuáng 3 measure word (for bedding) 一床被子 yī chuáng bèizi one quilt 两床毯子 liǎng chuáng tǎnzi two blankets 三床铺盖 sān chuángpù gài three sets of bedding</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>费用</headword>
		<pron tones="fei4yong5"/>
		<defn>cost; expenses 生产费用 Shēngchǎn fèiyong production cost 这笔费用由我们负担。 Zhè bǐ fèiyong yóu wǒmen fùdān. We'll bear the expenses.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>桌子</headword>
		<pron tones="zhuo1zi5"/>
		<defn>table; desk</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>椅子</headword>
		<pron tones="yi3zi5"/>
		<defn>chair</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>书架</headword>
		<pron tones="shu1jia4"/>
		<defn>bookshelf; a set of bookshelves; bookcase</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>微波炉</headword>
		<pron tones="wei1bo1lu2"/>
		<defn>microwave oven</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>烤箱</headword>
		<pron tones="kao3xiang1"/>
		<defn>oven</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>电器</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4qi4"/>
		<defn>Electrodomésticos</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>环境</headword>
		<pron tones="huan2jing4"/>
		<defn>environment; surroundings; circumstances 换换环境 huàn huàn huánjìng have a change of environment 为环境所迫 wéi huánjìng suǒ pò be forced by circumstances 在艰苦的环境中成长 zài jiānkǔ de huánjìng zhōng chéngzhǎng grow up under tough conditions 环境顺利 huánjìng shùnlì under favourable circumstances 如环境许可 rú huánjìng xǔkě if circumstances permit 创造适宜的经济和社会环境 chuàngzào shìyí de jīngjì hé shèhuì huánjìng create a favourable economic and social environment 改善投资环境 gǎishàn tóuzī huánjìng improve the investment environment</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>安静</headword>
		<pron tones="an1jing4"/>
		<defn>1 quiet; peaceful 这个地方很安静。 Zhège dìfang hěn ānjìng. It is very quiet here. 安静的环境 Ānjìng de huánjìng tranquil surroundings 病人需要安静。 Bìngrén xūyào ānjìng. The patient needs peace and quiet. 保持安静! Bǎochí ānjìng! Keep quiet! 2 calm; undisturbed 周围安安静静的, 没有任何异常情况。 Zhōuwéi ān'ānjìngjìng de, méiyǒu rènhé yìcháng qíngkuàng. Everything around was still and quiet. Nothing unusual happened. 孩子们都已经安静地入睡了。 Háizi men dōu yǐjing ānjìng de rùshuì le. The children are all sound asleep. 3 quiet down 大幕一拉开, 观众顿时安静下来。 Dà mù yī lākai, guānzhòng dùnshí ānjìng xiàlai. As soon as the curtain rose, the audience quieted down.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>安全</headword>
		<pron tones="an1quan2"/>
		<defn>safe; secure 转移到一个比较安全的地方 Zhuǎnyí dào yī ge bǐjiào ānquán de dìfang move to a safer place 安全到达 ānquán dàodá arrive safely 保证安全生产 bǎozhèng ānquán shēngchǎn ensure safety in production 安全行车 ānquán xíngchē safe driving 安全正点 ānquán zhèngdiǎn safe and punctual running (of trains, buses, etc.) 安全操作 ānquán cāozuò safe operation 安全停车距离 ānquán tíngchē jùlí safe stopping distance 安全高度 ānquán gāodù safe altitude 安全措施 ānquán cuòshī safety measures 安全设施 ānquán shèshī safety devices 安全规程 ānquán guīchéng safety regulations 交通安全 jiāotōng ānquán traffic safety 安全第一! Ānquán dì-yī! Safety first!</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>吵</headword>
		<pron tones="chao3"/>
		<defn>1 make a noise 别吵! Bié chǎo! Don't make so much noise! 吵得慌 chǎo de huāng terribly noisy 瞧, 孩子被你们吵醒了。 Qiáo, háizi bèi nǐmen chǎo xǐng le. Look! You've woken the child. 别吵他。 Bié chǎo tā. Don't disturb him. 2 quarrel; wrangle; squabble 不要为一点小事就吵起来。 Bùyào wèi yīdiǎn xiǎo shì jiù chǎo qǐlai. Don't squabble over trifles. 我不跟他吵。 Wǒ bù gēn tā chǎo. I will not quarrel with him. 吵翻了天 Chǎo fān le tiān kick up a terrific row See 吵chāo</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>小说</headword>
		<pron tones="xiao3shuo1"/>
		<defn>novel; fiction</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>笑话</headword>
		<pron tones="xiao4hua5"/>
		<defn>1 joke; jest 说笑话 shuō xiàohua crack a joke 2 laugh at; ridicule 笑话人 xiàohua rén laugh at sb. 咱们一定要赢, 别让人笑话咱们。 Zánmen yīdìng yào yíng, bié ràng rén xiàohua zánmen. We must win the game, and not give others any chance to laugh at us. See also 闹笑话 nào xiàohua  看笑话 kàn xiàohua</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>排</headword>
		<pron tones="pai2"/>
		<defn>1 arrange; put in order 排座位 pái zuòwèi arrange seats 把课桌椅排整齐 bǎ kèzhuō yǐ pái zhěngqí put the desks and chairs in order 节目单已排好。 Jiémùdān yǐ pái hǎo. The programme has been arranged. 2 row; line ▶ 前排 qiánpái 3 measure word row; line 一排椅子 Yī pái yǐzi a row (or line) of chairs 4 military platoon 5 rehearse 剧团正在排一出历史剧。 Jùtuán zhèngzài pái yī chū lìshǐjù. The troupe is rehearsing (for) a historical play. 
raft ▶ 竹排 zhúpái , 木排 mùpái 
1 exclude; eject; discharge 排脓 páinóng discharge pus 把水排出去 bǎ shuǐ pái chū qù drain the water away 2 push 排门而出 pái mén ér chū push the door open and go straight out 
pie 苹果排 píngguǒ pái apple pie See 排pǎi</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>导演</headword>
		<pron tones="dao3yan3"/>
		<defn>1 direct (a film, play, etc.) 2 director</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>演员</headword>
		<pron tones="yan3yuan2"/>
		<defn>actor or actress; performer 挑选演员 tiāoxuǎn yǎnyuán choose the cast 演员表 yǎnyuánbiǎo the cast</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>过马路</headword>
		<pron tones="guo4ma3lu4"/>
		<defn>to cross the street</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>蛇肉</headword>
		<pron tones="she2rou4"/>
		<defn>Carne de serpiente</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>筷子</headword>
		<pron tones="kuai4zi5"/>
		<defn>chopsticks 竹筷子 zhú kuàizi bamboo chopsticks</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>中奖</headword>
		<pron tones="zhong4jiang3"/>
		<defn>draw a prizewinning ticket (or win a prize) in a lottery; get the winning number in a bond</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>卡</headword>
		<pron tones="ka3"/>
		<defn>1 block; check 卡住通往海港的公路 Kǎzhù tōngwǎng hǎigǎng de gōnglù block the road to the seaport 会计及时卡住了这笔不必要的开支。 Kuàijì jíshí kǎzhù le zhè bǐ bù bìyào de kāizhī. The accountant checked this unnecessary spending in good time. 2 clutch; choke 卡脖子 kǎ bózi seige sb. by the throat 
1 short for 卡路里 kǎlùlǐ 2 short for 卡片 kǎpiàn See 卡qiǎ</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>书法</headword>
		<pron tones="shu1fa3"/>
		<defn>penmanship; calligraphy</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>游览</headword>
		<pron tones="you2lan3"/>
		<defn>go sight-seeing; tour; visit 游览西湖 yóulǎn Xī Hú go sight-seeing on the West Lake 游览长城 yóulǎn Chángchéng visit the Great Wall</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>故宫</headword>
		<pron tones="gu4gong1"/>
		<defn>imperial palace</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>小学</headword>
		<pron tones="xiao3xue2"/>
		<defn>1 primary (or elementary) school 2 philological studies</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>中学</headword>
		<pron tones="zhong1xue2"/>
		<defn>middle school 初(高)级中学 chū (gāo) jí zhōngxué junior (senior) middle school 
Chinese learning (a late Qing Dynasty term for Chinese traditional learning) 中学为体, 西学为用 Zhōngxué wéi tǐ, xīxué wéi yòng Chinese learning as the fundamental structure, Western learning for practical use</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>初中</headword>
		<pron tones="chu1zhong1"/>
		<defn>short for 初级中学 chūjí zhōngxué</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>高中</headword>
		<pron tones="gao1zhong1"/>
		<defn>short for 高级中学 gāojí zhōngxué</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>大学</headword>
		<pron tones="da4xue2"/>
		<defn>1 university; college 2 The Great Learning See also 四书 sìshū</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>毕业</headword>
		<pron tones="bi4ye4"/>
		<defn>graduate; finish school 还有一年, 他就大学毕业了。 Háiyǒu yī nián, tā jiù dàxué bìyè le. He'll graduate from college next year. 他中学还没毕业就参了军。 Tā zhōngxué hái méi bìyè jiù cēn le jūn. He enlisted before he had finished middle school.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>硕士</headword>
		<pron tones="shuo4shi4"/>
		<defn>Master 硕士学位 shuòshì xuéwèi Master's degree</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>博士</headword>
		<pron tones="bo2shi4"/>
		<defn>1 doctor 哲学博士 zhéxué bóshì Doctor of Philosophy (Ph. D.) 张博士 zhāng bóshì Doctor Zhang 念博士 niàn bóshì study (or read) for a doctorate 2 history court academician</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>地球</headword>
		<pron tones="di4qiu2"/>
		<defn>the earth; the globe</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>队员</headword>
		<pron tones="dui4yuan2"/>
		<defn>team member</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>简历</headword>
		<pron tones="jian3li4"/>
		<defn>biographical notes; curriculum vitae; résumé</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>学历</headword>
		<pron tones="xue2li4"/>
		<defn>record of formal schooling; academic credentials</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>简体字</headword>
		<pron tones="jian3ti3zi4"/>
		<defn>simplified Chinese character</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>简单</headword>
		<pron tones="jian3dan1"/>
		<defn>1 simple; uncomplicated 简单明了 jiǎndānmíngliǎo simple and clear; concise and explicit 这机器构造简单。 Zhè jīqì gòuzào jiǎndān. The machine is simple in structure. 吃得很简单 Chī de hěn jiǎndān have simple food 生活得很简单 shēnghuó de hěn jiǎndān lead a simple life 事情没那么简单。 Shìqing méi nàme jiǎndān. There is more to it. 2 (usu. used in the negative) commonplace; ordinary 她的枪法那么准,真不简单。 Tā de qiāngfǎ nàme zhǔn, zhēn bù jiǎndān. She's a marvel to be able to shoot with such accuracy. 这家伙鬼点子特多, 可不简单。 Zhè jiāhuo guǐdiǎnzi tè duō, kě bù jiǎndān. This fellow is no simpleton. He is full of tricks. (see also 不简单 bù jiǎndān) 3 oversimplified; casual 简单粗暴 jiǎndāncūbào do things in an oversimplified and crude way 不能用简单的方法去解决这个问题。 Bù néng yòng jiǎndān de fāngfǎ qù jiějué zhège wèntí. This matter cannot be settled in a summary fashion. 这篇文章我只是简单地看了看。 Zhè piān wénzhāng wǒ zhǐshì jiǎndān de kàn le kàn. I only skimmed through this article.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>毕业生</headword>
		<pron tones="bi4ye4sheng1"/>
		<defn>graduate</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>外语</headword>
		<pron tones="wai4yu3"/>
		<defn>foreign language</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>爱好</headword>
		<pron tones="ai4hao4"/>
		<defn>1 take great pleasure in; have sth. as a hobby; be keen on 爱好音乐 Àihào yīnyuè like music 爱好京剧 àihào Jīngjù be keen on Beijing opera 爱好体育 àihào tǐyù go in for sports 2 interest; hobby 她的爱好是多方面的。 Tā de àihào shì duōfāngmiàn de. She has a wide range of interests. 你在文娱方面有什么爱好？ Nǐ zài wényú fāngmiàn yǒu shénme àihào？ What kind of recreation do you go in for?</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>性格</headword>
		<pron tones="xing4ge2"/>
		<defn>nature; disposition; temperament 性格开朗 xìnggé kāilǎng have a bright and cheerful disposition</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>性别</headword>
		<pron tones="xing4bie2"/>
		<defn>sexual distinction; sex</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>找工作</headword>
		<pron tones="zhao3gong1zuo4"/>
		<defn>buscar trabajo</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>给简历</headword>
		<pron tones="gei3jian3li4"/>
		<defn>entregar CV</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>面试</headword>
		<pron tones="mian4shi4"/>
		<defn>interview</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>收入</headword>
		<pron tones="shou1ru4"/>
		<defn>0 ingresos 1 income; revenue; receipts; earnings; proceeds 集体(个人)∼ jítǐ(gèrén)∼ collective (personal) income 副业∼ fùyè ∼ income from sideline occupations 财政∼ cáizhèng ∼ state revenue 总∼ zǒng∼ gross income 现金和粮食∼ xiànjīn hé liángshi ∼ income in cash and grain ∼和支出 ∼ hé zhīchū receipts and expenditures; revenue and expenditure 人均∼ rénjūn ∼ average per capita income ∼相当可观 ∼ xiāngdāng kěguān earn quite a handsome income 2 take in; include 修订版∼许多新词语。 Xiūdìngbǎn ∼ xǔduō xīn cíyǔ. Many new words and phrases have been included in the revised edition.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>收拾</headword>
		<pron tones="shou1shi5"/>
		<defn>1 put in order; tidy; clear away 把工具收拾一下。 Bǎ gōngjù shōu shi yī xià. Put the tools in order. 收拾屋子 Shōushi wūzi tidy up the room 收拾床铺 shōushi chuángpù make the bed 收拾碗筷 shōushi wǎn-kuài clear away the bowls and chopsticks; clear the table 2 get things ready; pack 收拾药箱 shōushi yàoxiāng get one's medical kit ready; pack one's medical kit 收拾行李 shōushi xínglǐ pack one's luggage; pack up one's things 咱们赶紧收拾收拾走吧。 Zánmen gǎnjǐn shōushi shōushi zǒu ba. Let's get our things together at once and be off. 3 repair; mend 收拾鞋子 Shōushi xiézi mend shoes 4 informal settle with; punish 早晚我们要收拾这个坏蛋。 Zǎo wǎn wǒmen yào shōushi zhège huàidàn. We'll settle with the scoundrel one of these days.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>肚子</headword>
		<pron tones="du4zi5"/>
		<defn>1 belly; abdomen 肚子疼 dùzi téng have a stomachache; suffer from abdominal pain 笑得肚子疼 xiào de dùzi téng laugh till one's sides split 一肚子气 yīdùzi qì absolutely exasperated; full of pent-up anger 2 a belly-shaped thing ▶ 腿肚子 tuǐdùzi See 肚子dǔzi</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>姑姑</headword>
		<pron tones="gu1gu5"/>
		<defn>informal father's sister; aunt</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>红萝卜</headword>
		<pron tones="hong2luo2bo5"/>
		<defn>1 carrot 2 radish</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>服务员</headword>
		<pron tones="fu2wu4yuan2"/>
		<defn>attendant</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>服务</headword>
		<pron tones="fu2wu4"/>
		<defn>give service to; be in the service of; serve 为人民服务。 Wèi rénmín fúwù. Serve the people. 服务周到 Fúwù zhōudao provide good service 提高服务质量 tígāo fúwù zhìliàng improve one's service 他在邮局服务了三十年。 Tā zài yóujú fúwù le sānshí nián. He served in the post-office for thirty years. 这个饭店的服务非常好。 Zhège fàndiàn de fúwù fēicháng hǎo. The hotel provides very good service.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>毛巾</headword>
		<pron tones="mao2jin1"/>
		<defn>towel 毛巾布 máojīnbù towelling 毛巾架 máojīnjià towel rail or rack</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>迟到</headword>
		<pron tones="chi2dao4"/>
		<defn>be (or come, arrive) late 迟到五分钟 chídào wǔ fēnzhōng be five minutes late 上班从不迟到 shàngbān cóngbù chídào never be late for work</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>班</headword>
		<pron tones="ban1"/>
		<defn>1 class; team 甲班 jiǎbān class A 作业班 zuòyèbān work team 班上有十五个学生。 Bān shàng yǒu shíwǔ ge xuésheng. There're fifteen students in the class. 2 shift; duty 三班倒 sānbāndǎo work in three shifts 今天晚上是我的班儿。 Jīntiān wǎnshang shì wǒ de bānr. I'll be on duty tonight. 3 military squad 4 measure word a a group of people 这班年轻人真了不起。 Zhè bān niánqīngrén zhēn liǎobuqǐ. They're a fine bunch of young people. b a trip by bus, boat, etc. 搭下一班火车 Dā xià yī bān huǒchē take the next train 一路公共汽车每隔三分钟就有一班。 Yī lù gōnggòng qìchē měi gé sān fēnzhōng jiù yǒu yī bān. There's a Number One bus every three minutes. 5 regularly-run; regular; scheduled ▶ 班机 bānjī 6 old used as part of the name of a theatrical troupe 7 move troops; withdraw troops ▶ 班师 bānshī 8 (Bān) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>挣钱</headword>
		<pron tones="zheng4qian2"/>
		<defn>earn (or make) money 挣钱餬口 Zhèngqián zhān kǒu earn a living 他挣的钱不够养家的。 Tā zhèng de qián bùgòu yǎngjiā de. His earnings are not sufficient to support his family. 她的两个儿子都挣钱了。 Tā de liǎng ge érzi dōu zhèngqián le. Her sons are both earning now.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>赚钱</headword>
		<pron tones="zhuan4qian2"/>
		<defn>make money; make a profit 赚钱生意 Zhuànqián shēngyi a profitable business; a paying proposition (or concern)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>工资</headword>
		<pron tones="gong1zi1"/>
		<defn>NOUN salary</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>变化</headword>
		<pron tones="bian4hua4"/>
		<defn>change; vary 气温的变化 qìwēn de biànhuà variations (or fluctuations) of temperature 我家乡有了很大的变化。 Wǒ jiāxiāng yǒu le hěn dà de biànhuà. Great changes have taken place in my home village. 他发球变化多端。 Tā fāqiú biànhuàduōduān. He's always changing his way of serving.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>丈夫</headword>
		<pron tones="zhang4fu5"/>
		<defn>husband</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>常常</headword>
		<pron tones="chang2chang2"/>
		<defn>adverb frequently; often; many a time; more often than not 她常常工作到深夜。 Tā chángcháng gōngzuò dào shēnyè. She often works far into the night. 他俩常常通信, 交换学术上的看法。 Tā liǎ chángcháng tōngxìn, jiāohuàn xuéshù shàng de kànfǎ. The two of them frequently write to each other, exchanging views on academic questions.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>时常</headword>
		<pron tones="shi2chang2"/>
		<defn>adverb often; frequently 我们时常玩儿牌。 Wǒmen shícháng wánr pái. We often play cards.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>经常</headword>
		<pron tones="jing1chang2"/>
		<defn>1 day-to-day; everyday; daily 经常工作 jīngcháng gōngzuò day-to-day work 经常开支 jīngcháng kāizhī running expenses 2 adverb frequently; constantly; regularly; often 领导干部一定要经常关心群众疾苦。 Lǐngdǎo gànbù yīdìng yào jīngcháng guānxīn qúnzhòng jíkǔ. Leading cadres must always have the well-being of the masses at heart. 这类问题是经常发生的。 Zhè lèi wèntí shì jīngcháng fāshēng de. This kind of problem frequently crops up. or This sort of thing is a common occurrence. 他经常上图书馆去。 Tā jīngcháng shàng túshūguǎn qù. He goes to the library regularly. 经常化 jīngchánghuà become a regular practice; make a practice of it</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>表姐</headword>
		<pron tones="biao3jie3"/>
		<defn>the daughter of one's father's sister or of one's mother's brother or sister, who is older than oneself; older female cousin; cousin</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>表弟</headword>
		<pron tones="biao3di4"/>
		<defn>the son of one's father's sister or of one's mother's brother or sister, who is younger than oneself; younger male cousin; cousin</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>表哥</headword>
		<pron tones="biao3ge1"/>
		<defn>the son of one's father's sister or of one's mother's brother or sister, who is older than oneself; older male cousin; cousin</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>表妹</headword>
		<pron tones="biao3mei4"/>
		<defn>the daughter of one's father's sister or of one's mother's brother or sister, who is younger than oneself; younger female cousin; cousin</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>渴</headword>
		<pron tones="ke3"/>
		<defn>1 thirsty 我有点渴了。 Wǒ yǒu diǎn kě le. I'm gettimg a little thirsty. 渴死了 Kě sǐ le be dying of thirst 这里有开水, 渴了请随便喝。 Zhèlǐ yǒu kāishuǐ, kě le qǐng suíbiàn hē. Here's some boiled water. Have some whenever you're thirsty. 2 yearningly ▶ 渴念 kěniàn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>饿</headword>
		<pron tones="e4"/>
		<defn>1 hungry 挨饿 ái'è go hungry 孩子饿了。 Háizi è le. The child is hungry. 可把我饿坏了。 Kě bǎ wǒ è huài le. I feel famished. or I'm starving. 2 cause to starve; starve 别饿着小猪。 Bié è zhe xiǎo zhū. Don't starve the piglets. 好好饿他一顿就好了。 Hǎohāo è tā yī dùn jiù hǎo le. He'll feel better if you let him miss a meal.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>刷牙</headword>
		<pron tones="shua1ya2"/>
		<defn>brush (or clean) one's teeth</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>林</headword>
		<pron tones="lin2"/>
		<defn>1 forest; woods; grove 松林 sōnglín pine forest 2 a group of persons or things ▶ 艺林 yìlín 3 forestry ▶ 农林 nónglín 4 (Lín) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>田</headword>
		<pron tones="tian2"/>
		<defn>1 field; farmland; cropland 犁田 lítián plough a field 在田里劳动 zài tiánlǐ láodòng work in the fields; work on the land 2 an open area abounding in some natural product; field ▶ 煤田 méitián 3 (Tián) a surname 
formal go hunting ▶ 田猎 tiánliè</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>水</headword>
		<pron tones="shui3"/>
		<defn>1 water 请给我一杯水,  Qǐng gěi wǒ yī bēi shuǐ, Give me a glass of water, please. 2 river 汉水 Hànshuǐ the Han River 3 a general term for rivers, lakes, seas, etc.; water 水陆运输 shuǐ-lù yùnshū land and water transportation 水平如镜。 Shuǐpíngrújìng. The surface of the water is as smooth as a mirror. 4 a liquid  ▶ 汽水 qìshuǐ , 药水 yàoshuǐ 5 extra charges or incomes ▶ 贴水 tiēshuǐ , 外水 wàishuǐ 6 measure word washing (of a garment) 这件衬衫洗了三水了。 Zhè jiàn chènshān xǐ le sān shuǐ le. This shirt has gone through three washings. 7 (Shuǐ) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>象</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang4"/>
		<defn>1 elephant 2 elephant, one of the pieces in Chinese chess (象棋) 
1 appearance; shape; image ▶ 景象 jǐngxiàng , 印象 yìnxiàng , 抽象 chōuxiàng 2 imitate ▶ 象声 xiàngshēng , 象形 xiàngxíng</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>草</headword>
		<pron tones="cao3"/>
		<defn>1 grass 羊在山上吃草。 Yáng zài shān shàng chī cǎo. The sheep are grazing on the hillside. 2 straw 草可以做饲料, 也可以造纸。 Cǎo kěyǐ zuò sìliào, yě kěyǐ zàozhǐ. Straw can be used both for fodder and for papermaking. 
1 careless; rough 这几个字写得太草。 Zhè jǐ ge zì xiě de tài cǎo. These characters are written in a sloppy hand. 2 same as 草书 cǎoshū 3 the running or cursive hand of a phonetic alphabet 4 draft ▶ 起草 qǐcǎo , 草拟 cǎonǐ 
informal female livestock or poultry ▶ 草鸡 cǎojī , 草驴 cǎolǘ</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>马</headword>
		<pron tones="ma3"/>
		<defn>1 horse 2 horse, one of the pieces in Chinese chess 3 big; large ▶ 马蜂 mǎfēng 4 (Mǎ) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>刀</headword>
		<pron tones="dao1"/>
		<defn>1 knife; sword 2 mechanics cutting tool; tool ▶ 铣刀 xǐdāo 3 sth. shaped like a knife 冰刀 bīngdāo ice skates 4 measure word one hundred sheets (of paper)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>鱼</headword>
		<pron tones="yu2"/>
		<defn>1 fish 两条鱼 Liǎng tiáo yú two fish 2 (Yú) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>网</headword>
		<pron tones="wang3"/>
		<defn>1 net 一张网 yī zhāng wǎng a net 捉蝴蝶的网 zhuō húdié de wǎng a butterfly-net 2 network ▶ 铁路网 tiělùwǎng 3 catch with a net; net 网鱼 wǎngyú net a fish 4 cover or enclose as with a net 眼里网着红丝 yǎnlǐ wǎng zhe hóng sī have bloodshot eyes</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>云</headword>
		<pron tones="yun2"/>
		<defn>cloud 
1 short for 云南 Yúnnán 2 a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>下雨</headword>
		<pron tones="xia4yu3"/>
		<defn>rain</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>石</headword>
		<pron tones="shi2"/>
		<defn>1 stone; rock 2 stone inscription ▶ 金石 jīnshí 3 (Shí) a surname See 石dàn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>火</headword>
		<pron tones="huo3"/>
		<defn>1 fire 这屋里有火。 Zhè wū lǐ yǒu huǒ. There's a fire in the room. 2 firearms; ammunition ▶ 军火 jūnhuǒ 3 Chinese medicine internal heat-one of the six causes of disease ▶ 败火 bàihuǒ 4 fiery; flaming ▶ 火红 huǒhóng 5 urgent; pressing ▶ 火速 huǒsù 6 anger; temper 心头火起 xīntóuhuǒqǐ flare up in anger 你怎么这么大的火儿？ Nǐ zěnme zhème dà de huǒr？ Why are you in such a temper？ 他火儿了。 Tā huǒr le. He flared up. 7 same as 伙 huǒ</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>竹子</headword>
		<pron tones="zhu2zi5"/>
		<defn>bamboo</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>龟</headword>
		<pron tones="gui1"/>
		<defn>tortoise; turtle ▶ 乌龟 wūguī See 龟jūn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>豕</headword>
		<pron tones="shi3"/>
		<defn>formal pig</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>虎</headword>
		<pron tones="hu3"/>
		<defn>1 tiger 幼虎 Yòu hǔ a tiger cub 2 brave; vigorous ▶ 虎将 hǔjiàng 3 dialect look ferocious 他突然虎起脸对我吼起来。 Tā tūrán hǔ qǐ liǎn duì wǒ hǒu qǐlai. He suddenly turned ferocious and shouted at me. 
same as 唬 hǔ See 虎hù</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>舍</headword>
		<pron tones="she4"/>
		<defn>1 house; shed; hut 牛舍 niúshè cowshed 2 humble my place 敝舍 bìshè my place 3 humble (used before relatives younger than or junior to oneself) my 舍弟 shèdì my younger brother 舍侄 shèzhí my nephew 
an ancient unit of distance equal to 30 li (里) See 舍shě</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>羊</headword>
		<pron tones="yang2"/>
		<defn>1 sheep 放羊 fàngyáng put sheep out to pasture; graze sheep 羊叫 yángjiào baa; bleat 2 (Yáng) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>花</headword>
		<pron tones="hua1"/>
		<defn>1 flower; blossom; bloom 一朵花 yī duǒ huā a flower 2 anything resembling a flower ▶ 火花 huǒhuā , 雪花 xuěhuā 3 fireworks 放花 fànghuā let off fireworks 4 pattern; design 白底红花 bái dǐ hóng huā red flowers on a white background 她织的花儿真好看。 Tā zhī de huā'ér zhēn hǎokàn. The pattern she knitted is really beautiful. 这被面的花儿很大方。 Zhè bèi miàn de huā'ér hěn dàfang. The design on this quilt cover is quite elegant. 5 multicoloured; coloured; variegated 花衣服 huāyīfú bright-coloured clothes 花蝴蝶 huā húdié variegated butterfly 小花狗 xiǎo huā gǒu spotted puppy 布染花了。 Bù rǎn huā le. The cloth is dyed unevenly. 6 flower-decorated; coloured ▶ 花篮 huālán 7 blurred; dim 看书看得眼睛都花了 Kàn shū kàn de yǎnjing dōu huā le read until the print looks blurred 8 fancy; florid; flowery; showy 你的字太花了。 Nǐ de zì tài huā le. Your handwriting is too fancy. 9 cream; essence 文艺之花 Wényì zhī huā the cream of literature and art 10 used metaphorically for women ▶ 姊妹花 zǐmèihuā 11 used metaphorically for courtesans or prostitutes ▶ 寻花问柳 xúnhuā-wènliǔ 12 cotton ▶ 轧花 yàhuā 13 smallpox ▶ 出花 chūhuā , 种花 zhònghuā 14 wound ▶ 挂花 guàhuā 15 (Huā) a surname 
spend; expend 花不少钱 huā bùshǎo qián spend a lot of money 很花时间 hěn huā shíjiān take a lot of time; be time-consuming</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>门</headword>
		<pron tones="men2"/>
		<defn>1 door; gate; entrance 校门 xiàomén school gate 炉门儿 lúménr a stove door 柜门儿 guì ménr a cabinet door 请走南门。 Qǐng zǒu nánmén. Please use the south entrance. 这扇门关不上。 Zhè shàn mén guān bù shàng. The door won't shut. 到会议厅得穿过好几道门。 Dào huìyìtīng děi chuān guò hǎojǐ dào mén. You have to pass through several doors to get to the conference hall. 2 valve; switch ▶ 气门 qìmén① , 电门 diànmén 3 way to do sth; knack 我到钢厂劳动了一段时间, 对炼钢摸着点门儿了。 Wǒ dào gāng chǎng láodòng le yī duàn shíjiān, duì liàngāng mō zhe diǎn ménr le. After working in the steel mill for a while I got an inkling of how steel is made. 4 family 张门王氏 Zhāng mén wáng shì Mrs. Zhang, née Wang 5 (religious) sect; school (of thought) ▶ 佛门 fómén 6 relating to the teacher ▶ 同门 tóngmén 7 class; category ▶ 分门别类 fēnmén-biélèi 8 biology phylum 亚门 yàmén subphylum 脊椎动物门 jǐzhuī dòngwù mén Vertebrata 9 computer gate “与”门 “yǔ”mén AND gate “非”门 “fēi”mén NOT gate 10 measure word a (for subjects of study, etc.) 两门功课 liǎng mén gōngkè two subjects; two courses 这门学问 zhè mén xuéwen this subject of study 你选了几门课？ Nǐ xuǎn le jǐ mén kè？ How many courses did you select? 掌握三门技术 zhǎngwò sān mén jìshù master three skills b (for cannons) 一门大炮 yī mén dàpào a piece of artillery; a cannon; a gun c (for a marriage) 一门亲事 yī mén qīnshì a marriage d (for relatives) 一门亲戚 yī mén qīnqi a set of relatives 11 (Mén) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>犬</headword>
		<pron tones="quan3"/>
		<defn>dog ▶ 警犬 jǐngquǎn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>女</headword>
		<pron tones="nü3"/>
		<defn>1 woman; female 女教师 nǚjiàoshī woman teacher 女医生 nǚyīshēng woman doctor 女售货员 nǚshòuhuòyuán saleswoman 女运动员 nǚyùndòngyuán sportswoman 女民兵 nǚ mínbīng militiawoman 女演员 nǚyǎnyuán actress 女英雄 nǚyīngxióng heroine 女飞行员 nǚ fēixíngyuán aviatrix 女职工 nǚzhígōng women staff members and women workers 女学生 nǚxuésheng girl student 2 daughter; girl ▶ 儿女 ér-nǚ 3 the tenth of the twenty-eight constellations (二十八宿) into which the celestial sphere was divided in ancient Chinese astronomy (consisting of four stars in the shape of a sieve in Aquarius)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>妈妈</headword>
		<pron tones="ma1ma5"/>
		<defn>informal ma; mum; mummy; mother</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>山</headword>
		<pron tones="shan1"/>
		<defn>1 hill; mountain 一座高山 Yī zuò gāoshān a high mountain 2 anything resembling a mountain ▶ 冰山 bīngshān 3 a bunch of straw in which silkworms spin cocoons 蚕上山了。 Cán shàngshān le. The silkworms have gone into the straw bundles to spin their cocoons. 4 gable 5 (Shān) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>弓</headword>
		<pron tones="gong1"/>
		<defn>1 bow 用弓和箭射鹿 yòng gōng hé jiàn shè lù shoot a deer with a bow and arrow 2 anything bow-shaped 弹棉花用的绷弓儿 tán miánhua yòng de bēng gōngr bow used to tease cotton 3 wooden land-measuring dividers 4 an old unit of length for measuring land, equal to five chi (尺) 5 bend; arch; bow 弓着背 gōng zhe bèi arch one's back; bend low 弓着腿坐着 gōng zhe tuǐ zuò zhe sitting with arched legs</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>放</headword>
		<pron tones="fang4"/>
		<defn>colocar</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>暑假</headword>
		<pron tones="shu3jia4"/>
		<defn>summer vacation (or holidays)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>寒假</headword>
		<pron tones="han2jia4"/>
		<defn>winter vacation</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>请假</headword>
		<pron tones="qing3jia4"/>
		<defn>ask for leave 请三天假 qǐng sān tiān jià ask for three days' leave 因病请假一天 yīn bìng qǐngjià yī tiān ask for a day's sick leave</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>打架</headword>
		<pron tones="da3jia4"/>
		<defn>come to blows; fight; scuffle</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>吵架</headword>
		<pron tones="chao3jia4"/>
		<defn>quarrel; have a row; wrangle 我跟他吵架了。 Wǒ gēn tā chǎojià le. I had a quarrel with him.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>机长</headword>
		<pron tones="ji1zhang3"/>
		<defn>aircraft (or crew) commander</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>船长</headword>
		<pron tones="chuan2zhang3"/>
		<defn>captain; skipper</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>班长</headword>
		<pron tones="ban1zhang3"/>
		<defn>1 class monitor 2 military squad leader 3 (work) team leader</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>校长</headword>
		<pron tones="xiao4zhang3"/>
		<defn>1 headmaster (of a middle or primary school); principal 2 president (of a university, college, etc.); chancellor</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>长大</headword>
		<pron tones="zhang3da4"/>
		<defn>grow up; be brought up 我长大了当医生。 Wǒ zhǎngdà le dāng yīshēng. I'm going to be a doctor when I grow up. 在红旗下长大 Zài hóngqí xià zhǎngdà be brought up (or grow up) under the red flag</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>算了</headword>
		<pron tones="suan4le5"/>
		<defn>1 forget about it; let it be 2 settled</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>坏了</headword>
		<pron tones="huai4le5"/>
		<defn>1 shoot! 2 gosh! 3 oh, no! 4 (suffix) to the utmost</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>工作经验</headword>
		<pron tones="gong1zuo4 jing1yan4"/>
		<defn>NOUN work experience</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>马上</headword>
		<pron tones="ma3shang4"/>
		<defn>adverb 1 at once; immediately; straight away; right away 我们马上动手。 Wǒmen mǎshàng dòngshǒu. We'll start working straight away. 你马上就走吗？ Nǐ mǎshàng jiù zǒu ma？ Are you leaving right away? 我马上就回来。 Wǒ mǎshàng jiù huílai. I won't be a minute. or I'll be back in a minute. 演出马上就要开始了。 Yǎnchū mǎshàng jiùyào kāishǐ le. The performance will begin in a minute. 马上集合! Mǎshàng jíhé! Fall in immediately! 2 in the near future; soon 工作没有结束, 他马上还不会走。 Gōngzuò méiyǒu jiéshù, tā mǎshàng hái bù huì zǒu. The work isn't finished yet, so he won't be leaving anytime soon. 马上就要高考了。 Mǎshàng jiùyào gāokǎo le. The college entrance examinations are coming up soon.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>计划</headword>
		<pron tones="ji4hua4"/>
		<defn>1 plan; project; programme 切实可行的计划 qièshíkěxíng de jìhuà a feasible (or workable) plan 宏伟的计划 hóngwěi de jìhuà a magnificent project 河流开发计划 héliú kāifā jìhuà a river development programme 有计划地进行 yǒu jìhuà de jìnxíng proceed in a planned way 计划外的商品 jìhuà wài de shāngpǐn goods produced over and above the plan 计划外项目 jìhuà wài xiàngmù projects outside the plan 2 map out; plan 计划好了再动手干。 Jìhuà hǎo le zài dòngshǒu gàn. Map it out before you start. 我们计划下周出发。 Wǒmen jìhuà xià zhōu chūfā. We plan to leave next week.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>来回票</headword>
		<pron tones="lai2hui2piao4"/>
		<defn>round-trip ticket; return ticket</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>惊喜</headword>
		<pron tones="jing1xi3"/>
		<defn>pleasantly surprised 惊喜地叫了起来 jīngxǐ de jiào le qǐlai call out in happy astonishment</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>加油站</headword>
		<pron tones="jia1you2zhan4"/>
		<defn>filling (or petrol, gas) station</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>饿死了</headword>
		<pron tones="e4si3 le5"/>
		<defn>VERB to starve to death</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>晴天</headword>
		<pron tones="qing2tian1"/>
		<defn>fine day; sunny day</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>打字</headword>
		<pron tones="da3zi4"/>
		<defn>typewrite; type</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>对了</headword>
		<pron tones="dui4le5"/>
		<defn>1 Correct! 2 Oh, that's right, ... (when one suddenly remembers sth one wanted to mention) 3 Oh, by the way, ...</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>难看</headword>
		<pron tones="nan2kan4"/>
		<defn>1 ugly; unsightly 这座楼房真难看。 Zhè zuò lóufáng zhēn nán kàn. This building is ugly. 他听到这个消息, 脸色变得很难看。 Tā tīngdào zhège xiāoxi, liǎnsè biàn de hěn nán kàn. When he heard the news, his face took on a ghastly expression. 2 shameful; embarrassing 咱们在音乐会上要是演奏不好, 那就太难看了。 Zánmen zài yīnyuèhuì shàng yào shì yǎnzòu bù hǎo, nà jiù tài nán kàn le. It would be a shame if we put on a bad performance at the concert.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>听众</headword>
		<pron tones="ting1zhong4"/>
		<defn>audience; listeners</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>观众</headword>
		<pron tones="guan1zhong4"/>
		<defn>spectator; viewer; audience</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>宽</headword>
		<pron tones="kuan1"/>
		<defn>1 wide; broad 宽肩膀 kuān jiānbǎng broad-shouldered 宽边草帽 kuān biān cǎomào broad-brimmed straw hat 眼界宽 yǎnjiè kuān have a broad outlook 这条马路很宽。 Zhè tiáo mǎlù hěn kuān. This road is very wide. 2 width; breadth 这条河有一里宽。 Zhè tiáo hé yǒu yī lǐ kuān. This river is one li wide. 3 relax; relieve 听说他的病情并不严重, 我们的心就宽多了。 Tīngshuō tā de bìngqíng bìng bù yánzhòng, wǒmen de xīn jiù kuān duō le. We were greatly relieved to learn that his condition was not serious. 把心放宽一点。 Bǎ xīn fàngkuān yīdiǎn. Relax, don't worry so much. or Don't take it too hard. 4 extend 限期能再宽几天吗？ Xiànqī néng zài kuān jǐ tiān ma？ Can the deadline be extended a few more days? 5 generous; lenient ▶ 从宽 cóngkuān 6 comfortably off; well-off 他手头比过去宽多了。 Tā shǒutóu bǐ guòqu kuān duō le. He's much better off than before.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>窄</headword>
		<pron tones="zhai3"/>
		<defn>1 narrow 窄道 zhǎidào narrow path 2 petty; narrow 心眼儿窄 xīnyǎnr zhǎi petty; oversensitive 3 hard up; badly off 父亲死后, 家里的日子过得挺窄。 Fùqin sǐ hòu, jiālǐ de rìzi guò de tǐng zhǎi. We were very hard up after my father died.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>贵</headword>
		<pron tones="gui4"/>
		<defn>1 expensive; costly; dear 这本书不贵。 Zhè běn shū bù guì. This book is not expensive. 丝绸比棉布贵。 Sīchóu bǐ miánbù guì. Silk is more expensive than cotton. 我买贵了。 Wǒ mǎi guì le. I paid too much for it. 2 highly valued; valuable 兵贵精, 不贵多。 Bīng guì jīng, bù guì duō. Troops are valued for their quality, not their number. 3 of high rank; noble 贵妇人 guìfùrén a noble lady 4 honorific your 贵国 guìguó your country 您贵姓？ Nín guìxìng？ May I ask your name? or What's your name, please? 5 (Guì) short for 贵州 Guìzhōu</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>便宜</headword>
		<pron tones="pian2yi5"/>
		<defn>1 cheap 便宜货 piányihuò goods sold at bargain prices 价钱相当便宜。 Jiàqian xiāngdāng piányi. It's a real bargain. or It's quite cheap. 2 unmerited advantages; unearned gains ▶ 讨便宜 tǎo piányi , 占便宜 zhàn piányi 3 let sb. off lightly 这次便宜了他。 Zhècì piányi le tā. This time we have let him off lightly. See 便宜biànyí</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>潮湿</headword>
		<pron tones="chao2shi1"/>
		<defn>moist; damp 这间屋子太潮湿, 不适宜住人。 Zhè jiān wūzi tài cháoshī, bù shìyí zhù rén. This room is too damp to live in.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>干燥</headword>
		<pron tones="gan1zao4"/>
		<defn>1 dry; arid 气候干燥 Qìhòu gānzào arid climate 大便干燥 dàbiàn gānzào constipated; costive 2 dull; uninteresting 干燥无味 gānzàowúwèi dry as dust; dull</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>干净</headword>
		<pron tones="gan1jing4"/>
		<defn>1 clean; neat and tidy 把院子扫干净 bǎ yuànzi sǎo gānjìng sweep the yard clean 他穿得干干净净的。 Tā chuān de gāngānjìngjìng de. His clothes are neat and tidy. 屋子收拾得挺干净。 Wūzi shōushi de tǐng gānjìng. The room is neat and tidy. 干干净净过春节 Gāngānjìngjìng guò Chūnjié give every place a thorough cleaning for the Spring Festival 不干不净, 吃了生病。 Bùgānbùjìng, chī le shēngbìng. Unclean food can make you ill. 2 complete; total 把谷子扬干净 Bǎ gǔzi yáng gānjìng winnow the grain thoroughly 忘得干干净净 wàng de gāngānjìngjìng have completely forgotten; clean forgot</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>脏</headword>
		<pron tones="zang4"/>
		<defn>internal organs of the body, usu. referring to the heart, liver, spleen, lungs and kidneys; viscera ▶ 心脏 xīnzàng See 脏zāng</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>新</headword>
		<pron tones="xin1"/>
		<defn>1 new; fresh; up-to-date 新技术 xīnjìshù new (or up-to-date) technique 新品种 xīn pǐnzhǒng a new variety 最新消息 zuìxīn xiāoxi the latest news 新社会 xīn shèhuì the new society 2 brand new; unused 新笔 xīn bǐ a new pen 新衣服 xīn yīfu new clothes 3 newly; freshly; recently 新建的工厂 xīnjiàn de gōngchǎng a newly built factory 新漆的门 xīn qī de mén a freshly painted door 他是新来的。 Tā shì xīn lái de. He's a new arrival. 这本书是我新买的。 Zhè běn shū shì wǒ xīn mǎi de. This is the book I've just bought. 4 recently married or just being married 新女婿 Xīn nǚxu a man newly married to one's daughter; daughter's bridegroom 新媳妇 xīnxífu a woman newly married to one's son; son's bride 5 (Xīn) short for 新疆维吾尔自治区 Xīnjiāng Wéiwú'ěr Zìzhìqū 6 (Xīn) the Xin Dynasty (8-23 A.D., between the Western Han and the Eastern Han)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>旧</headword>
		<pron tones="jiu4"/>
		<defn>1 old 2 opposite: new 新 3 former 4 worn (with age)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>预</headword>
		<pron tones="yu4"/>
		<defn>in advance; beforehand ▶ 预支 yùzhī 
same as 与 yù</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>乡</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang1"/>
		<defn>1 country; countryside; village; rural area ▶ 城乡 chéngxiāng 2 native place; home village or town 丝绸之乡 sīchóu zhī xiāng the home of silk 3 township (a rural administrative unit under the county)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>预报</headword>
		<pron tones="yu4bao4"/>
		<defn>forecast 天气预报 tiānqì yùbào weather forecast 商情预报 shāngqíng yùbào commercial prediction</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>转</headword>
		<pron tones="zhuan3"/>
		<defn>1 turn; shift; change 把全党工作重点转到经济建设上来 bǎ quándǎng gōngzuò zhòngdiǎn zhuǎn dào jīngjì jiànshè shàng lái shift the focus of the work of the Party to economic construction 转败为胜 zhuǎnbàiwéishèng turn defeat into victory 转弱为强 zhuǎnruòwéiqiáng transform (or grow) from weak to strong 晴转多云 qíng zhuǎn duō yún change from fine to cloudy; clear to cloudy 她转过头来和我说话。 Tā zhuǎn guò tóu lái hé wǒ shuōhuà. She spoke to me over her shoulder. 2 pass on; transfer 这封信请你转给他。 Zhè fēng xìn qǐng nǐ zhuǎngěi tā. Please pass the letter on to him. 把她的邮件转寄到她的新地址 Bǎ tā de yóujiàn zhuǎn jì dào tā de xīn dìzhǐ forward her mail to her new address 把钱从活期存款转为定期存款 bǎ qián cóng huóqī cúnkuǎn zhuǎnwéi dìngqī cúnkuǎn transfer the money from a current to a fixed deposit account See 转zhuàn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>窗户</headword>
		<pron tones="chuang1hu5"/>
		<defn>window; casement</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>可怕</headword>
		<pron tones="ke3pa4"/>
		<defn>fearful; frightful; terrible; terrifying 做了一个可怕的梦 Zuò le yī ge kěpà de mèng had a terrible dream 真可怕!他自杀了! Zhēn kěpà! Tā zìshā le! How dreadful! He committed suicide. 困难再大也没什么可怕的。 Kùnnan zài dà yě méi shénme kěpà de. However great the difficulties, there's nothing to be afraid of.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>如果</headword>
		<pron tones="ru2guo3"/>
		<defn>conjunction if; in case (of); in the event of 你如果要来, 请事先告诉我。 Nǐ rúguǒ yào lái, qǐng shìxiān gàosu wǒ. Let me know in advance if you're coming. 我们如果不加强学习, 就会跟不上形势。 Wǒmen rúguǒ bù jiāqiáng xuéxí, jiù huì gēnbushàng xíngshì. We can't keep abreast of the developing situation unless we study harder. 我明天再来, 如果你现在有事的话。 Wǒ míngtiān zài lái, rúguǒ nǐ xiànzài yǒu shì de huà. I'll come here tomorrow if you're tied up right now. 如果不是他指引的话, 我们就迷路了。 Rúguǒ bù shì tā zhǐyǐn de huà, wǒmen jiù mílù le. If it weren't for him, we would have gone astray. 如果发生火警, 拨120电话。 Rúguǒ fāshēng huǒjǐng, bō 120 diànhuà. In case of fire, dial 120. 如果下雨, 联欢会将在室内举行。 Rúguǒ xiàyǔ, liánhuānhuì jiāng zài shìnèi jǔxíng. In the event of rain, the party will be held indoors.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>海边</headword>
		<pron tones="hai3bian1"/>
		<defn>seaside</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>忘记</headword>
		<pron tones="wang4ji4"/>
		<defn>1 forget 我永不会忘记我们初次见面的那一天。 Wǒ yǒngbù huì wàngjì wǒmen chū cì jiànmiàn de nà yī tiān. I'll never forget the day we first met. 他紧张地工作, 忘记了去吃天饭。 Tā jǐnzhāng de gōngzuò, wàngjì le qù chī tiān fàn. He was working so hard that he forgot to go for supper. 2 overlook; neglect 不能忘记自己的责任。 Bùnéng wàngjì zìjǐ de zérèn. One mustn't neglect one's duties.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>世界</headword>
		<pron tones="shi4jie4"/>
		<defn>1 world 全世界 quánshìjiè the whole world 世界大事 shìjiè dàshì world events 世界冠军 shìjiè guànjūn world champion 世界纪录 shìjiè jìlù world record 2 Buddhism the universe ▶ 大千世界 dàqiān shìjiè 3 field; sphere; domain; realm 内心世界 nèixīn shìjiè a person's inner world 科学世界 kēxué shìjiè the domain of sciences 禽鸟世界 qínniǎo shìjiè the feathered world</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>空气</headword>
		<pron tones="kong1qi4"/>
		<defn>1 air 湿空气 Shīkōngqì moist air 山上空气稀薄。 Shān shàng kōngqì xībó. Up in the mountains the air is thin. 2 atmosphere 会场上空气紧张。 Huìchǎng shàng kōngqì jǐnzhāng. A tense atmosphere pervaded the meeting. 这里的政治空气很浓厚。 Zhèlǐ de zhèngzhì kōngqì hěn nónghòu. People here take a great interest in politics.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>污染</headword>
		<pron tones="wu1ran3"/>
		<defn>pollute; contaminate 这条河已为该厂的废水所污染。 Zhè tiáo hé yǐ wéi gāi chǎng de fèishuǐ suǒ wūrǎn. The river has been polluted by the waste water from that factory. 污染地带 Wūrǎn dìdài contaminated zone</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>阴天</headword>
		<pron tones="yin1tian1"/>
		<defn>an overcast sky; a cloudy day</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>雾</headword>
		<pron tones="wu4"/>
		<defn>1 fog 中午时分雾就散了。 Zhōngwǔ shífèn wù jiù sàn le. Around midday, the fog lifted. 2 fine spray ▶ 喷雾器 pēnwùqì</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>下冰雹</headword>
		<pron tones="xia4bing1bao2"/>
		<defn>granizo</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>打雷</headword>
		<pron tones="da3lei2"/>
		<defn>thunder 远处在打雷。 Yuǎnchù zài dǎléi. It's thundering in the distance.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>闪电</headword>
		<pron tones="shan3dian4"/>
		<defn>lightning</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>刮风</headword>
		<pron tones="gua1feng1"/>
		<defn>be windy</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>暴风雨</headword>
		<pron tones="bao4feng1yu3"/>
		<defn>rainstorm; storm; tempest 遇上暴风雨 yùshàng bàofēngyǔ be caught in a storm 革命的暴风雨 gémìng de bàofēngyǔ a storm of revolution; a revolutionary tempest 暴风雨般的掌声 bàofēngyǔ bān de zhǎngshēng thunderous applause</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>叙述</headword>
		<pron tones="xu4shu4"/>
		<defn>narrate (in speech or writing); recount; relate</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>进入</headword>
		<pron tones="jin4ru4"/>
		<defn>enter; get into 进入阵地 Jìnrù zhèndì get into position 进入决赛阶段 jìnrù juésài jiēduàn enter the finals 运动已进入高潮。 Yùndòng yǐ jìnrù gāocháo. The movement has reached a high tide. 中国社会主义建设进入了新的发展时期。 Zhōngguó shèhuìzhǔyì jiànshè jìnrù le xīn de fāzhǎn shíqī. China has entered a new stage of development in socialist construction.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>经过</headword>
		<pron tones="jing1guo4"/>
		<defn>1 pass; go through; undergo 这汽车经过动物园吗？ Zhè qìchē jīngguò dòngwùyuán ma？ Does this bus pass the Zoo? 经过长期磨练 jīngguò chángqī móliàn undergo a long process of tempering 2 preposition as a result of; after; through 经过充分讨论, 大家取得了一致意见。 Jīngguò chōngfèn tǎolùn, dàjiā qǔdé le yīzhì yìjian. After thorough discussion unanimity was achieved. 经过抢救, 病人脱离了危险。 Jīngguò qiǎngjiù, bìngrén tuōlí le wēixiǎn. The patient is out of danger after emergency treatment. 3 process; course 事件的全部经过 Shìjiàn de quánbù jīngguò the whole course of the incident; the whole process from beginning to end 事情的经过是这样的。 Shìqing de jīngguò shì zhèyàng de. This is how it happened.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>高考</headword>
		<pron tones="gao1kao3"/>
		<defn>(short for 高等学校招生考试) college entrance examination</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>打工</headword>
		<pron tones="da3gong1"/>
		<defn>dialect do manual work</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>得到</headword>
		<pron tones="de2dao4"/>
		<defn>get; obtain; gain; receive 得到及时治疗 dédào jíshí zhìliáo get timely medical treatment 得到群众的支持 dédào qúnzhòng de zhīchí enjoy the support of the masses 退休工人得到很好的照顾。 Tuìxiū gōngrén dédào hěn hǎo de zhàogu. Retired workers are all well provided for.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>奖学金</headword>
		<pron tones="jiang3xue2jin1"/>
		<defn>scholarship; exhibition</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>读</headword>
		<pron tones="du2"/>
		<defn>1 read; read aloud 这部小说值得一读。 Zhè bù xiǎoshuō zhíde yī dú. This novel is worth reading. 读报 dúbào read the newspaper aloud 老师读一句, 同学们跟着读一句。 Lǎoshī dú yī jù, tóngxué men gēnzhe dú yī jù. The students read after the teacher sentence by sentence. 2 attend school 读完大学 Dú wán dàxué finish college See 读dòu</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>国际</headword>
		<pron tones="guo2ji4"/>
		<defn>international 国际地位 guójì dìwèi international status (or standing) 国际合作 guójì hézuò international cooperation 国际问题 guójì wèntí international problem; foreign relations issue 国际形势 guójì xíngshì the international (or world) situation 国际影响 guójì yǐngxiǎng international repercussions; impact abroad 带有国际性 dàiyǒu guójìxìng have an international character</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>净出口</headword>
		<pron tones="jing4 chu1kou3"/>
		<defn>NOUN net exports</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>贸易</headword>
		<pron tones="mao4yi4"/>
		<defn>trade 和别国进行贸易 Hé bié guó jìnxíng màoyì trade with foreign countries; do business with other countries 贸易中心 màoyì zhōngxīn trade centre</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>当</headword>
		<pron tones="dang1"/>
		<defn>1 work as; serve as;</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>空时</headword>
		<pron tones="kong1shi2"/>
		<defn>tener tiempo libre</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>运动</headword>
		<pron tones="yun4dong4"/>
		<defn>1 motion; movement 运动的物质 yùndòng de wùzhì matter in motion 运动的形式 yùndòng de xíngshì form of motion 行星的运动 xíngxīng de yùndòng the movement of a planet 运动是物质的存在方式。 Yùndòng shì wùzhì de cúnzài fāngshì. Motion is the mode of existence of matter. 乘敌运动之际, 打击敌人。 Chéng dí yùndòng zhījì, dǎjī dírén. Attack the enemy while he is on the move. 2 sports; athletics; exercise 室外运动 Shìwài yùndòng outdoor sports 游泳是我喜爱的运动。 Yóuyǒng shì wǒ xǐ'ài de yùndòng. Swimming is my favourite sport. 散步也是一种运动。 Sànbù yě shì yī zhǒng yùndòng. Walking is also a form of exercise. 3 (political) movement; campaign; drive 竞选运动 Jìngxuǎn yùndòng election campaign 技术革新运动 jìshù géxīn yùndòng a drive for technological innovation</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>旅游</headword>
		<pron tones="lü3you2"/>
		<defn>tour; tourism</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>申请表</headword>
		<pron tones="shen1qing3biao3"/>
		<defn>application form</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>单身</headword>
		<pron tones="dan1shen1"/>
		<defn>1 unmarried; single 2 not be with one's family; live alone 单身在外 dānshēnzàiwài live alone away from home</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>名字</headword>
		<pron tones="ming2zi5"/>
		<defn>1 name or given name 您叫什么名字？ Nín jiào shénme míngzi？ What's your name? or May I know your name? 2 name (of a thing) 这种花的名字很特别。 Zhèzhǒng huā de míngzi hěn tèbié. This flower has a peculiar name.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>职业</headword>
		<pron tones="zhi2ye4"/>
		<defn>occupation; profession; vocation 从事各种职业的人 Cóngshì gèzhǒng zhíyè de rén people of all occupations 这里填上你的姓名、职业等等。 Zhèlǐ tián shàng nǐ de xìngmíng, zhíyè děngdeng. Put down your name, occupation, etc. here. 他的职业是医生。 Tā de zhíyè shì yīshēng. He is a doctor by profession. 我们的职业有保障。 Wǒmen de zhíyè yǒu bǎozhàng. Our jobs are secure.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>工作单位</headword>
		<pron tones="gong1zuo4 dan1wei4"/>
		<defn>an organization in which one works; place of work</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>住址</headword>
		<pron tones="zhu4zhi3"/>
		<defn>address</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>电话</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4hua4"/>
		<defn>1 telephone; phone 请别把电话挂上。 Qǐng bié bǎ diànhuà guà shàng. Hold the line, please. 他把电话挂了。 Tā bǎ diànhuà guà le. He's hung up. 2 phone call 打电话 dǎ diànhuà make a phone call; phone sb.; call (or ring) sb. up; give sb. a ring 他正在打电话。 Tā zhèngzài dǎ diànhuà. He's on the phone. 有你的电话。 Yǒu nǐ de diànhuà. There's a phone call for you. or You're wanted on the phone.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>国籍</headword>
		<pron tones="guo2ji2"/>
		<defn>nationality; citizenship 你是哪国国籍？ Nǐ shì nǎ guó guójí？ What's your nationality？ 他是中国国籍。 Tā shì Zhōngguó guójí. He has Chinese nationality (or is of Chinese nationality). 选择国籍 Xuǎnzé guójí choose one's nationality 保留中国国籍 bǎoliú Zhōngguó guójí retain one's Chinese citizenship 国籍不明的飞机 guójí bùmíng de fēijī an unidentified aircraft</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>婚姻状况</headword>
		<pron tones="hun1yin1 zhuang4kuang4"/>
		<defn>marital status</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>社会</headword>
		<pron tones="she4hui4"/>
		<defn>society; community 人类社会 rénlèi shèhuì human society 国际社会 guójì shèhuì international community 社会财富 shèhuì cáifù wealth of society; public wealth 社会地位 shèhuì dìwèi social position; social status 社会福利 shèhuì fúlì social welfare; public welfare 社会环境 shèhuì huánjìng social environment 社会基础 shèhuì jīchǔ social base; social basis 社会实践 shèhuì shíjiàn social practice</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>社会关系</headword>
		<pron tones="she4hui4 guan1xi5"/>
		<defn>1 human relations in society; social relations 2 one's social connections; relatives and friends 她有很多社会关系在海外。 Tā yǒu hěn duō shèhuì guānxi zài hǎiwài. Many of her relatives and friends are residing abroad.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>关系</headword>
		<pron tones="guan1xi5"/>
		<defn>1 connections; relations; relationship 夫妻关系 fūqī guānxi relations between husband and wife 家庭关系 jiātíng guānxi family connections 社会关系 shèhuì guānxi social connections 军民关系 jūnmín guānxi relationship between the army and the people 外交关系 wàijiāo guānxi diplomatic relations 两国间的友好合作关系 liǎng guó jiān de yǒuhǎo hézuò guānxi friendly relations and cooperation between the two countries 搞好关系 gǎohǎo guānxi build (or establish) good personal relations 他们两个人是什么关系？ Tāmen liǎng ge rén shì shénme guānxi？ What is the relationship between the two of them? 他们的关系不好。 Tāmen de guānxi bù hǎo. They are not on good terms. 她和上司的关系很好。 Tā hé shàngsi de guānxi hěn hǎo. She's well in with her superior. 发生关系 fāshēng guānxi have sexual relations with sb. (not as husband and wife) 2 relevance; bearing; influence; significance 这件事跟我没有关系。 Zhè jiàn shì gēn wǒ méiyǒu guānxi. This matter has nothing to do with me. 你回答的话跟他所问的我看不出有什么关系。 Nǐ huídá de huà gēn tā suǒ wèn de wǒ kàn bù chū yǒu shénme guānxi. I don't see any connection between your answer and his question. 这一点对今后工作关系重大。 Zhè yīdiǎn duì jīnhòu gōngzuò guānxi zhòngdà. This has an important bearing on our future work. 你上午去还是下午去,关系不大。 Nǐ shàngwǔ qù hái shì xiàwǔ qù, guānxi bù dà. It won't make much difference whether you go in the morning or in the afternoon. 3 (usu. used with 由于 or 因为 to indicate cause or reason) 由于时间关系, 就谈到这里吧。 Yóuyú shíjiān guānxi, jiù tán dào zhèlǐ ba. Since time is limited, I'll have to stop here. 4 credentials showing membership in or connection with an organization 党员调动工作时要转党的关系。 Dǎngyuán diàodòng gōngzuò shí yào zhuǎn dǎng de guānxi. When a Party member is transferred to another place of work, his Party credentials are sent there. 组织关系带来了吗？ Zǔzhī guānxi dàilái le ma？ Have you brought your membership credentials with you？ 5 concern; affect; have a bearing on; have to do with 农业关系国计民生极大。 Nóngyè guānxi guójìmínshēng jí dà. Agriculture is of vital importance to the nation's economy and the people's livelihood. 交通运输是关系到工农业生产的重要部门。 Jiāotōng yùnshū shì guānxi dào gōngnóngyè shēngchǎn de zhòngyào bùmén. Transport and communications play a very important part in industrial and agricultural production. See also 没关系 méi guānxi</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>称谓</headword>
		<pron tones="cheng1wei4"/>
		<defn>appellation; title</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>妻子</headword>
		<pron tones="qi1zi5"/>
		<defn>wife</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>儿子</headword>
		<pron tones="er2zi5"/>
		<defn>son</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>父亲</headword>
		<pron tones="fu4qin5"/>
		<defn>father</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>母亲</headword>
		<pron tones="mu3qin5"/>
		<defn>mother</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>年龄</headword>
		<pron tones="nian2ling2"/>
		<defn>age 他参军还不够年龄。 Tā cānjūn hái bùgòu niánlíng. He is too young to join the army. 从马的牙齿可以看出它的年龄。 Cóng mǎ de yáchǐ kěyǐ kànchū tā de niánlíng. You can tell a horse's age from its teeth. 年龄不饶人。 Niánlíng bù ráo rén. Age will show itself. or Age will tell.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>商人</headword>
		<pron tones="shang1ren2"/>
		<defn>businessman; merchant; trader</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>律师</headword>
		<pron tones="lü4shi1"/>
		<defn>lawyer; (British) barrister; (British) solicitor; (American) attorney 我想请个律师来打这场官司。 Wǒ xiǎng qǐng ge lǜshī lái dǎ zhè cháng guānsi. I'm trying to employ a lawyer to handle the case.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>导游</headword>
		<pron tones="dao3you2"/>
		<defn>1 conduct a sightseeing tour 2 tourist guide 3 guidebook 导游图 dǎoyóutú tourist map</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>旅行社</headword>
		<pron tones="lü3xing2she4"/>
		<defn>travel service; travel agency</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>特长</headword>
		<pron tones="te4chang2"/>
		<defn>what one is skilled in; strong point; speciality 他有什么特长？ Tā yǒu shénme tècháng？ What is he skilled in? 绘画不是他的特长。 Huìhuà bù shì tā de tècháng. Painting is not his strong point. 发挥每个人的特长 Fāhuī měi ge rén de tècháng give scope to everyone's special skill</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>眼睛</headword>
		<pron tones="yan3jing5"/>
		<defn>eye 她那双眼睛十分动人。 Tā nà shuāng yǎnjing shífēn dòngrén. Her eyes are very beautiful. 群众的眼睛是雪亮的。 Qúnzhòng de yǎnjing shì xuěliàng de. The masses are sharp-sighted. or The masses have sharp eyes.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>总是</headword>
		<pron tones="zong3shi4"/>
		<defn>always</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>时髦</headword>
		<pron tones="shi2mao2"/>
		<defn>fashionable; stylish; in vogue 时髦的服装 Shímáo de fúzhuāng fashionable clothes 赶时髦 gǎn shímáo follow the fashion</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>努力</headword>
		<pron tones="nu3li4"/>
		<defn>make great efforts; try hard; exert oneself 努力工作 Nǔlì gōngzuò work hard 努力发展生产 nǔlì fāzhǎn shēngchǎn actively expand production 为实现科学技术现代化而努力奋斗 wèi shíxiàn kēxué jìshù xiàndàihuà ér nǔlì fèndòu exert oneself in the struggle for the modernization of science and technology 尽最大努力 jìn zuì dà nǔlì do one's utmost; do the best one can 大家再努一把力。 Dàjiā zài nǔ yī bǎ lì. Let's make still greater efforts. 学好一门外语要作出极大的努力。 Xué hǎo yī mén wàiyǔ yào zuò chū jí dà de nǔlì. It takes great effort to master a foreign language. 努力办好广播, 为全中国人民和全世界人民服务。 Nǔlì bàn hǎo guǎngbō, wèi quán Zhōngguó rénmín hé quánshìjiè rénmín fúwù. Strive to do broadcasting work well and serve the people of China and the world.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>认认真真</headword>
		<pron tones="ren4ren4zhen1zhen1"/>
		<defn>ADVB earnestly</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>像</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang4"/>
		<defn>1 be like; resemble; take after 姐妹俩长得很像。 Jiěmèi liǎ zhǎng de hěn xiàng. The two sisters are very much alike. 这孩子像他父亲。 Zhè háizi xiàng tā fùqin. The child takes after its father. 像猛虎下山一样向敌人扑去 Xiàng měnghǔ xiàshān yīyàng xiàng dírén pū qù charge at the enemy like tigers dashing down a mountain 像雷锋一样全心全意为人民服务 xiàng Léi Fēng yīyàng quánxīnquányì wèi rénmín fúwù serve the people wholeheartedly as Lei Feng did 2 look as if; seem 像要下雨了。 Xiàng yào xià yǔ le. It looks like rain. 像是有人在敲门。 Xiàng shì yǒurén zài qiāo mén. It sounds like somebody's knocking on the door. 3 such as; like 像黄继光这样的英雄人物, 将永远活在人民的心里。 Xiàng huáng jì guāng zhèyàng de yīngxióng rénwù, jiāng yǒngyuǎn huó zài rénmín de xīnli. Heroes such as Huang Jiguang will always live in the hearts of the people. 4 likeness (of sb.); portrait; picture ▶ 画像 huàxiàng , 铜像 tóngxiàng 5 physics image 虚像 xūxiàng virtual image 实像 shíxiàng real image</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>个子</headword>
		<pron tones="ge4zi5"/>
		<defn>height; stature; build 高个子 gāogèzi a tall person 小个子 xiǎogèzi a small fellow; a short person</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>头发</headword>
		<pron tones="tou2fa5"/>
		<defn>hair (on the human head)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>抽烟</headword>
		<pron tones="chou1yan1"/>
		<defn>smoke (a cigarette or a pipe) 你抽烟吗？ Nǐ chōuyān ma？ Do you smoke? 请抽烟。 Qǐng chōuyān. Have a smoke. 抽一袋烟 Chōu yī dài yān smoke a pipe</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>小偷</headword>
		<pron tones="xiao3tou1"/>
		<defn>petty (or sneak) thief; pilferer</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>向南</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang4nan2"/>
		<defn>southward</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>热情</headword>
		<pron tones="re4qing2"/>
		<defn>1 enthusiasm; zeal; warmth 爱国热情 Àiguó rèqíng patriotic zeal 工作热情 gōngzuò rèqíng enthusiasm for work 他充满热情地陈述了自己的意见。 Tā chōngmǎn rèqíng de chénshù le zìjǐ de yìjian. He expressed his views with a great deal of warmth. 2 warm; fervent; enthusiastic; warmhearted 热情接待 Rèqíng jiēdài warmly receive; give sb. a warm reception 热情支持这个倡议 rèqíng zhīchí zhège chàngyì fervently (or enthusiastically) support this proposal 对旅客非常热情 duì lǚkè fēicháng rèqíng be very warm towards the passengers 热情的字句 rèqíng de zìjù warm words 他十分爽直热情。 Tā shífēn shuǎngzhí rèqíng. He is very frank and warmhearted.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>旁边</headword>
		<pron tones="pang2bian1"/>
		<defn>side 我坐在他旁边。 Wǒ zuò zài tā pángbiān. I sat by his side. 旁边有一棵树。 Pángbiān yǒu yī kē shù. There is a tree nearby.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>欢迎</headword>
		<pron tones="huan1ying2"/>
		<defn>1 welcome; greet 欢迎大家批评 huānyíng dàjiā pīpíng Criticisms are welcome. 我们受到了非常热烈的欢迎。 Wǒmen shòudào le fēicháng rèliè de huānyíng. We received a very warm welcome. 欢迎您到北京来! Huānyíng nín dào Běijīng lái! Welcome to Beijing! 到机场欢迎贵宾 Dào jīchǎng huānyíng guìbīn meet distinguished guests at the airport 欢迎老王给我们唱个歌! Huānyíng lǎo wáng gěi wǒmen chàng ge gē! Let's ask Lao Wang to sing us a song! 欢迎词 huānyíngcí welcoming speech; address of welcome 欢迎会 huānyínghuì a party (or meeting) to welcome sb. 2 be well received 这部电影深受群众欢迎。 Zhè bù diànyǐng shēnshòu qúnzhòng huānyíng. The film has been well received by the people.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>困难</headword>
		<pron tones="kun4nan5"/>
		<defn>1 difficulty 情况十分困难。 Qíngkuàng shífēn kùnnan. Conditions are very difficult. 山上空气稀薄, 呼吸很困难。 Shān shàng kōngqì xībó, hūxī hěn kùnnan. Up in the mountains the air is thin and breathing is difficult. 困难重重 kùnnanchóngchóng be beset with difficulties 2 financial difficulties; straitened circumstances 生活困难 shēnghuó kùnnan live in straitened circumstances 困难户 kùnnanhù families with financial (or material) difficulties 他三岁时死了父亲, 家里更困难了。 Tā sān suì shí sǐ le fùqin, jiālǐ gèng kùnnan le. The boy's family has been much worse off since his father died when he was three.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>认真</headword>
		<pron tones="ren4zhen1"/>
		<defn>conscientious; earnest; serious 认真对待 rènzhēn duìdài deal seriously with 给予认真的考虑 jǐyǔ rènzhēn de kǎolǜ give serious consideration to 认真的自我批评 rènzhēn de zìwǒ pīpíng an earnest self-criticism 他干什么都认真。 Tā gàn shénme dōu rènzhēn. He is very conscientious in whatever he does. or He's a conscientious worker. 办事不认真 Bàn shì bù rènzhēn work half-heartedly 进行认真的研究 jìnxíng rènzhēn de yánjiū make a serious study 
take seriouly; take to heart 我是说着玩儿的, 你怎么就认起真来了？ Wǒ shì shuō zhe wánr de, nǐ zěnme jiù rèn qǐ zhēn lái le？ I was only joking. Why take it seriously (or to heart)?</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>解释</headword>
		<pron tones="jie3shi4"/>
		<defn>explain; expound; interpret 解释一个新词 jiěshì yī ge xīncí explain a new word 解释法律 jiěshì fǎlǜ interpret laws 河水的流动可以用重力原理来解释。 Héshuǐ de liúdòng kěyǐ yòng zhònglì yuánlǐ lái jiěshì. The flow of water in a river is explained by the principle of gravity. 对这件事你作何解释？ Duì zhè jiàn shì nǐ zuò hé jiěshì？ How do you account for this? 这些事实不能有别的解释。 Zhèxiē shìshí bù néng yǒu bié de jiěshì. The facts admit of no other explanation. 这是误会, 解释一下就行了。 Zhè shì wùhuì, jiěshì yīxià jiù xíng le. This is a misunderstanding. A little explanation will clear it up. 你应该虚心听取同志们的批评, 不要老是解释。 Nǐ yīnggāi xūxīn tīngqǔ tóngzhì men de pīpíng, bùyào lǎoshi jiěshì. You should listen carefully to the criticism of the comrades and not keep trying to explain things away. 对本协定在解释上遇有分歧, 应以中文本为准。 Duì běn xiédìng zài jiěshì shàng yù yǒu fēnqí, yīng yǐ zhōng wénběn wéi zhǔn. In case there is any divergence of interpretation of this agreement, the Chinese text shall prevail.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>功课</headword>
		<pron tones="gong1ke4"/>
		<defn>1 schoolwork; homework 做功课 zuò gōngkè do homework 2 a school subject 他在学校里门门功课都很好。 Tā zài xuéxiào lǐ mén mén gōngkè dōu hěn hǎo. He does well in every subject at school.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>满意</headword>
		<pron tones="man3yi4"/>
		<defn>satisfied; pleased; content 双方对会谈的结果表示满意。 Shuāngfāng duì huìtán de jiéguǒ biǎoshì mǎnyì. Both sides expressed satisfaction with the results of the talks. 大家对他的工作很满意。 Dàjiā duì tā de gōngzuò hěn mǎnyì. Everyone was pleased with his work. 我妻子不满意我给她照的像。 Wǒ qīzi bù mǎnyì wǒ gěi tā zhào de xiàng. My wife isn't satisfied with the photo I took of her. 他给了我一个满意的答复。 Tā gěi le wǒ yī ge mǎnyì de dáfù. He gave me a satisfactory reply. 她满意地笑了。 Tā mǎnyì de xiào le. She smiled with contentment.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>点点头</headword>
		<pron tones="dian3dian5tou2"/>
		<defn>VERB to nod ones head</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>屋子</headword>
		<pron tones="wu1zi5"/>
		<defn>room 三间屋子 sān jiān wūzi three rooms</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>热热闹闹</headword>
		<pron tones="re4re5nao4nao4"/>
		<defn>ADVB busily</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>电子游戏</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4zi3 you2xi4"/>
		<defn>video game; TV game</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>装饰</headword>
		<pron tones="zhuang1shi4"/>
		<defn>decorate; adorn; ornament; deck 彩旗和鲜花把公园装饰得十分绚丽。 Cǎiqí hé xiānhuā bǎ gōngyuán zhuāngshì de shífēn xuànlì. The park was gaily decorated with bunting and flowers. 装饰图案 Zhuāngshì tú'àn decorative pattern</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>装修</headword>
		<pron tones="zhuang1xiu1"/>
		<defn>fit up (a house, etc.) 装修门面 zhuāngxiū ménmiàn fit up the front of a shop</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>东方</headword>
		<pron tones="dong1fang1"/>
		<defn>1 the east 东方欲晓。 Dōngfāngyùxiǎo. Dawn is breaking. 2 (Dōngfāng) the East; the Orient 3 (Dōngfāng) a two-character surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>功夫</headword>
		<pron tones="gong1fu5"/>
		<defn>1 time 他三天工夫就学会了滑冰。 Tā sān tiān gōngfu jiù xuéhuì le huábīng. It took him only three days to learn to skate. 她去了没多大工夫就回来了。 Tā qù le méi duō dà gōngfu jiù huílai le. She didn't take long to get there and come back. 明天有工夫再来吧。 Míngtiān yǒu gōngfu zài lái ba. Come again tomorrow if you have time. 2 dialect at that time 我当闺女那工夫, 连大门都不敢出。 Wǒ dāng guīnü nà gōngfu, lián dàmén dōu bù gǎn chū. When I was a girl, I didn't even dare to go outdoors. 3 workmanship; skill; art 练工夫 Liàn gōngfu (of actors, athletes, etc.) practise 这位杂技演员可真有工夫! Zhè wèi zájì yǎnyuán kě zhēn yǒu gōngfu! The acrobat's skill is really superb! 4 effort; work 花了好大工夫 Huā le hǎo dà gōngfu put in a lot of work</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>巨</headword>
		<pron tones="ju4"/>
		<defn>huge; tremendous; gigantic 巨幅标语 jùfú biāoyǔ a huge poster 巨型运输机 jùxíng yùnshūjī a giant transport plane 为数甚巨 wéi shù shèn jù a huge sum</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>成龙</headword>
		<pron tones="Cheng2 Long2"/>
		<defn>Jackie Chan (1954-), kungfu film and cantopop star</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>熟悉</headword>
		<pron tones="shu2xi1"/>
		<defn>know sth. or sb. well; be familiar with; have an intimate knowledge of 他们彼此很熟悉。 Tāmen bǐcǐ hěn shúxī. They know each other very well. 用群众熟悉的语言来写作 Yòng qúnzhòng shúxī de yǔyán lái xiězuò write in language familiar to the masses 你到了那里, 要先熟悉当地的情况。 Nǐ dào le nàli, yào xiān shúxī dāngdì de qíngkuàng. When you get there, first of all familiarize yourself with the situation. 他对各项生产数字很熟悉。 Tā duì gèxiàng shēngchǎn shùzì hěn shúxī. He has the various production figures at his fingertips. 他对这工作不熟悉。 Tā duì zhè gōngzuò bù shúxī. He is new to the task. 熟悉内情 shúxī nèiqíng know the ins and outs of the matter; know the inside story of; be in the know</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>受欢迎</headword>
		<pron tones="shou4huan1ying2"/>
		<defn>1 popular 2 well-received</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>成功</headword>
		<pron tones="cheng2gong1"/>
		<defn>succeed; be a success 大会开得很成功。 Dàhuì kāi de hěn chénggōng. The congress was a great success. 试验成功了吗？ Shìyàn chénggōng le ma？ Did the experiment come off all right? 这项革新一定能够成功。 Zhè xiàng géxīn yīdìng nénggòu chénggōng. The innovation is bound to be a success.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>好莱坞</headword>
		<pron tones="Hao3lai2wu4"/>
		<defn>Hollywood</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>之一</headword>
		<pron tones="zhi1yi1"/>
		<defn>1 one of (sth) 2 one out of a multitude 3 one (third, quarter, percent etc)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>于</headword>
		<pron tones="yu2"/>
		<defn>preposition 1 (indicating time or place) in; on; at 生于上海 shēngyú Shànghǎi be born in Shanghai 就学于北京大学 jiù xué yú Běijīng Dàxué study at Beijing University 驰名于全世界 chímíng yú quánshìjiè be famous all over the world; be of world renown 第一次世界大战爆发于一九一四年。 Dì-yī cì shìjiè dàzhàn bàofā yú yī jiǔyīsì nián. The First World War broke out in 1914. 来信于十五日收到。 Láixìn yú shíwǔ rì shōudào. Your letter was received on the 15th. 此项工程将于三年内完成。 Cǐ xiàng gōngchéng jiāng yú sān nián nèi wánchéng. This engineering project is to be completed within three years. 2 (indicating direction) 求助于人 qiúzhùyúrén ask people for help 热衷于集邮 rèzhōng yú jíyóu be keen on stamp collecting 3 (indicating giving or yielding to sb.) 腐朽的势力让位于新生的势力。 Fǔxiǔ de shìli ràngwèi yú xīn shēng de shìli. Decaying forces give way to new rising forces. 4 with regard to; concerning; to 有利于提高产量 Yǒulì yú tígāo chǎnliàng be conducive to higher yields 这样于你自己不利。 Zhèyàng yú nǐ zìjǐ bùlì. It won't do you any good. 操之过急, 于事无补。 Cāozhīguòjí, yúshìwúbǔ. It would be of no avail to act with undue haste. 5 (indicating beginning or origin) from 黄河发源于青海。 Huáng Hé fā yuányú Qīnghǎi. The Yellow River rises in Qinghai Province. 他毕业于上海圣约翰大学。 Tā bìyè yú Shànghǎi shèng yuē hàn dàxué. He graduated from St. !John's University of Shanghai. 认识来源于实践。 Rènshi láiyuányú shíjiàn. Knowledge comes from practice. 6 (indicating comparison) 不少于五千人 Bù shǎoyú wǔqiān rén no less than 5000 people 友谊贵于黄金。 Yǒuyì guì yú huángjīn. Friendship is more precious than gold. 金星略小于地球。 Jīnxīng lüè xiǎoyú dìqiú. Venus is a little smaller than the earth. 7 (indicating the doer of an action) by 主队败于客队。 Zhǔduì bài yú kèduì. The home team was defeated by the visiting team. 见笑于人 Jiànxiào yú rén be laughed at (by others)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>领馆</headword>
		<pron tones="ling3guan3"/>
		<defn>1 consulate 2 consular official</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>厨师</headword>
		<pron tones="chu2shi1"/>
		<defn>cook; chef</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>使馆区</headword>
		<pron tones="shi3guan3qu1"/>
		<defn>NOUN foreign consular quarter</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>周围</headword>
		<pron tones="zhou1wei2"/>
		<defn>around; round; about 关心周围的群众 Guānxīn zhōuwéi de qúnzhòng have concern for the people around one 团结在党的周围 tuánjié zài dǎng de zhōuwéi rally round the Party 环顾周围 huángù zhōuwéi look about; look around 周围环境 zhōuwéi huánjìng surroundings; environment 周围温度 zhōuwéi wēndù environment (or ambient) temperature</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>武打</headword>
		<pron tones="wu3da3"/>
		<defn>acrobatic fighting in Chinese opera or dance</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>留</headword>
		<pron tones="liu2"/>
		<defn>1 remain; stay 你留在原地。 Nǐ liú zài yuándì. Stay where you are. 会后你留一下。 Huì hòu nǐ liú yīxià. Will you please remain after the meeting. 他留在农村工作了。 Tā liú zài nóngcūn gōngzuò le. He stayed on in the countryside to work. 2 reside in a foreign country to study 留日 Liú rì study in Japan 留美 liúMěi study in the U.S. 3 ask sb. to stay; keep sb. where he is 他们一定要留我们吃午饭。 Tāmen yīdìng yào liú wǒmen chī wǔfàn. They pressed us to stay for lunch. 那我就不留你了。 Nà wǒ jiù bù liú nǐ le. In that case I won't keep you any longer. 4 pay attention to ▶ 留心 liúxīn 5 reserve; keep; save 留座位 Liú zuòwèi reserve a seat for sb. 把钱留起来, 以后用。 Bǎ qián liú qǐlai, yǐhòu yòng. Save the money for use later on. 留着这个有什么用？ Liú zhe zhège yǒu shénme yòng？ What's the use of keeping this? 三块钱给你两块, 我留一块。 Sān kuài qián gěi nǐ liǎng kuài, wǒ liú yī kuài. Here's three yuan. I give you two and I keep one. 这本书是我给你留着的。 Zhè běn shū shì wǒ gěi nǐ liú zhe de. I've kept this book for you. 6 let grow; grow; wear 留胡子 liú húzi grow a beard (or moustache) 留小辫儿 liú xiǎobiànr wear plaits (or braids); wear one's hair in plaits (or braids) 留短头发 liú duǎn tóufa wear one's hair short; have short hair; have bobbed hair 7 accept (sth. given); take 礼物先留下来。 Lǐwù xiān liú xiàlái. Let's accept the gift first. 我们的邻居想把五只小猫都给我们, 我们只留了一只。 Wǒmen de línjū xiǎng bǎ wǔ zhī xiǎo māo dōu gěi wǒmen, wǒmen zhǐ liú le yī zhī. Our neighbours wanted to give us all of their five kittens, but we only took one. 8 leave behind 给她留个条。 Gěi tā liú ge tiáo. Leave a note for her. 请他留个地址。 Qǐng tā liú ge dìzhǐ. Ask him to leave his address. 他把孩子留在家里了。 Tā bǎ háizi liú zài jiālǐ le. He left the children at home. 他死后留下三个孩子。 Tā sǐ hòu liú xià sān ge háizi. He died and left three children. 他父亲死后给他留下一所房子。 Tā fùqin sǐ hòu gěi tā liúxià yī suǒ fángzi. His father died and left him a house. 祖先留给了我们丰富的文化遗产。 Zǔxiān liúgěi le wǒmen fēngfù de wénhuà yíchǎn. Our forefathers have left us a rich cultural heritage. 这次参观给我们留下了深刻的印象。 Zhè cì cānguān gěi wǒmen liúxià le shēnkè de yìnxiàng. The visit made a deep impression on us.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>红十字</headword>
		<pron tones="Hong2shi2zi4"/>
		<defn>Red Cross</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>食品</headword>
		<pron tones="shi2pin3"/>
		<defn>alimentos</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>替身</headword>
		<pron tones="ti4shen1"/>
		<defn>1 substitute; replacement; stand-in 2 scapegoat</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>聪明</headword>
		<pron tones="cong1ming5"/>
		<defn>intelligent; bright; clever 聪明能干 cōngming nénggàn bright and capable 这孩子很聪明。 Zhè háizi hěn cōngming. This child is very clever.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>动作</headword>
		<pron tones="dong4zuo4"/>
		<defn>1 movement; motion; action 动作敏捷(缓慢) dòngzuò mǐnjié(huǎnmàn) quick (slow) in one's movements 优美的舞蹈动作 yōuměi de wǔdǎo dòngzuò graceful dance movements 2 act; start moving 且看他下一步如何动作。 Qiě kàn tā xià yī bù rúhé dòngzuò. Let's see how he acts next.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>敢</headword>
		<pron tones="gan3"/>
		<defn>1 bold; courageous; daring ▶ 勇敢 yǒnggǎn 2 be brave enough; dare 敢想、敢说、敢干 Gǎn xiǎng, gǎn shuō, gǎn gàn dare to think, dare to speak and dare to act 过去连想都不敢想的事, 现在变成了现实。 Guòqu lián xiǎng dōu bù gǎn xiǎng de shì, xiànzài biànchéng le xiànshí. What one couldn't even imagine in the past has now become reality. 3 have the confidence to; be certain; be sure 我敢说他一定乐于接受这个任务。 Wǒ gǎn shuō tā yīdìng lèyú jiēshòu zhège rènwu. I'm confident he will be willing to undertake the task. 我不敢说他究竟哪一天来。 Wǒ bù gǎn shuō tā jiūjìng nǎ yī tiān lái. I'm not sure just what day he will come. 4 formal polite make bold; venture 敢问 Gǎnwèn I venture to ask; may I ask 
dialect perhaps; I'm afraid</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>录</headword>
		<pron tones="lu4"/>
		<defn>1 record; write down; copy ▶ 抄录 chāolù , 记录 jìlù 2 choose; employ; hire ▶ 录用 lùyòng 3 tape-record 报告已经录下来了。 Bàogào yǐjing lù xià lái le. The speech has been tape-recorded. 你给我录盘磁带, 好吗？ Nǐ gěi wǒ lù pán cídài, hǎo ma？ Would you please copy a tape for me? 4 record; register; collection ▶ 语录 yǔlù , 回忆录 huíyìlù</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>唱片</headword>
		<pron tones="chang4pian4"/>
		<defn>phonograph (or gramophone) record; disc 放唱片 fàng chàngpiàn play a phonograph record 灌唱片 guàn chàngpiàn cut a disc</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>奥运会</headword>
		<pron tones="Ao4yun4hui4"/>
		<defn>short for 奥林匹克运动会 Àolínpǐkè Yùndònghuì</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>宣传</headword>
		<pron tones="xuan1chuan2"/>
		<defn>conduct propaganda; propagate; disseminate; give publicity to 宣传共产主义思想 Xuānchuán gòngchǎnzhǔyì sīxiǎng disseminate communist ideas 宣传党的方针政策 xuānchuán dǎng de fāngzhēn zhèngcè publicize the Party's general and specific policies 宣传群众 xuānchuán qúnzhòng spread propaganda among the masses 广为宣传 guǎngwéi xuānchuán give wide publicity to 做宣传要看对象。 Zuò xuānchuán yào kàn duìxiàng. In doing propaganda we must consider our audience.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>协会</headword>
		<pron tones="xie2hui4"/>
		<defn>association; society 中国人民对外友好协会 Zhōngguó rénmín duìwài yǒuhǎo xiéhuì the Chinese People's Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>会长</headword>
		<pron tones="hui4zhang3"/>
		<defn>the president of an association or society</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>婚外情</headword>
		<pron tones="hun1wai4qing2"/>
		<defn>extramarital affair</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>段</headword>
		<pron tones="duan4"/>
		<defn>1 measure word section; segment; part 一段铁路 Yī duàn tiělù a section of railway 一段衣料 yī duàn yīliào a length of dress material 这段历史 zhè duàn lìshǐ this phase of history 一段时间 yī duàn shíjiān a period of time 边界东段 biānjiè dōng duàn the eastern sector of the boundary 2 paragraph; passage 另起一段 lìng qǐ yī duàn start a new paragraph 这是钢琴五重奏《鳟鱼》里我最喜欢的一段。 Zhè shì gāngqín wǔ zhòng zòu 《Zūnyú》 lǐ wǒ zuì xǐhuan de yī duàn. That is my favourite passage from the piano quintet, The Trout. 3 (Duàn) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>一个人</headword>
		<pron tones="yi1ge4ren2"/>
		<defn>1 by oneself (without assistance) 2 alone (without company)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>有的</headword>
		<pron tones="you3de5"/>
		<defn>some 有的这样说, 有的那样说。 Yǒude zhèyàng shuō, yǒude nàyàng shuō. Some say one thing, some say another. 这些衣服, 有的好看, 有的不太好看。 Zhèxiē yīfu,  yǒude hǎokàn, yǒude bù tài hǎokàn. Some of these clothes look nice, some don't.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>除了</headword>
		<pron tones="chu2le5"/>
		<defn>preposition 1 except 除了老王, 我都通知到了。 Chúle lǎo wáng, wǒ dōu tōngzhī dào le. I've notified everyone except Lao Wang. 那条山路, 除了这位老猎人, 谁也不熟悉。 Nà tiáo shānlù,  chúle zhè wèi lǎo lièrén, shuí yě bù shúxī. Nobody knows the mountain path well except the old hunter. 除了下雨, 我每天都坚持长跑。 Chúle xiàyǔ, wǒ měitiān dōu jiānchí chángpǎo. I practise long-distance running every day except on rainy days. 2 (used correlatively with 还, 也,  etc.) besides; in addition to 懂日语的, 除了我还有两个人。 Dǒng Rìyǔ de, chúle wǒ háiyǒu liǎng ge rén. There are two others besides me who know some Japanese. 除了教课, 他还负责学校里青年团的工作。 Chúle jiāokè, tā hái fùzé xuéxiào lǐ qīngniántuán de gōngzuò. Besides teaching, he's in charge of the school's Youth League work. 3 (used correlatively with 就是) if not... (then...); either ... (or...) 刚生下来的孩子, 除了吃就是睡。 Gāng shēng xiàlai de háizi, chúle chī jiù shì shuì. If a newborn baby isn't eating, then it's sleeping. 这几天除了刮风, 就是下雨。 Zhè jǐ tiān chúle guāfēng, jiù shì xià yǔ. Recently we've been having either windy or rainy days.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>卖钱</headword>
		<pron tones="mai4qian2"/>
		<defn>sell for money 这东西卖不了几个钱。 Zhè dōngxi màibuliǎo jǐ ge qián. You can't get much for this if you sell it.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>最</headword>
		<pron tones="zui4"/>
		<defn>adverb 1 (used before an adjective or a verb) most; -est 最大 zuìdà the biggest 最小 zuìxiǎo the smallest 最美 zuì měi the most beautiful 最不发达国家 zuì bù fādá guójiā the least developed country 最基本的条件 zuì jīběn de tiáojiàn fundamental prerequisites 他最不讲道理。 Tā zuì bù jiǎng dàoli. He's most unreasonable. 我最喜欢吃巧克力冰淇淋。 Wǒ zuì xǐhuan chī qiǎokèlì bīngqilín. I like chocolate ice cream best. 2 (used before a noun of locality or a place word) farthest to or nearest (a place) 最上头 Zuì shàngtou farthest to (or nearest) the top; at the very top 最东头 zuì dōngtóu farthest to the east; at the very east end</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>毛衣</headword>
		<pron tones="mao2yi1"/>
		<defn>woollen sweater; sweater; woolly</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>外套</headword>
		<pron tones="wai4tao4"/>
		<defn>1 overcoat 2 loose coat; outer garment</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>大衣</headword>
		<pron tones="da4yi1"/>
		<defn>overcoat; topcoat</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>衬衫</headword>
		<pron tones="chen4shan1"/>
		<defn>1 shirt 2 blouse</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>汗衫</headword>
		<pron tones="han4shan1"/>
		<defn>1 undershirt; T-shirt 2 dialect shirt</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>帽子</headword>
		<pron tones="mao4zi5"/>
		<defn>1 headgear; hat; cap 戴上(摘下)帽子 dàishang(zhāixià)màozi put on (take off) a hat or cap 2 label; tag; brand 摘掉文盲的帽子 zhāi diào wénmáng de màozi rid oneself of the label of “illiterate” 大庆油田的胜利建成使我国甩掉了“贫油”的帽子。 Dàqìng yóutián de shènglì jiànchéng shǐ wǒguó shuǎidiào le “pínyóu” de màozi. The successful opening of the Daqing oilfield took the “oil-poor” label off China. See also 戴帽子 dài màozi  扣帽子 kòu màozi</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>裤子</headword>
		<pron tones="ku4zi5"/>
		<defn>trousers; pants</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>裙子</headword>
		<pron tones="qun2zi5"/>
		<defn>skirt</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>围巾</headword>
		<pron tones="wei2jin1"/>
		<defn>muffler; scarf</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>袜子</headword>
		<pron tones="wa4zi5"/>
		<defn>socks; stockings; hose</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>鞋子</headword>
		<pron tones="xie2zi5"/>
		<defn>shoe</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>手套</headword>
		<pron tones="shou3tao4"/>
		<defn>1 gloves; mittens 2 baseball gloves; mitts</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>件</headword>
		<pron tones="jian4"/>
		<defn>1 measure word a (for matters in general) 一件事 Yī jiàn shì a matter; a thing 一件工作 yī jiàn gōngzuò a piece of work; a job b (for clothing, furniture, luggage, etc.) 一件大衣 yī jiàn dàyī an overcoat 一件家具 yī jiàn jiāju a piece of furniture 三件行李 sān jiàn xíngli three pieces of luggage 2 single item ▶ 工件 gōngjiàn , 零件 língjiàn 3 letter; correspondence; paper; document ▶ 来件 láijiàn , 密件 mìjiàn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>顶</headword>
		<pron tones="ding3"/>
		<defn>1 the crown of the head ▶ 秃顶 tūdǐng 2 top 此山之顶有一古庙。 Cǐ shān zhī dǐng yǒu yī gǔ miào. There is an old temple at the top of the mountain. 3 carry on the head 头上顶着一罐水 Tóu shàng dǐng zhe yī guàn shuǐ carry a pitcher of water on one's head 农民们顶着月亮抢收稻子。 Nóngmín men dǐng zhe yuèliang qiǎngshōu dàozi. The peasants did a rush job reaping the rice in the moonlight. 4 gore; butt 这牛爱顶人。 Zhè niú ài dǐng rén. This bull gores people. 5 go against 顶风雪, 战严寒 Dǐng fēngxuě, zhàn yánhán face blizzards and brave severe cold 6 push from below or behind; push up; prop up 嫩芽把土顶起来了。 Nènyá bǎ tǔ dǐng qǐlai le. The sprouts have pushed up the earth. 用千斤顶把汽车顶起来 Yòng qiānjīndǐng bǎ qìchē dǐng qǐlai jack up a car 7 retort; turn down 我顶了他几句。 Wǒ dǐng le tā jǐ jù. I said a few words to him in retort. 把抗议顶回去 Bǎ kàngyì dǐng huíqu reject a protest 8 cope with; stand up to 负担虽重, 他们两个也顶下来了。 Fùdān suī zhòng, tāmen liǎng ge yě dǐng xiàlai le. The load was heavy, but the two of them coped with it all right. 9 take the place of; substitute; replace 顶别人的名字 Dǐng biéren de míngzi assume sb. else's name 不能拿次货顶好货卖。 Bù néng ná cìhuò dǐng hǎo huò mài. You shouldn't pass inferior goods off as high-quality goods and sell them. 10 equal; be equivalent to 一台收割机能顶几十个人。 Yī tái shōugējī néng dǐng jǐshí ge rén. One harvester can do the work of scores of people. 11 old take over or turn over ▶ 顶盘 dǐngpán 12 measure word (for things which have a top) 一顶帽子 Yī dǐng màozi a cap; a hat 一顶帐子 yī dǐng zhàngzi a mosquito net 13 adverb very; most; extremely 顶有用 dǐng yǒuyòng very useful 顶小的那个孩子 dǐng xiǎo de nà ge háizi the youngest (or smallest) child 我顶喜欢贝多芬的音乐。 Wǒ dǐng xǐhuan bèi duō fēn de yīnyuè. I'm very fond of Beethoven's music.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>条</headword>
		<pron tones="tiao2"/>
		<defn>1 twig 这棵葡萄长出了许多新条。 Zhè kē pútao zhǎng chū le xǔduō xīn tiáo. This grapevine has grown many new twigs. 2 a long narrow piece; strip; slip 把一块布撕成条 Bǎ yī kuài bù sī chéng tiáo tear a piece of cloth into strips 3 a brief informal note 经理不在, 请你给他留个条吧。 Jīnglǐ bù zài, qǐng nǐ gěi tā liú ge tiáo ba. The manager is out. Will you leave a note for him please? 4 item; article 这项条约的正文共八条。 Zhè xiàng tiáoyuē de zhèngwén gòng bā tiáo. The main body of the treaty consists of eight articles. 5 order ▶ 有条不紊 yǒutiáo-bùwěn 6 measure word (for long or narrow or thin things) 一条床单 Yī tiáo chuángdān a bed sheet 两条鱼 liǎng tiáo yú two fish 三条船 sān tiáo chuán three ships 一条大街 yī tiáo dàjiē an avenue 一条肥皂 yī tiáo féizào a bar of soap 一条香烟 yī tiáo xiāngyān a carton of cigarettes 一条裤子 yī tiáo kùzi a pair of trousers 7 measure word (for certain nouns) 一条好汉 yī tiáo hǎohàn a brave man 两条新闻 liǎng tiáo xīnwén two pieces (or items) of news 四条建议 sì tiáo jiànyì four proposals 一条好嗓子 yī tiáo hǎo sǎngzi a good voice 一条妙计 yī tiáo miàojì a brilliant scheme 三条人命 sān tiáo rénmìng three human lives</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>双</headword>
		<pron tones="shuang1"/>
		<defn>1 two; twin; both; dual 双目失明 shuāngmù shīmíng blind in both eyes 双发动机飞机 shuāng fādòngjī fēijī a twin-engined plane 粮食、棉花双丰收 liángshi, miánhua shuāng fēngshōu bumper harvests of both grain and cotton 2 measure word (for shoes, socks, chopsticks, etc.) pair 一双鞋 yī shuāng xié a pair of shoes 一双袜子 yī shuāng wàzi a pair of socks 3 (opp. 单 “odd”) even ▶ 双数 shuāngshù , 双号 shuānghào 4 double; twofold 双份 shuāngfèn double the amount; twice as much</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>副</headword>
		<pron tones="fu4"/>
		<defn>1 deputy; assistant; vice- 副主席 fùzhǔxí vice-chairman 副总理 fùzǒnglǐ vice-premier 副部长 fùbùzhǎng vice-minister 副领事 fùlǐngshì vice-consul 副书记 fù shūji deputy secretary 副秘书长 fù mìshūzhǎng deputy secretary-general 副主任 fùzhǔrèn deputy director 副经理 fù jīnglǐ deputy manager 副主编 fù zhǔbiān associate editor in chief 副司令员 fù sīlìngyuán assistant commanding officer (or commandant) (飞机)副驾驶员 (fēijī) fù jiàshǐyuán copilot 2 assistant post; a person who takes an assistant post ▶ 大副 dàfù , 二副 èrfù 3 auxiliary; subsidiary; secondary 副泵 fù bèng auxiliary pump 4 correspond to; fit ▶ 名不副实 míng bù fù shí 
measure word 1 for a set of sth. 一副手套 yī fù shǒutào a pair of gloves 2 for facial expression 一副笑脸 yī fù xiàoliǎn a smiling face 装出一副庄严的面孔 zhuāng chū yī fù zhuāngyán de miànkǒng put on solemn looks; assume a solemn face</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>衣服</headword>
		<pron tones="yi1fu5"/>
		<defn>clothing; clothes 外边冷, 多穿些衣服。 Wàibian lěng, duō chuān xiē yīfu. It's cold outside. Put on more clothes.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>文具</headword>
		<pron tones="wen2ju4"/>
		<defn>writing materials; stationery 文具店 wénjùdiàn stationer's; stationery shop</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>铅笔</headword>
		<pron tones="qian1bi3"/>
		<defn>pencil</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>圆珠笔</headword>
		<pron tones="yuan2zhu1bi3"/>
		<defn>ball-point pen; ball-pen</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>钢笔</headword>
		<pron tones="gang1bi3"/>
		<defn>pen; fountain pen</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>支</headword>
		<pron tones="zhi1"/>
		<defn>1 prop up; put up 支帐篷 zhī zhàngpeng put up a tent 用两张凳子把木板支起来 yòng liǎng zhāng dèngzi bǎ mùbǎn zhī qǐlai prop up the board with two stools 两手支着头 liǎng shǒu zhī zhe tóu rest one's head in both hands 2 protrude; raise 支着耳朵听 zhī zhe ěrduo tīng prick up one's ears 他那两只虎牙朝两边支着。 Tā nà liǎng zhī hǔyá cháo liǎngbiān zhī zhe. His two upper canine teeth protrude. 3 support; sustain; bear 孩子疼得支不住了。 Háizi téng de zhī bù zhù le. The child couldn't bear the pain. 4 send away; put sb. off 把他们支开 Bǎ tāmen zhī kāi put them off with excuses; send them away upon some pretext 这事甭支别人了, 你自个儿去吧。 Zhè shì béng zhī biéren le, nǐ zìgěr qù ba. Don't send anyone else; better go yourself. 5 pay or draw (money) 支拨 zhībō pay a sum of money or transfer a sum of money in payment 上银行支款 shàng yínháng zhī kuǎn go to the bank to draw money 6 (Zhī) a surname 
1 branch; offshoot 支店 zhīdiàn branch store 邮政支局 yóuzhèng zhījú branch post office 2 measure word a (for long, thin, inflexible objects) 一支钢笔 yī zhī gāngbǐ a pen 一支箭 yī zhī jiàn an arrow 一支香烟 yī zhī xiāngyān a cigarette b (for troops, fleets, etc.) 两支队伍 liǎng zhī duìwu two contingents of troops 一支舰队 yī zhī jiànduì a fleet c (for songs or musical compositions) 一支曲子 yī zhī qǔzi a tune 一支新歌 yī zhī xīn gē a new song d (for the illuminating power of electric lights) watt 一个四十支光的灯泡 yī ge sìshí zhī guāng de dēngpào a 40-watt bulb e (for the size or quality of yarn) count 六十支纱 liùshí zhī shā 60-count yarn 细(中)支棉纱 xì (zhōng) zhī miánshā fine (medium) count yarn 
short for 地支 dìzhī (see also 干支 gānzhī)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>本子</headword>
		<pron tones="ben3zi5"/>
		<defn>1 book; notebook 改本子 Gǎi běnzi go over students' written exercises; correct papers 2 edition 这两个本子都是宋本。 Zhè liǎng ge běnzi dōu shì Sòng běn. Both of these are Song Dynasty block-printed editions.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>本</headword>
		<pron tones="ben3"/>
		<defn>1 the root or stem of a plant 水有源, 木有本。 Shuǐ yǒu yuán, mù yǒu běn. A stream has its source; a tree has its roots. 2 foundation; basis; origin 兵民是胜利之本。 Bīng mín shì shènglì zhī běn. The army and the people are the foundation of victory. 3 capital; principal ▶ 还本 huánběn 4 principal; major; central ▶ 本部 běnbù 5 adverb originally; at first 我本想不去。 Wǒ běn xiǎng bù qù. Originally I didn't want to go. 6 one's own; native 本厂 Běn chǎng this factory 7 current; this; present 本周 běnzhōu this week; the current week 本决议 běn juéyì this resolution 8 be based on 每句话都有所本。 Měi jù huà dōu yǒusuǒ běn. Every statement is well-founded. 
1 book ▶ 笔记本 bǐjìběn 2 manuscript; copy ▶ 抄本 chāoběn 3 script ▶ 剧本 jùběn 4 edition; version ▶ 普及本 pǔjíběn 5 measure word (for books, parts of a serial, etc.) 两本书 Liǎng běn shū two books 这部电影有十二本。 Zhè bù diànyǐng yǒu shí'èr běn. This is a twelve-reel film.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>词典</headword>
		<pron tones="ci2dian3"/>
		<defn>dictionary</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>部</headword>
		<pron tones="bu4"/>
		<defn>1 part; section 分为三部 Fēnwéi sān bù divide into three parts (or sections) 南部 nánbù the southern part 2 unit; ministry; department; board 解放军某部 jiěfàngjūn mǒu bù a certain PLA unit 3 headquarters ▶ 指挥部 zhǐhuībù 4 troops; forces 5 formal control; command ▶ 所部 suǒbù 6 measure word (for books and films) 两部字典 liǎng bù zìdiǎn two dictionaries 一部电影 yī bù diànyǐng a film 7 measure word dialect (for machines and vehicles) 一部机器 yī bù jīqì a machine 两部汽车 liǎng bù qìchē two cars</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>书</headword>
		<pron tones="shu1"/>
		<defn>1 write 振笔直书 zhènbǐzhíshū take up the pen and write vigorously 2 style of calligraphy; script ▶ 楷书 kǎishū 3 book 一本关于中国历史的新书 yī běn guānyú Zhōngguó lìshǐ de xīnshū a new work on Chinese history 4 letter ▶ 家书 jiāshū 5 document ▶ 国书 guóshū , 证书 zhèngshū</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>铅笔刀</headword>
		<pron tones="qian1bi3dao1"/>
		<defn>a small knife for sharpening pencils; pen-knife</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>剪刀</headword>
		<pron tones="jian3dao1"/>
		<defn>scissors; shears 一把剪刀 yī bǎ jiǎndāo a pair of scissors</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>订书机</headword>
		<pron tones="ding4shu1ji1"/>
		<defn>1 stapler; stapling-machine 2 bookbinding machine</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>橡皮</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang4pi2"/>
		<defn>1 (vulcanized) rubber 橡皮胶水 xiàngpí jiāoshuǐ rubber cement 橡皮手套 xiàngpí shǒutào rubber (operating) gloves 2 eraser; rubber</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>尺子</headword>
		<pron tones="chi3zi5"/>
		<defn>rule; ruler</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>胶水</headword>
		<pron tones="jiao1shui3"/>
		<defn>mucilage; glue</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>食物</headword>
		<pron tones="shi2wu4"/>
		<defn>food; eatables; edibles</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>盐巴</headword>
		<pron tones="yan2ba1"/>
		<defn>dialect table salt; salt</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>糖</headword>
		<pron tones="tang2"/>
		<defn>another name for 碳水化合物 tànshuǐ huàhéwù 
1 sugar 咖啡里少搁点儿糖。 Kāfēi lǐ shǎo gē diǎnr táng. Don't put too much sugar in the coffee. 你喝茶搁糖吗? Nǐ hēchá gē táng ma？ Do you take sugar in your tea? 2 sweets; candy; sweetmeats 一袋糖 yī dài táng a bag of sweets 吃块糖。 Chī kuài táng. Have a candy.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>油</headword>
		<pron tones="you2"/>
		<defn>1 oil; fat; grease; petroleum 摊鸡蛋要多放点油。 Tān jīdàn yào duō fàng diǎn yóu. You have to put in more oil when making an omelet. 汽车该加油了。 Qìchē gāi jiāyóu le. The car's engine is in need of oil. 2 apply tung oil, varnish, or paint 油门窗 Yóu mén-chuāng paint the doors and windows 3 oily; greasy; stained or smeared with oil or grease 这炖肉太油了。 Zhè dùn ròu tài yóu le. The stewed pork is too greasy. 你的上衣油了。 Nǐ de shàngyī yóu le. Your coat has got oil stains on it. 4 oily; glib 这家伙嘴油得很。 Zhè jiāhuo zuǐ yóu de hěn. That fellow has a very glib tongue. 这个人油极了。 Zhège rén yóu jíle. That chap is much too slippery (or tricky). 他打麻将打得可油了。 Tā dǎ májiàng dǎ de kě yóu le. He is an old hand at mahjong.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>醋</headword>
		<pron tones="cu4"/>
		<defn>1 vinegar 2 jealousy (as in a love affair)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>酱油</headword>
		<pron tones="jiang4you2"/>
		<defn>soy sauce; soy</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>肉</headword>
		<pron tones="rou4"/>
		<defn>1 meat (esp. pork); flesh 她不吃肉。 Tā bù chī ròu. She does not eat meat. 许多动物的肉可以吃。 Xǔduō dòngwù de ròu kěyǐ chī. The flesh of many animals is eatable. 掉肉 Diào ròu lose flesh 身上没有肉 shēnshang méiyǒu ròu be skinny 2 pulp; flesh (of fruit) 冬瓜肉厚。 Dōngguā ròu hòu. A white gourd is rich in pulp. 3 dialect not crisp; not crunchy; squashy 肉瓤西瓜 Ròu ráng xīguā a squashy watermelon 4 dialect slow (in movement); sluggish 肉脾气 ròu píqi a phlegmatic temperament 这个人做事真肉。 Zhège rén zuò shì zhēn ròu. He does everything in such a lethargic way.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>香肠</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang1chang2"/>
		<defn>sausage</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>鸡肉</headword>
		<pron tones="ji1rou4"/>
		<defn>chicken (as food)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>鸡蛋</headword>
		<pron tones="ji1dan4"/>
		<defn>(hen's) egg</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>牛奶</headword>
		<pron tones="niu2nai3"/>
		<defn>milk</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>酸奶</headword>
		<pron tones="suan1nai3"/>
		<defn>yoghurt; sour milk</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>奶酪</headword>
		<pron tones="nai3lao4"/>
		<defn>cheese</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>豆腐</headword>
		<pron tones="dou4fu5"/>
		<defn>bean curd</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>豆</headword>
		<pron tones="dou4"/>
		<defn>an ancient stemmed cup or bowl 
pod-bearing plant or its seeds ▶ 扁豆 biǎndòu 
a bean-shaped thing ▶ 花生豆儿 huāshēngdòur</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>面包</headword>
		<pron tones="mian4bao1"/>
		<defn>bread</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>面条</headword>
		<pron tones="mian4tiao2"/>
		<defn>noodles</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>米</headword>
		<pron tones="mi3"/>
		<defn>1 (husked) rice 2 shelled or husked seed ▶ 高粱米 gāoliangmǐ , 花生米 huāshēngmǐ 3 (Mǐ) a surname 
metre</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>土豆</headword>
		<pron tones="tu3dou4"/>
		<defn>informal potato</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>香菇</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang1gu1"/>
		<defn>Xianggu mushroom</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>饼干</headword>
		<pron tones="bing3gan1"/>
		<defn>biscuit; cracker</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>糖果</headword>
		<pron tones="tang2guo3"/>
		<defn>sweets; candy; sweetmeats 糖果店 tángguǒdiàn sweet shop; candy store; confectionery 这孩子糖果吃得太多。 Zhè háizi tángguǒ chī de tài duō. That child eats too much candy.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>巧克力</headword>
		<pron tones="qiao3ke4li4"/>
		<defn>chocolate 果仁巧克力 Guǒrén qiǎokèlì nut chocolate 酒心巧克力 jiǔ xīn qiǎokèlì whisky heart chocolate 巧克力饼干 qiǎokèlì bǐnggān chocolate biscuit</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>冰凌</headword>
		<pron tones="bing1ling2"/>
		<defn>ice</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>蛋糕</headword>
		<pron tones="dan4gao1"/>
		<defn>cake</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>南瓜</headword>
		<pron tones="nan2gua1"/>
		<defn>pumpkin; cushaw</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>黄瓜</headword>
		<pron tones="huang2gua1"/>
		<defn>cucumber</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>白菜</headword>
		<pron tones="bai2cai4"/>
		<defn>Chinese cabbage</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>白萝卜</headword>
		<pron tones="bai2luo2bo5"/>
		<defn>1 white radish 2 daikon 3 Raphanus sativus longipinnatus</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>红椒</headword>
		<pron tones="hong2jiao1"/>
		<defn>pimiento rojo</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>葱</headword>
		<pron tones="cong1"/>
		<defn>1 onion; scallion 2 green ▶ 葱绿 cōnglǜ</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>大葱</headword>
		<pron tones="da4cong1"/>
		<defn>green Chinese onion</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>大蒜</headword>
		<pron tones="da4suan4"/>
		<defn>garlic 一头大蒜 yī tóu dàsuàn a head of garlic</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>生姜</headword>
		<pron tones="sheng1jiang1"/>
		<defn>informal ginger</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>苹果</headword>
		<pron tones="ping2guo3"/>
		<defn>apple (the tree and its fruit) 苹果脯 píngguǒ fǔ preserved apple 苹果干 píngguǒ gān dried apple slices 苹果酱 píngguǒjiàng apple jam 苹果酒 píngguǒjiǔ cider; applejack 苹果园 píngguǒ yuán apple orchard</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>葡萄</headword>
		<pron tones="pu2tao5"/>
		<defn>grape 一串葡萄 yī chuàn pútao a bunch (or cluster) of grapes 葡萄架 pútaojià grape trellis 葡萄藤 pútaoténg grapevine 葡萄园 pútaoyuán vineyard; grapery</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>香蕉</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang1jiao1"/>
		<defn>banana</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>梨</headword>
		<pron tones="li2"/>
		<defn>pear</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>橙子</headword>
		<pron tones="cheng2zi5"/>
		<defn>orange (the fruit)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>柠檬</headword>
		<pron tones="ning2meng2"/>
		<defn>lemon 柠檬糖 níngméng táng lemon drops 柠檬汁 níngméng zhī lemon juice</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>草莓</headword>
		<pron tones="cao3mei2"/>
		<defn>strawberry (the plant or the fruit)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>桃子</headword>
		<pron tones="tao2zi5"/>
		<defn>peach</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>柿子</headword>
		<pron tones="shi4zi5"/>
		<defn>Kaki (fruta)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>西红柿</headword>
		<pron tones="xi1hong2shi4"/>
		<defn>tomato 番茄酱 fānqiéjiàng tomato ketchup (or catsup); tomato sauce 番茄汁 fānqiézhī tomato juice</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>西瓜</headword>
		<pron tones="xi1gua1"/>
		<defn>watermelon</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>木瓜</headword>
		<pron tones="mu4gua1"/>
		<defn>1 botany Chinese flowering quince 2 dialect papaya</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>菠萝</headword>
		<pron tones="bo1luo2"/>
		<defn>pineapple</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>火龙果</headword>
		<pron tones="huo3long2guo3"/>
		<defn>1 red pitaya 2 dragon fruit 3 dragon pearl fruit (genus Hylocereus)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>荔枝</headword>
		<pron tones="li4zhi1"/>
		<defn>litchi; lichee</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>学校</headword>
		<pron tones="xue2xiao4"/>
		<defn>school; educational institution 师范学校 shīfàn xuéxiào teachers school; normal school 专业学校 zhuānyè xuéxiào specialized school; vocational school 高等学校 gāoděng xuéxiào institution of higher learning</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>地图</headword>
		<pron tones="di4tu2"/>
		<defn>map</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>杂志</headword>
		<pron tones="za2zhi4"/>
		<defn>1 magazine 订一份杂志 dìng yī fèn zázhì subscribe to a magazine 2 (often used in book titles) miscellaneous notes; notes 王念孙《读书杂志》 wáng niàn sūn 《Dúshū Zázhì》 Wang Niansun's Miscellaneous Reading Notes</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>背包</headword>
		<pron tones="bei1bao1"/>
		<defn>1 knapsack; rucksack; infantry (or field) pack; backpack 2 military blanket roll</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>电脑</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4nao3"/>
		<defn>popular name for 电子计算机 diànzǐ jìsuànjī</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>自行车</headword>
		<pron tones="zi4xing2che1"/>
		<defn>bicycle; bike 骑自行车 Qí zìxíngchē ride a bicycle 骑自行车进城 qí zìxíngchē jìnchéng go down town by bike</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>报纸</headword>
		<pron tones="bao4zhi3"/>
		<defn>1 newspaper 报纸夹 Bàozhǐ jiā newspaper holder 2 newsprint</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>画报</headword>
		<pron tones="hua4bao4"/>
		<defn>illustrated magazine or newspaper; pictorial</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>红绿灯</headword>
		<pron tones="hong2lü4deng1"/>
		<defn>traffic light; traffic signal</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>灯</headword>
		<pron tones="deng1"/>
		<defn>lamp; lantern</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>客人</headword>
		<pron tones="ke4ren2"/>
		<defn>guest</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>东方人</headword>
		<pron tones="dong1fang1ren2"/>
		<defn>Orientales</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>这个星期</headword>
		<pron tones="zhe4ge5xing1qi1"/>
		<defn>Esta semana</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>这个月</headword>
		<pron tones="zhe4ge5yue4"/>
		<defn>Este mes</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>电院</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4yuan4"/>
		<defn>Cine</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>向</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang4"/>
		<defn>towards; to</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>电器</headword>
		<pron tones="dian4qi4"/>
		<defn>Electrodomésticos</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>给简历</headword>
		<pron tones="gei3jian3li4"/>
		<defn>entregar CV</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>空时</headword>
		<pron tones="kong1shi2"/>
		<defn>tener tiempo libre</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>红椒</headword>
		<pron tones="hong2jiao1"/>
		<defn>pimiento rojo</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>机票</headword>
		<pron tones="ji1piao4"/>
		<defn>1 air ticket 2 passenger ticket M: 张zhāng [张]</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>身份证</headword>
		<pron tones="shen1fen5zheng4"/>
		<defn>identity card; identification card; ID card; ID</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>手机</headword>
		<pron tones="shou3ji1"/>
		<defn>cell phone</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>签证</headword>
		<pron tones="qian1zheng4"/>
		<defn>1 visa; visé 入(出)境签证 rù (chū) jìng qiānzhèng entry (exit) visa 过境签证 guòjìng qiānzhèng transit visa 一次有效出入境签证 yī cì yǒuxiào chū-rùjìng qiānzhèng entry-exit visa valid for a single journey 多次往返有效的出入境签证 duōcì wǎng-fǎn yǒuxiào de chū-rùjìng qiānzhèng multiple entry-exit visa 团体签证 tuántǐ qiānzhèng group visa 互免签证 hù miǎn qiānzhèng mutual exemption of visas 2 grant a visa 签证机关 qiānzhèng jīguān visa office</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>现金</headword>
		<pron tones="xian4jin1"/>
		<defn>1 ready money; cash 现金付款 xiànjīn fùkuǎn cash payment; payment in cash 现金交易 xiànjīn jiāoyì cash transaction 现金支出 xiànjīn zhīchū out-of-pocket expenses 2 cash reserve in a bank</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>字典</headword>
		<pron tones="zi4dian3"/>
		<defn>character dictionary (which defines only single characters, though including compounds as illustrative examples; e.g. the Xinhua Zidian 《新华字典》,  the Kangxi Zidian 《康熙字典》)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>驾照</headword>
		<pron tones="jia4zhao4"/>
		<defn>driver's license</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>传真机</headword>
		<pron tones="chuan2zhen1ji1"/>
		<defn>fax machine</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>文件</headword>
		<pron tones="wen2jian4"/>
		<defn>documents; papers; instruments 文件编号 wénjiàn biānhào the reference or serial number of a document 文件袋 wénjiàndài documents pouch; dispatch case 文件柜 wénjiànguì filing cabinet</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>判断</headword>
		<pron tones="pan4duan4"/>
		<defn>1 judge; decide; determine 判断是非 Pànduàn shì-fēi judge (or decide) what is right and what is wrong 判断情况 pànduàn qíngkuàng assess (or size up) the situation 你判断得很正确。 Nǐ pànduàn de hěn zhèngquè. Your judgment is sound. 你判断错了。 Nǐ pànduàn cuò le. You used bad judgment. 正确的判断来源于周密的调查研究。 Zhèngquè de pànduàn láiyuányú zhōumì de diàochá yánjiū. Correct judgments stem from thorough investigation and study. 2 logic judgment</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>海鲜</headword>
		<pron tones="hai3xian1"/>
		<defn>seafood</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>泰国</headword>
		<pron tones="Tai4guo2"/>
		<defn>Thailand</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>新鲜</headword>
		<pron tones="xin1xian1"/>
		<defn>1 fresh 新鲜空气 xīnxiān kōngqì fresh air 新鲜牛奶 xīn xiān niúnǎi fresh milk 新鲜的水果 xīnxiān de shuǐguǒ fresh fruit 鱼有点不新鲜了。 Yú yǒu diǎn bù xīnxiān le. The fish is slightly off. 尝个新鲜 Cháng ge xīnxiān have a taste of what is just in season 2 new; novel; strange 新鲜经验 xīnxiān jīngyàn new (or fresh) experience 这话真新鲜。 Zhè huà zhēn xīnxiān. That's a strange thing to say.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>有用</headword>
		<pron tones="you3yong4"/>
		<defn>useful</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>表演</headword>
		<pron tones="biao3yan3"/>
		<defn>to act; to play/performance</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>晒</headword>
		<pron tones="shai4"/>
		<defn>to bask in the sunlight; to tan</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>名胜古迹</headword>
		<pron tones="ming2sheng4-gu3ji4"/>
		<defn>places of historic interest and scenic beauty; scenic spots and historical sites</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>不得了</headword>
		<pron tones="bu4de2liao3"/>
		<defn>(of degrees) extremely; exceedingly</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>政治</headword>
		<pron tones="zheng4zhi4"/>
		<defn>politics; political affairs 政治历史清白(清楚) Zhèngzhì lìshǐ qīngbái (qīngchu) have a clean (clear) political record 政治上可靠 zhèngzhì shàng kěkào politically reliable 政治表现 zhèngzhì biǎoxiàn political behaviour or record 政治待遇 zhèngzhì dàiyù political treatment 政治挂帅 zhèngzhìguàshuài put politics in command 政治基础 zhèngzhì jīchǔ political basis 政治交易 zhèngzhì jiāoyì political deal (or transaction) 政治觉悟 zhèngzhì juéwù political consciousness (or awareness, understanding) 政治空气 zhèngzhì kōngqì political atmosphere 政治立场 zhèngzhì lìchǎng political stand 政治路线 zhèngzhì lùxiàn political line 政治骗子 zhèngzhì piànzi political swindler 政治生命 zhèngzhì shēngmìng political life 政治态度 zhèngzhì tàidu political attitude 政治舞台 zhèngzhì wǔtái political arena (or stage, scene) 政治信仰 zhèngzhì xìnyǎng political conviction (or belief) 政治性 zhèngzhìxìng political nature 政治溴觉 zhèngzhì xiù jué political sense of smell; political acumen (or sensitiveness)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>首都</headword>
		<pron tones="shou3du1"/>
		<defn>captial</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>赶快</headword>
		<pron tones="gan3kuai4"/>
		<defn>adverb at once; quickly 赶快跟我走。 Gǎnkuài gēn wǒ zǒu. Come along with me at once. 赶快把这块地收完。 Gǎnkuài bǎ zhè kuài dì shōu wán. Let's finish harvesting this plot quickly. 赶快! Gǎnkuài! Be quick! or Hurry up!</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>淡</headword>
		<pron tones="dan4"/>
		<defn>not salty</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>淡季</headword>
		<pron tones="dan4ji4"/>
		<defn>slack (or dull, off) season 争取做到蔬菜淡季不淡, 旺季不烂 zhēngqǔ zuòdào shūcài dànjì bù dàn, wàngjì bù làn strive for an ample supply of vegetables in the off seasons and avoid waste in the peak periods</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>旺季</headword>
		<pron tones="wang4ji4"/>
		<defn>peak period; busy season 西红柿旺季 Xīhóngshì wàngjì tomato season</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>打折</headword>
		<pron tones="da3zhe2"/>
		<defn>to sell at a discount; to give a discount</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>单证</headword>
		<pron tones="dan1zheng4"/>
		<defn>(international trade) documentation (e.g. a bill of lading)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>单证票</headword>
		<pron tones="dan1zheng4piao4"/>
		<defn>Billete de avion (ida)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>签</headword>
		<pron tones="qian1"/>
		<defn>1 sign; autograph 签支票 qiān zhīpiào sign a cheque 2 make brief comments on a document 看完请签个意见。 Kàn wán qǐng qiān ge yìjian. After you've read it, please write down a few brief comments.  1 bamboo slips used for divination or drawing lots ▶ 抽签 chōuqiān 2 label; sticker ▶ 标签 biāoqiān 3 a slender pointed piece of bamboo or wood ▶ 牙签 yáqiān 4 (of sewing) tack 把袖口签上 Bǎ xiùkǒu qiān shàng tack on a cuff</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>信用卡</headword>
		<pron tones="xin4yong4ka3"/>
		<defn>credit card</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>行李</headword>
		<pron tones="xing2li5"/>
		<defn>baggage; luggage</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>月初</headword>
		<pron tones="yue4chu1"/>
		<defn>the beginning of the month</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>月中</headword>
		<pron tones="yue4zhong1"/>
		<defn>the middle of the month</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>月底</headword>
		<pron tones="yue4di3"/>
		<defn>the end of the month</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>经济舱</headword>
		<pron tones="jing1ji4cang1"/>
		<defn>economy class</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>年初</headword>
		<pron tones="nian2chu1"/>
		<defn>the beginning of the year 去年年初 qùnián niánchū at the beginning of last year</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>年中</headword>
		<pron tones="nian2zhong1"/>
		<defn>1 within the year 2 in the middle of the year 3 mid-year</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>年底</headword>
		<pron tones="nian2di3"/>
		<defn>the end of the year</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>航班</headword>
		<pron tones="hang2ban1"/>
		<defn>scheduled flight; flight number</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>订</headword>
		<pron tones="ding4"/>
		<defn>0 reservar 1 conclude; draw up; agree on ∼条约 ∼ tiáoyuē conclude a treaty ∼合同 ∼ hétong enter into (or make) a contract ∼计划 ∼ jìhuà draw up (or work out) a plan ∼日期 ∼ rìqī fix (or agree on) a date ∼生产指标 ∼ shēngchǎn zhǐbiāo set a production target 2 subscribe to (a newspaper, etc.); book (seats, tickets, etc.); order (merchandise, etc.) ∼《中国日报》 ∼ 《Zhōngguó Rìbào》 subscribe to China Daily ∼房间 ∼ fángjiān make room (or hotel) reservations ∼座 ∼zuò make reservations for seats in a restaurant, theatre, etc. 3 make corrections; revise ▶ 修∼ xiū∼ 4 staple together 他把两封信∼在一起。 Tā bǎ liǎng fēng xìn ∼ zài yīqǐ. He stapled the two letters together.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>放假</headword>
		<pron tones="fang4jia4"/>
		<defn>to have a holiday or vacation</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>搬家</headword>
		<pron tones="ban1jia1"/>
		<defn>1 move (house) 我们下星期搬家。 Wǒmen xiàxīngqī bānjiā. We're moving next week. 2 remove; move 把这个箱子搬搬家, 别挡路。 Bǎ zhège xiāngzi bān bānjiā, bié dǎnglù. Please move the box out of the way.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>一般来说</headword>
		<pron tones="yi1ban1lai2shuo1"/>
		<defn>generally speaking</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>出院</headword>
		<pron tones="chu1yuan4"/>
		<defn>(of an inpatient) leave hospital 病愈出院 bìngyù chūyuàn be discharged from hospital after recovery 出院证明 chūyuàn zhèngmíng hospital discharge certificate</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>平常</headword>
		<pron tones="ping2chang2"/>
		<defn>ordinary; common</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>托运</headword>
		<pron tones="tuo1yun4"/>
		<defn>consign for shipment; check 你的行李托运了吗？ Nǐ de xíngli tuōyùn le ma？ Have you checked your baggage? 你的行李都拿下来了吗？有托运的没有？ Nǐ de xíngli dōu ná xiàlai le ma？ Yǒu tuōyùn de méiyǒu？ Have you got all your baggage off? Is there any checked through? 你有几件托运的行李？ Nǐ yǒu jǐ jiàn tuōyùn de xíngli？ How many pieces of consigned baggage have you got?</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>箱子</headword>
		<pron tones="xiang1zi5"/>
		<defn>box; case; trunk</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>超重</headword>
		<pron tones="chao1zhong4"/>
		<defn>1 overload 2 overweight 超重信件 chāozhòng xìnjiàn overweight letter 超重行李 chāozhòngxíngli excess luggage</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>登机牌</headword>
		<pron tones="deng1ji1pai2"/>
		<defn>boarding pass</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>登机证</headword>
		<pron tones="deng1ji1zheng4"/>
		<defn>boarding pass</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>乱</headword>
		<pron tones="luan4"/>
		<defn>in disorder; in a mess</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>担心</headword>
		<pron tones="dan1xin1"/>
		<defn>worry; feel anxious 我真担心她的健康。 Wǒ zhēn dānxīn tā de jiànkāng. I do worry about her health. 快给老大娘写信, 免得她担心。 Kuài gěi lǎodàniáng xiěxìn, miǎnde tā dānxīn. Write to the old lady at once so as to set her mind at rest.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>照顾</headword>
		<pron tones="zhao4gu5"/>
		<defn>1 give consideration to; show consideration for; make allowance(s) for 照顾到两国的友好关系 Zhàogu dào liǎng guó de yǒuhǎo guānxi out of consideration for the friendship of the two countries 照顾全局 zhàogu quánjú take the whole into account; consider the situation as a whole 照顾多数 zhàogu duōshù make allowance for the majority; think in terms of the majority 照顾实际需要 zhàogu shíjì xūyào consider actual needs 照顾他的困难 zhàogu tā de kùnnan take his difficulties into account 给予适当照顾 jǐyǔ shìdàng zhàogu give appropriate preferential treatment 青年团的工作要照顾青年的特点。 Qīngniántuán de gōngzuò yào zhàogu qīngnián de tèdiǎn. The Youth League in its work must take the characteristics of youth into consideration. 2 look after; care for; attend to 照顾伤员 Zhàogu shāngyuán look after the wounded 烈军属受到政府的特别照顾。 Liè jūnshǔ shòudào zhèngfǔ de tèbié zhàogu. Families of martyrs and servicemen receive special care from the government. 3 (of a customer) patronize</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>纽约</headword>
		<pron tones="Niu3yue1"/>
		<defn>New York</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>实习</headword>
		<pron tones="shi2xi2"/>
		<defn>to practice; to do an internship</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>平安</headword>
		<pron tones="ping2'an1"/>
		<defn>safe and sound</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>发</headword>
		<pron tones="fa1"/>
		<defn>to make a fortune</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>学期</headword>
		<pron tones="xue2qi1"/>
		<defn>school term; term; semester</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>指出</headword>
		<pron tones="zhi3chu1"/>
		<defn>point out</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>吃掉</headword>
		<pron tones="chi1diao4"/>
		<defn>VERB to eat up</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>记住</headword>
		<pron tones="ji4zhu5"/>
		<defn>remember; learn by heart; bear in mind 把这首诗记住 bǎ zhè shǒu shī jìzhu learn the poem by heart 你记得住这些数字吗？ Nǐ jì de zhù zhèxiē shùzì ma？ Can you carry all these figures in your head? 我记不住这么多电话号码。 Wǒ jì bù zhù zhème duō diànhuà hàomǎ. I can't bear in mind so many telephone numbers. 我们要记住这个教训。 Wǒmen yào jìzhu zhège jiàoxun. We must keep this lesson in mind.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>呆</headword>
		<pron tones="dai1"/>
		<defn>1 slow-witted; dull 这孩子大病之后变呆了。 Zhè háizi dà bìng zhīhòu biàn dāi le. After recovering from a serious illness, the child became slow-witted. 这人怎么那么呆! Zhè rén zěnme nàme dāi! What a silly man! 2 blank; wooden 呆呆地望着 Dāi dāi de wàngzhe stare at sth. blankly 吓呆了 xià dāi le be stupefied; be scared stiff; be dumbstruck 3 informal stay 呆在家里 dāi zài jiālǐ stay at home 我在那家饭店呆了三个天上。 Wǒ zài nà jiā fàndiàn dāi le sān ge tiānshàng. I stayed three nights at that hotel.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>许多</headword>
		<pron tones="xu3duo1"/>
		<defn>many; much; a great deal of; a lot of 许多人 xǔduō rén many people 积累了许多经验 jīlěi le xǔduō jīngyàn have accumulated much experience 我们有许多工作要做。 Wǒmen yǒu xǔduō gōngzuò yào zuò. We have a lot of work to do. 他讲的内容, 许多是我不知道的。 Tā jiǎng de nèiróng, xǔduō shì wǒ bù zhīdao de. Much of what he said was new to me. 她好像一下子老了许多。 Tā hǎoxiàng yīxiàzi lǎo le xǔduō. She seems to have aged a lot. 现在也顾不得这许多了, 送病人去医院要紧。 Xiànzài yě gùbude zhè xǔduō le, sòng bìngrén qù yīyuàn yào jǐn. We have no time to consider anything else. We have to rush the patient to hospital without delay.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>伟大</headword>
		<pron tones="wei3da4"/>
		<defn>great; mighty 我们伟大的祖国 wǒmen wěidà de zǔguó our great country 伟大的事业 wěidà de shìyè a great undertaking 伟大的胜利 wěidà de shènglì a signal victory</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>菜肴</headword>
		<pron tones="cai4yao2"/>
		<defn>cooked dishes (usu. meat dishes)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>杂技</headword>
		<pron tones="za2ji4"/>
		<defn>acrobatics</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>刺激</headword>
		<pron tones="ci4ji1"/>
		<defn>1 stimulation; stimulus; incentive 强刺激 Qiángcìjī a strong stimulus 竞争给产业以有力的刺激。 Jìngzhēng gěi chǎnyè yǐ yǒulì de cìjī. Competition is a strong incentive to industry. 2 stimulate; urge on; encourage 咖啡能刺激神经。 Kāfēi néng cìjī shénjīng. Coffee can stimulate one's nerves. 刺激生产 Cìjī shēngchǎn stimulate production 成绩能刺激人们作出更大的努力。 Chéngjì néng cìjī rénmen zuò chū gèng dà de nǔlì. Success will stimulate people to further efforts. 3 provoke; irritate; upset 别刺激他。 Bié cìjī tā. Don't provoke him. 这一不幸的消息给了她很大的刺激。 Zhè yī bùxìng de xiāoxi gěi le tā hěn dà de cìjī. She was badly upset by the sad news.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>百货</headword>
		<pron tones="bai3huo4"/>
		<defn>general merchandise 日用百货 Rìyòng bǎihuò articles of daily use</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>心烦</headword>
		<pron tones="xin1fan2"/>
		<defn>be vexed; be perturbed 这事真叫人心烦。 Zhè shì zhēn jiào rén xīnfán. This is really a bother. or This is really upsetting.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>放心</headword>
		<pron tones="fang4xin1"/>
		<defn>to set one's mind at rest; to be at ease; to feel relieved</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>尝</headword>
		<pron tones="chang2"/>
		<defn>taste; try the flavour of 尝尝味道。 Chángcháng wèidao. Try it and see if it tastes all right. 尝到甜头 chángdào tiántóu become aware of the benefits of; come to know the good of  ever; once ▶ 未尝 wèicháng , 何尝 hécháng</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>无聊</headword>
		<pron tones="wu2liao2"/>
		<defn>1 bored 整天呆在家里, 他感到无聊透了。 Zhěngtiān dāi zài jiālǐ, tā gǎndào wúliáo tòu le. He felt very much bored to stay at home all day long. 2 senseless; silly; stupid 不要讲这种无聊的话。 Bùyào jiǎng zhèzhǒng wúliáo de huà. Don't make such silly remarks.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>台北</headword>
		<pron tones="tai2bei3"/>
		<defn>CITY Taibei</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>开心</headword>
		<pron tones="kai1xin1"/>
		<defn>1 happy; joyous; elated 他们去长城玩得很开心。 Tāmen qù Chángchéng wán de hěn kāixīn. They went on a trip to the Great Wall and enjoyed themselves very much. 2 amuse oneself at sb.'s expense; make fun of sb. 别拿这老汉开心了。 Bié ná zhè lǎohàn kāixīn le. Don't amuse yourself at the old man's expense. 他有一点儿结巴, 别的孩子就拿他开心。 Tā yǒu yīdiǎnr jiēba, bié de háizi jiù ná tā kāixīn. Because he stammerd slightly, the other boys made fun of him.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>声音</headword>
		<pron tones="sheng1yin1"/>
		<defn>sound; voice 震耳欲聋的声音 Zhèn'ěryùlóng de shēngyīn an ear-splitting sound 她的声音很高。 Tā de shēngyīn hěn gāo. She has a high-pitched voice.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>短信</headword>
		<pron tones="duan3xin4"/>
		<defn>SMS; text message</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>说话</headword>
		<pron tones="shuo1hua4"/>
		<defn>1 speak; talk; say 他不爱说话。 Tā bù ài shuōhuà. He doesn't like to talk. 感动得说不出话来 Gǎndòng de shuō bù chū huà lái be too moved to say anything 还是让事实来说话吧。 Háishi ràng shìshí lái shuōhuà ba. Let the facts speak for themselves. 说话算数 shuōhuà suànshù honour one's word; mean what one says 我们说话是算数的。 Wǒmen shuō huà shì suànshù de. What we say counts. 说话不算话 Shuōhuà bù suàn huà go back on one's word 现在人民有了说话的权利。 Xiànzài rénmín yǒu le shuōhuà de quánlì. Now the people have got the right to speak. 2 chat; talk 我找他说话儿去。 Wǒ zhǎo tā shuōhuàr qù. I'd like to have a chat with him. 我们正说着话, 他进来了。 Wǒmen zhèng shuō zhe huà, tā jìnlai le. We were talking when he came in. 3 gossip; talk 你这样干, 别人当然要说话。 Nǐ zhèyàng gàn, biéren dāngrán yào shuōhuà. Considering what you've done, it's natural that people should be talking.  dialect 1 in a jiffy; in a minute; right away 说话就得。 Shuōhuà jiù děi. It'll be ready in a jiffy. 2 word; talk 他这句说话很有道理。 Tā zhè jù shuōhuà hěn yǒu dàoli. What he said was quite right. 3 a kind of storytelling popular in Tang and Song times</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>看出</headword>
		<pron tones="kan4chu1"/>
		<defn>make out; see 看出问题在哪里 Kàn chū wèntí zài nǎli see where the trouble is 看不出真假 kàn bù chū zhēn-jiǎ cannot tell whether it is genuine or fake 我没看出他的用意。 Wǒ méi kàn chū tā de yòngyì. I failed to see his intention. 看不出来, 你还会弹钢琴。 Kàn bù chūlai, nǐ hái huì tán gāngqín. I never expected that you could play the piano. 我一眼就看出是他。 Wǒ yī yǎn jiù kàn chū shì tā. I recognized him at first glance.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>耐心</headword>
		<pron tones="nai4xin1"/>
		<defn>1 patient 耐心等待 nàixīn děngdài wait patiently 她做任何事都耐心得很。 Tā zuò rènhé shì dōu nàixīn de hěn. She does everything patiently. 2 patience 失去耐心 Shīqù nàixīn lose one's patience; be out of patience</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>孝顺</headword>
		<pron tones="xiao4shun4"/>
		<defn>show filial obedience 她对父母十分孝顺。 Tā duì fùmǔ shífēn xiàoshùn. She is extremely filial towards her parents.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>心里</headword>
		<pron tones="xin1li5"/>
		<defn>in the heart; at heart; in (the) mind 心里发闷 xīnli fāmèn feel constriction in the area of the heart 心里不痛快 xīnli bù tòngkuai feel bad about sth. 记在心里 jì zài xīnli keep (or bear) in mind 心里有事 xīnli yǒu shì have sth. on one's mind 心里装着亿万人民 xīnli zhuāng zhe yìwàn rénmín have at heart the wellbeing of hundreds of millions 他将永远活在我们心里。 Tā jiāng yǒngyuǎn huó zài wǒmen xīnli. He will live forever in our hearts.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>重要</headword>
		<pron tones="zhong4yao4"/>
		<defn>important</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>讲</headword>
		<pron tones="jiang3"/>
		<defn>to speak; to tell; to explain</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>最后</headword>
		<pron tones="zui4hou4"/>
		<defn>final; last; ultimate 最后胜利 zuìhòu shènglì final victory 最后解决问题 zuìhòu jiějué wèntí bring the issue to a final solution; settle the question once and for all 作最后挣扎 zuò zuìhòu zhēngzhá make a last-ditch struggle 坐在最后一排 zuò zài zuìhòu yī pái sit in the last row 他们的建议最后被采纳了。 Tāmen de jiànyì zuìhòu bèi cǎinà le. Their suggestion was eventually accepted. 最后, 我想谈一下学习问题。 Zuìhòu, wǒ xiǎng tán yī xià xuéxí wèntí. Lastly, I would like to touch on the problem of study.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>而是</headword>
		<pron tones="er2shi4"/>
		<defn>OTHR and additionally</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>而且</headword>
		<pron tones="er2qie3"/>
		<defn>but also; and also</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>滚蛋</headword>
		<pron tones="gun3dan4"/>
		<defn>offensive beat it; scram 滚你的蛋吧! Gǔn nǐ de dàn ba! Get lost!</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>伯伯</headword>
		<pron tones="bo2bo5"/>
		<defn>informal 1 father's elder brother; uncle 二伯伯 èr bóbo second uncle 2 a term of address for a man of one's father's generation who is older than one's father; uncle 张伯伯 zhāng bóbo Uncle Zhang</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>叔叔</headword>
		<pron tones="shu1shu5"/>
		<defn>informal 1 father's younger brother; uncle 2 (a child's form of address for any young man one generation its senior) uncle</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>舅舅</headword>
		<pron tones="jiu4jiu5"/>
		<defn>uncle (mother's brother)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>阿姨</headword>
		<pron tones="a1yi2"/>
		<defn>Tía por parte de madre (también para allegadas a la familia)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>夫妻</headword>
		<pron tones="fu1qi1"/>
		<defn>husband and wife</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>老公</headword>
		<pron tones="lao3gong1"/>
		<defn>dialect husband</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>老婆</headword>
		<pron tones="lao3po5"/>
		<defn>informal wife</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>种</headword>
		<pron tones="zhong3"/>
		<defn>kind; sort; type</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>复杂</headword>
		<pron tones="fu4za2"/>
		<defn>complicated</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>瘦</headword>
		<pron tones="shou4"/>
		<defn>thin</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>软</headword>
		<pron tones="ruan3"/>
		<defn>1 soft; flexible; supple; pliable 软椅 ruǎn yǐ a soft chair 柳条很软。 Liǔtiáo hěn ruǎn. Willow twigs are pliable. 2 soft; mild; gentle 你对他软了些。 Nǐ duì tā ruǎn le xiē. You've been a bit soft with him. 他话说得太软了。 Tā huà shuō de tài ruǎn le. He spoke too mildly. 她看儿子哭了, 心软了下来。 Tā kàn érzi kū le, xīnruǎn le xiàlai. When she saw her son cry, her heart softened 3 weak; feeble 他两腿发软。 Tā liǎng tuǐ fā ruǎn. His legs felt weak (or like jelly). 最近以来, 爷爷的身子骨儿越来越感到软了。 Zuìjìn yǐlái, yéye de shēnzigǔr yuèláiyuè gǎndào ruǎn le. Grandfather has been getting feebler lately. 4 poor in quality, ability, etc. 货色软 Huòsè ruǎn poor-quality goods 工夫软 gōngfu ruǎn inadequate skill 5 easily moved or influenced 他心肠软。 Tā xīncháng ruǎn. He is tender-hearted.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>轻</headword>
		<pron tones="qing1"/>
		<defn>light; small</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>重</headword>
		<pron tones="zhong4"/>
		<defn>serious; heavy</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>智能</headword>
		<pron tones="zhi4neng2"/>
		<defn>intellectual power; intellectual ability</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>碟</headword>
		<pron tones="die2"/>
		<defn>small plate; small dish 一碟炒黄豆 Yī dié chǎo huángdòu a dish of fried soya beans</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>随身碟</headword>
		<pron tones="sui2shen1die2"/>
		<defn>1 USB flash drive (Tw) 2 see also 闪存盘shǎncúnpán [闪存盘]</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>平板电脑</headword>
		<pron tones="ping2ban3dian4nao3"/>
		<defn>NOUN tablet computer</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>希望</headword>
		<pron tones="xi1wang4"/>
		<defn>to hope/hope</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>加州</headword>
		<pron tones="jia1zhou1"/>
		<defn>NOUN California</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>更</headword>
		<pron tones="geng4"/>
		<defn>more</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>美丽</headword>
		<pron tones="mei3li4"/>
		<defn>beautiful 美丽富饶的国家 měilì fùráo de guójiā a beautiful and richly-endowed country 美丽的小姑娘 měilì de xiǎogūniang a pretty little girl 让我们的青春更美丽! Ràng wǒmen de qīngchūn gèng měilì! Let's make the days of our youth as beautiful as can be!</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>暑期班</headword>
		<pron tones="shu3qi1ban1"/>
		<defn>Clases de verano</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>中心</headword>
		<pron tones="zhong1xin1"/>
		<defn>centre; heart; core; hub 在广场中心 zài guǎngchǎng zhōngxīn at the centre of the square 抓住问题的中心 zhuāzhù wèntí de zhōngxīn get to the heart of the matter 陆路交通的中心 lùlù jiāotōng de zhōngxīn hub of overland communications 中心城市 zhōngxīn chéngshì key city 中心工作 zhōngxīn gōngzuò central task 中心环节 zhōngxīn huánjié key link; central link 中心问题 zhōngxīn wèntí central issue; crucial question</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>转机</headword>
		<pron tones="zhuan3ji1"/>
		<defn>0 hacer escala aerea 1 a favourable turn; a turn for the better 他的病有了∼。 Tā de bìng yǒu le ∼. The patient has taken a turn for the better. or His condition is improving. 战局出现∼。 Zhànjú chūxiàn ∼. The war situation was improving. 2 change planes</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>靠</headword>
		<pron tones="kao4"/>
		<defn>1 lean against; lean on 扁担靠在门背后。 Biǎndan kào zài mén bèihòu. The shoulder pole is standing behind the door. 把梯子靠在墙上 Bǎ tīzi kào zài qiáng shàng lean a ladder against a wall 2 stand by the side of; get near; come up to 车辆一律靠右走。 Chēliàng yīlǜ kào yòu zǒu. All vehicles should keep to the right. 船已经靠码头了。 Chuán yǐjing kào mǎtou le. The ship has docked. 疗养院靠海。 Liáoyǎngyuàn kào hǎi. The sanatorium stands by the sea. 他已是靠五十的人了。 Tā yǐ shì kào wǔshí de rén le. He's already close on fifty. 3 depend on; rely on 他家里靠他维持生活。 Tā jiālǐ kào tā wéichí shēnghuó. His family depended on him for support. 4 trust ▶ 可靠 kěkào 
(in traditional opera) stage armour (made of silk and embroidered back and front) 扎靠 Zhā kào wear stage armour</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>旅馆</headword>
		<pron tones="lü3guan3"/>
		<defn>inn; hotel</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>素餐</headword>
		<pron tones="su4can1"/>
		<defn>1 a vegetarian meal 2 be a vegetarian 3 formal not work for one's living; eat the bread of idleness</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>道</headword>
		<pron tones="dao4"/>
		<defn>0 pasillo 1 road; way; path 这是往古北口去的∼儿。 Zhè shì wǎng gǔ běi kǒu qù de ∼r. This road goes (or leads) to Gubeikou. 山间小∼ Shānjiān xiǎo∼ a mountain path 2 channel; course ▶ 河∼ hé∼ 3 way; method ▶ 养生之∼ yǎngshēng zhī ∼ 4 doctrine; principle; the Tao; the Way ▶ 孔孟之∼ Kǒng-Mèng zhī ∼ 5 Taoism; Taoist ▶ ∼士 dàoshì 6 superstitious sect ▶ 会∼门 huìdàomén 7 line 画一条斜∼儿 huà yī tiáo xié ∼r draw a slanting line 8 measure word a (for long and narrow objects) 一∼河 yī ∼ hé a river 万∼金光 wàn ∼ jīnguāng myriads of golden rays 一∼缝儿 yī ∼ fèngr a crack  b (for doors, walls, etc.) 两∼门 liǎng ∼ mén two successive doors 三∼防线 sān ∼ fángxiàn three lines of defence c (for orders, questions, etc.) 一∼命令 yī ∼ mìnglìng an order 出五∼题 chū wǔ ∼ tí set five questions (for an examination, etc.) d (for courses in a meal, stages in a procedure, etc.) 上四∼菜 shàng sì ∼ cài serve four courses 省一∼手续 shěng yī ∼ shǒuxù save one step in the process 上三∼漆 shàng sān ∼ qī apply three coats of paint 
circuit (an administrative division of a province in former times) ∼台 ∼tái intendant of a circuit 
1 say; talk; speak ▶ 能说会∼ néngshuōhuì∼ 2 say (polite words) ▶ ∼谢 dàoxiè 3 say (the words quoted) 她笑∼：“你说对了!” Tā xiào ∼ ： “nǐ shuō duì le!” She said with a smile, “You're right!” 4 think; suppose 我∼是老周呢, 原来是你。 Wǒ ∼ shì lǎo zhōu ne, yuánlái shì nǐ. So it's you! I thought it was Lao Zhou.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>平时</headword>
		<pron tones="ping2shi2"/>
		<defn>0 normalmente 1 at ordinary times; in normal times 他∼住在厂里, 星期六才回家。 Tā ∼ zhù zài chǎng lǐ, Xīngqīliù cái huíjiā. Ordinarily he sleeps at the factory and goes home only on Saturdays. 2 in peacetime ∼多流汗, 战∼少流血。 ∼ duō liúhàn, zhànshí shǎo liúxuè. Losing more sweat in peacetime (training, etc.) means shedding less blood in war. ∼编制 ∼ biānzhì peacetime establishment; peace organization (or footing) ∼兵力 ∼ bīnglì peacetime strength</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>跳舞</headword>
		<pron tones="tiao4wu3"/>
		<defn>1 dance (as a performance) 2 dance (socially or in a ballroom)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>根据</headword>
		<pron tones="gen1ju4"/>
		<defn>0 según 1 preposition on the basis of; according to; in the light of; in line with ∼天气预报, 明天要下雨。 ∼ tiānqì yùbào, míngtiān yào xià yǔ. According to the weather forecast, it's going to rain tomorrow. 我们∼具体情况制订了这个计划。 Wǒmen ∼ jùtǐ qíngkuàng zhìdìng le zhège jìhuà. We made the plan in the light of the specific conditions. ∼这样的考虑 ∼ zhèyàng de kǎolǜ in line with these considerations ∼公报的精神 ∼ gōngbào de jīngshén in the spirit of the communiqué ∼同名小说拍摄的影片 ∼ tóngmíng xiǎoshuō pāishè de yǐngpiàn a film based on the novel of the same title 2 basis; grounds; foundation 说话要有∼。 Shuōhuà yào yǒu ∼. One should avoid making assertions without good grounds. 毫无∼ Háowú ∼ utterly groundless</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>回答</headword>
		<pron tones="hui2da2"/>
		<defn>answer; reply; response 请回答我的问题。 Qǐng huídá wǒ de wèntí. Answer my question, please. 从理论上回答了这个问题 Cóng lǐlùn shàng huídá le zhège wèntí furnish a theoretical answer to this question 他的回答是“我不知道”。 Tā de huídá shì “wǒ bù zhīdao”. “I don't know” was his reply. 事实是对造谣者最有力的回答。 Shìshí shì duì zàoyáo zhě zuì yǒulì de huídá. Facts are the most powerful rebuff to rumourmongers.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>转眼</headword>
		<pron tones="zhuan3yan3"/>
		<defn>0 en seguida 1 in the twinkling of an eye; in an instant; in a flash 这孩子一∼就不见了。 Zhè háizi yī∼ jiù bù jiàn le. The child disappeared in the twinkling of an eye. ∼间, 一个月就过去了。 ∼jiān, yī ge yuè jiù guòqu le. A month passed before we knew it.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>到处</headword>
		<pron tones="dao4chu4"/>
		<defn>adverb at all places; everywhere 侵略者到处挨打。 Qīnlüèzhě dàochù áidǎ. The invaders were attacked wherever they went. 烟头不要到处乱扔。 Yāntóu bùyào dàochù luàn rēng. Don't drop cigarette ends about.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>投</headword>
		<pron tones="tou2"/>
		<defn>1 to cast 2 to send 3 to throw oneself (into the river etc) 4 to seek refuge 5 to place oneself into the hands of</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>回信</headword>
		<pron tones="hui2xin4"/>
		<defn>1 write in reply; write back 我回了他一封信。 Wǒ huí le tā yī fēng xìn. I wrote him a reply. 望早日回信。 Wàng zǎorì huíxìn. I'm looking forward to hearing from you soon. 2 a letter in reply 3 a verbal message in reply; reply 事情办妥了, 我给你个回信儿。 Shìqing bàn tuǒ le, wǒ gěi nǐ ge huíxìnr. I'll let you know when I'm through with it.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>单位</headword>
		<pron tones="dan1wei4"/>
		<defn>1 unit (as a standard of measurement) 长度单位 chángdù dānwèi a unit of length 货币单位 huòbì dānwèi monetary unit 单位面积产量 dānwèi miànji chǎnliàng yield per unit area 以秒为单位计算时间 yǐ miǎo wéi dānwèi jìsuàn shíjiān measure time by the second 2 unit (as an organization, department, division, section, etc.) 行政单位 xíngzhèng dānwèi administrative unit 生产单位 shēngchǎn dānwèi production unit 基层单位 jīcéng dānwèi basic (or grass-roots) unit</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>招聘</headword>
		<pron tones="zhao1pin4"/>
		<defn>1 recruitment 2 to invite applications for a job</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>经验</headword>
		<pron tones="jing1yan4"/>
		<defn>1 experience 经验丰富 jīngyàn fēngfù have rich experience; be very experienced 经验不足 jīngyàn bùzú lack experience; not be sufficiently experienced 直接(间接)经验 zhíjiē(jiànjiē)jīngyàn direct (indirect) experience 2 go through; experience 我从来没经验过这样的艰难。 Wǒ cónglái méi jīngyàn guò zhèyàng de jiānnán. I have never experienced such hardships.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>优秀</headword>
		<pron tones="you1xiu4"/>
		<defn>0 sobresaliente 1 outstanding; excellent; splendid; fine ∼作品 ∼ zuòpǐn (literary or artistic) works of excellence ∼电影 ∼ diànyǐng highly rated films ∼人才 ∼ réncái talented persons ∼生 ∼ shēng excellent students ∼的共产党员 ∼ de Gòngchǎndǎngyuán an exemplary Communist 中华民族的∼儿女 Zhōnghuá mínzú de ∼ ér-nǚ worthy sons and daughters of the Chinese nation 今天打靶, 他得了个∼。 Jīntiān dǎbǎ, tā déle ge ∼. He got an “excellent” in today's target practice. 成绩∼ Chéngjì ∼ get excellent results or marks</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>肯定</headword>
		<pron tones="ken3ding4"/>
		<defn>1 affirm; confirm; approve; regard as positive 肯定十月革命的伟大意义 Kěndìng Shíyuè Gémìng de wěidà yìyì affirm the great significance of the October Revolution 肯定成绩 kěndìng chéngjì affirm the achievements 对于我们的工作的看法, 肯定一切或者否定一切, 都是片面性的。 Duìyú wǒmen de gōngzuò de kànfǎ,  kěndìng yīqiè huòzhě fǒudìng yīqiè, dōu shì piànmiànxìng de. In the appraisal of our work, it is one-sided to affirm everything or to negate everything. 他的设计得到了总工程师的肯定。 Tā de shèjì dédào le zǒnggōngchéngshī de kěndìng. His design was approved by the chief engineer. 2 positive; affirmative 肯定的判断 Kěndìng de pànduàn a positive assessment 他的回答是肯定的。 Tā de huídá shì kěndìng de. His answer is in the affirmative. 3 definite; sure 请给我一个肯定的答复。 Qǐng gěi wǒ yī ge kěndìng de dáfù. Please give me a definite answer. 他今天来不来, 我不能肯定。 Tā jīntiān lái bù lái, wǒ bù néng kěndìng. I'm not sure whether he will come today. 他肯定敌人要逃跑。 Tā kěndìng dírén yào táopǎo. He was sure that the enemy would try to get away. 4 adverb certainly; undoubtedly; definitely 肯定按时送到 Kěndìng ànshí sòng dào guarantee punctual delivery 情况肯定是对我们有利的。 Qíngkuàng kěndìng shì duì wǒmen yǒulì de. The situation is undoubtedly in our favour.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>所</headword>
		<pron tones="suo3"/>
		<defn>1 measure word (for houses, schools, hospitals, etc.)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>地位</headword>
		<pron tones="di4wei4"/>
		<defn>1 position; standing; place; status 政治地位 Zhèngzhì dìwèi political position (or standing) 国际地位 guójì dìwèi international standing 经济地位 jīngjì dìwèi economic status 社会地位 shèhuì dìwèi social position (or status) 地位平等 dìwèi píngděng equal in status; on an equal footing 一定的历史地位 yīdìng de lìshǐ dìwèi a proper or definite place in history 他地位变了, 但普通劳动者的本色没有变。 Tā dìwèi biàn le, dàn pǔtōng láodòngzhě de běnshǎi méiyǒu biàn. His status has changed but he's kept the fine qualities of an ordinary labourer. 2 place (as occupied by a person or thing)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>稳定</headword>
		<pron tones="wen3ding4"/>
		<defn>1 stable; steady 物价稳定。 Wùjià wěndìng. Prices remain stable. 情绪稳定 Qíngxù wěndìng be in a calm, unruffled mood 稳定的多数 wěndìng de duōshù a stable majority 不稳定的国际金融市场 bù wěndìng de guójì jīnróng shìchǎng a shaky international monetary market 保持该地区的稳定和繁荣 bǎochí gāi dìqū de wěndìng hé fánróng maintain the stability and prosperity of the area 2 stabilize; steady 稳定物价 wěndìng wùjià stabilize commodity prices 稳定情绪 Wěndìng qíngxù set sb.'s mind at rest; reassure sb.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>适合</headword>
		<pron tones="shi4he2"/>
		<defn>0 adecuado 1 suit; fit ∼当地情况 ∼ dāngdì qíngkuàng be suited to local conditions ∼他的口味 ∼ tā de kǒuwèi suit his taste; be to his taste 这类野生植物不∼用作饲料。 Zhè lèi yěshēng zhíwù bù ∼ yòngzuò sìliào. These wild plants are not fit for fodder. 她∼做教师。 Tā ∼ zuò jiàoshī. She's fit for teaching.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>跳槽</headword>
		<pron tones="tiao4cao2"/>
		<defn>1 to change jobs 2 job-hopping</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>外企</headword>
		<pron tones="wai4qi3"/>
		<defn>short for 外资企业 wàizī qǐyè</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>白领</headword>
		<pron tones="bai2ling3"/>
		<defn>white collar</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>比不上</headword>
		<pron tones="bi3bu4shang4"/>
		<defn>can't compare with</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>过奖</headword>
		<pron tones="guo4jiang3"/>
		<defn>polite overpraise; give undeserved compliment 您的英语说得真好。--您过奖了。 Nín de Yīngyǔ shuō de zhēn hǎo. -- Nín guòjiǎng le. You speak very good English. --Thank you. You flatter me.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>失眠</headword>
		<pron tones="shi1mian2"/>
		<defn>(suffer from) insomnia 病人昨夜失眠。 Bìngrén zuóyè shīmián. The patient had a sleepless night last night. 经常性的失眠对身体极为有害。 Jīngchángxìng de shīmián duì shēntǐ jíwéi yǒuhài. A persistent insomnia is very harmful to one's health.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>要求</headword>
		<pron tones="yao1qiu2"/>
		<defn>0 requisito 1 ask; demand; require; claim ∼增加工资 ∼ zēngjiā gōngzī demand a raise in pay ∼发言 ∼ fāyán ask to be heard; ask for the floor ∼入党 ∼ rùdǎng ask to join the Party; apply for admission to the Party 严格∼自己 yángé ∼ zìjǐ set strict demands on oneself; be strict with oneself ∼赔偿 ∼ péicháng claim compensation 这项工作∼精神高度集中。 Zhè xiàng gōngzuò ∼ jīngshén gāodù jízhōng. This job calls for intense concentration. 对他不∼过高。 Duì tā bùyào ∼ guò gāo. Don't ask too much of him. 2 requirement; demand; claim 达到质量∼ Dádào zhìliàng ∼ fulfil quality requirements 提出领土∼ tíchū lǐngtǔ ∼ make territorial claims 满足他的∼ mǎnzú tā de ∼ satisfy (or meet) his demands</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>能力</headword>
		<pron tones="neng2li4"/>
		<defn>ability; capacity; capability 能力强 nénglì qiáng have great ability; be very capable 培养学生的推理能力 péiyǎng xuésheng de tuīlǐ nénglì develop the students' reasoning capacity 分析问题和解决问题的能力 fēnxi wèntí hé jiějué wèntí de nénglì ability to analyse and solve problems 他经验丰富, 有能力担当这项工作。 Tā jīngyàn fēngfù, yǒu nénglì dāndāng zhè xiàng gōngzuò. He is very experienced and has the ability to take on this responsibility.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>抓紧</headword>
		<pron tones="zhua1jin3"/>
		<defn>firmly grasp; pay close attention to 抓紧学习 zhuājǐn xuéxí attend to one's studies in earnest; study hard 抓紧时机 zhuājǐn shíjī seize or grasp the opportunity 抓紧时间 zhuājǐn shíjiān make the best use of one's time 抓而不紧, 等于不抓。 Zhuā ér bù jǐn, děngyú bù zhuā. Not to grasp firmly is not to grasp at all. 必须把农业抓紧。 Bìxū bǎ nóngyè zhuājǐn. We must pay close attention to agriculture. 要按时完成, 我们得抓紧一些。 Yào ànshí wánchéng, wǒmen děi zhuājǐn yīxiē. We must work harder if we want to meet the deadline. 经理对公司的财务抓得很紧。 Jīnglǐ duì gōngsī de cáiwù zhuā de hěn jǐn. The manager kept a firm hand on the finances of the company.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>离开</headword>
		<pron tones="li2kai1"/>
		<defn>leave; depart from; deviate from 他已经离开北京了。 Tā yǐjing líkāi Běijīng le. He has left Beijing. 小孩儿离不开母亲。 Xiǎo hái'ér líbukāi mǔqin. Children cannot do without their mothers. 离开本题 Líkāi běntí stray from the subject; digress 离不开手儿 líbukāi shǒur be too busy with the job on hand; have one's hands full</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>老板</headword>
		<pron tones="lao3ban3"/>
		<defn>shopkeeper; proprietor; boss</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>连</headword>
		<pron tones="lian2"/>
		<defn>1 link; join; connect 把这两条电线连起来。 Bǎ zhè liǎng tiáo diànxiàn lián qǐlai. Connect these two electric wires. 把零散的土地连成一片 Bǎ língsǎn de tǔdì liánchéng yī piàn join together scattered pieces of land 这两句话连不起来。 Zhè liǎng jù huà lián bù qǐlai. The two sentences are disconnected. or The two sentences don't hang together. 2 adverb continuously; in succession; one after another 他连说了三个钟头。 Tā lián shuō le sān ge zhōngtóu. He spoke continuously for three hours. 他连着三天没来。 Tā lián zhe sān tiān méi lái. He hasn't come for three days in a row. 连发三封电报 Lián fā sān fēng diànbào send three telegrams in succession 连挫强手 lián cuò qiángshǒu defeat strong opponents one after another 连战皆捷 liánzhànjiējié win a series of victories; win battle after battle 3 preposition including 连你一共十个人。 Lián nǐ yī gòng shí ge rén. There are ten people, including you. 4 military company 一营有三个连。 Yī yíng yǒu sān ge lián. A battalion has three companies. 5 (Lián) a surname 
preposition (used correlatively with 也, 都, etc.) even 连我都知道。 Lián wǒ dōu zhīdao. Even I know. 他连报也看不懂。 Tā lián bào yě kàn bù dǒng. He can't even read a newspaper. 他连看都没看。 Tā lián kàn dōu méi kàn. He didn't even look.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>准备</headword>
		<pron tones="zhun3bei4"/>
		<defn>1 prepare; get ready 为会议准备文件 wèi huìyì zhǔnbèi wénjiàn prepare documents for a meeting. 作最坏的准备 zuò zuì huài de zhǔnbèi prepare for the worst 随时准备歼灭入侵之敌 suíshí zhǔnbèi jiānmiè rùqīn zhī dí be prepared at all times to wipe out any invader 你准备好了吗？ Nǐ zhǔnbèi hǎo le ma？ Are you ready? 可能还会有更大的洪水到来, 我们必须有所准备。 Kěnéng hái huì yǒu gèng dà de hóngshuǐ dàolái, wǒmen bìxū yǒusuǒ zhǔnbèi. Worse floods are likely, so we must get prepared. 准备阶段 zhǔnbèi jiēduàn preparatory stage 2 intend; plan 今年暑假我准备回老家看看。 Jīnnián shǔjià wǒ zhǔnbèi huí lǎojiā kànkan. I intend to visit my native place this summer vacation. 我们准备下星期一开始试验。 Wǒmen zhǔnbèi xiàxīngqī yī kāishǐ shìyàn. We plan to start the experiment next Monday.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>广告</headword>
		<pron tones="guang3gao4"/>
		<defn>advertisement 登广告 dēng guǎnggào put an advertisement in a newspaper, magazine, etc. 做广告 zuò guǎnggào advertise 贴广告 tiē guǎnggào post a bill</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>英里</headword>
		<pron tones="ying1li3"/>
		<defn>mile</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>再说</headword>
		<pron tones="zai4shuo1"/>
		<defn>0 además 1 put off until some time later 这事先搁两天∼。 Zhè shìxiān gē liǎng tiān ∼. Let's put the matter aside for a couple of days. 等他打定了主意∼。 Děng tā dǎ dìng le zhǔyi ∼. Wait until he's made up his mind. 2 conjunction what's more; besides 现在去找他太晚了, ∼我路也不熟。 Xiànzài qù zhǎo tā tài wǎn le, ∼ wǒ lù yě bù shú. It's too late to go and see him now; besides, I don't quite know the way.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>一个多</headword>
		<pron tones="yi1 ge5 duo1"/>
		<defn>SWAN PHRASE more than one</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>上边</headword>
		<pron tones="shang4bian5"/>
		<defn>1 above; over; on top of; on the surface of 飞机在云层上面飞行。 Fēijī zài yúncéng shàngmian fēixíng. The plane flew above the clouds. 粉墙上面挂着大幅标语。 Fěnqiáng shàngmian guà zhe dàfú biāoyǔ. Large streamers bearing slogans were hanging on the white wall. 你的行李袋就在我的箱子上面。 Nǐ de xínglǐdài jiù zài wǒ de xiāngzi shàngmian. Your bag is on top of my suit-case. 上面就是琉璃塔了。 Shàngmian jiùshì liúlítǎ le. Further up is the glazed-tile pagoda. 大桥上面走汽车, 下面走火车。 Dà qiáo shàngmian zǒu qìchē, xiàmian zǒu huǒchē. The upper deck of the bridge is for motor vehicles, the lower deck for trains. 运河上面架了一座桥。 Yùnhé shàngmian jià le yī zuò qiáo. A bridge has been built across the canal. 2 above-mentioned; aforesaid; foregoing 上面所举的例子 Shàngmian suǒ jǔ de lìzi the above-mentioned example 上面这几条理由 shàngmian zhè jǐ tiáo lǐyóu the aforesaid reasons 上面几个发言 shàngmian jǐ ge fāyán the speeches you've just heard; the previous speeches 3 higher authorities; higher-ups 上面有指示。 Shàngmian yǒu zhǐshì. There are instructions from above. 4 aspect; respect; regard 他在外语上面下了很多功夫。 Tā zài wàiyǔ shàngmian xià le hěn duō gōngfu. He has put a lot of effort into his study of foreign languages. 5 the elder generation of one's family; the elders</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>下边</headword>
		<pron tones="xia4bian5"/>
		<defn>1 below; under; underneath 大桥下面 dà qiáo xiàmian under the bridge 图表下面的说明 túbiǎo xiàmian de shuōmíng the caption below the chart 褥子下面铺着一领席。 Rùzi xiàmian pū zhe yī lǐng xí. There is a mat underneath the mattress. 2 the next in order; following 下面该谁了？ Xiàmian gāi shuí le？ Who's next? 下面一个 xiàmian yī ge the next one 必须记住下面几点。 Bìxū jìzhu xiàmian jǐ diǎn. The following points should be borne in mind. 下面请老李谈谈。 Xiàmian qǐng lǎo lǐ tán tán. Now we'll ask Lao Li to say something. 这个问题我下面还要谈到。 Zhège wèntí wǒ xiàmian hái yào tán dào. I'll come back to this point later on. 3 lower level; subordinate 细心倾听下面的意见 Xìxīn qīngtīng xiàmian de yìjian listen carefully to the views of one's subordinates 了解下面的情况 liǎojiě xiàmian de qíngkuàng find out about how things are at the lower levels</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>前边</headword>
		<pron tones="qian2bian5"/>
		<defn>1 in front; at the head; ahead 在房子前面 zài fángzi qiánmian in front of the house 前面有座位。 Qiánmian yǒu zuòwèi. There're seats in the front rows. 走在队伍前面 Zǒu zài duìwu qiánmian march at the head of the column 前面就是宿营地。 Qiánmian jiùshì sùyíngdì. The campsite is right ahead. 前面来了一个人。 Qiánmian lái le yī ge rén. A man was coming towards us. 科学研究工作应当走在经济建设的前面。 Kēxué yánjiū gōngzuò yīngdāng zǒu zài jīngjì jiànshè de qiánmian. Scientific research should anticipate economic construction. 2 above; preceding 前面提到的原则 Qiánmian tídào de yuánzé the above-mentioned principle 前面的一章 qiánmian de yī zhāng the preceding chapter</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>后边</headword>
		<pron tones="hou4bian5"/>
		<defn>1 at the back; in the rear; behind 后面还有座位。 Hòumian háiyǒu zuòwèi. There are vacant seats at the back. 2 later 这个问题我后面还要讲。 Zhège wèntí wǒ hòumian háiyào jiǎng. I'll come back to this question later.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>里边</headword>
		<pron tones="li3bian5"/>
		<defn>inside; in; within 他们都在里边。 Tāmen dōu zài lǐbian. They are all inside. 里边有很多人。 Lǐbian yǒu hěn duō rén. There are a lot of people inside. 这所房子里边还没完工。 Zhè suǒ fángzi lǐbian hái méi wángōng. The inside of this house isn't finished yet. 他一年里边没有请过一次假。 Tā yī nián lǐbian méiyǒu qǐng guò yī cì jià. He has not once asked for leave during the whole year. 这里边有问题。 Zhèlǐ bian yǒu wèntí. There is something wrong here. or Something is wrong here. 里边请! Lǐbian qǐng! Come on in, please!</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>外边</headword>
		<pron tones="wai4bian5"/>
		<defn>1 outside; out 到外边散步 dào wàibian sànbù go out for a walk 咱们上外边去谈, 好不好？ Zánmen shàng wàibian qù tán, hǎo bù hǎo？ Let's go outside to talk, shall we? 2 a place other than where one lives or works 她儿子在外边工作。 Tā érzi zài wàibian gōngzuò. Her son works somewhere away from home. 3 exterior; outside 行李卷儿外边再裹一层塑料布。 Xínglijuǎnr wàibian zài guǒ yī céng sùliào bù. Wrap a plastic sheet round the bedroll.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>左边</headword>
		<pron tones="zuo3bian5"/>
		<defn>the left; the left (or left-hand) side 房子左边有一棵榆树。 Fángzi zuǒbian yǒu yī kē yúshù. There's an elm tree on the left of the house.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>右边</headword>
		<pron tones="you4bian5"/>
		<defn>the right (or right-hand) side; the right</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>东边</headword>
		<pron tones="dong1bian5"/>
		<defn>the east; east side</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>南边</headword>
		<pron tones="nan2bian5"/>
		<defn>1 south; the southern side 2 informal the southern part of the country, esp. the area south of the Changjiang River; the South</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>西边</headword>
		<pron tones="xi1bian5"/>
		<defn>the west; west side</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>北边</headword>
		<pron tones="bei3bian1"/>
		<defn>1 north; the northern side 加拿大在美国的北边。 Jiānádà zài Měiguó de běibiān. Canada lies north of the United States of America. 2 same as 北方 běifāng②</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>中间</headword>
		<pron tones="zhong1jian1"/>
		<defn>1 among; between 生活在人民群众中间 shēnghuó zài rénmín qúnzhòng zhōngjiān live among the masses of the people 坐在他们两人中间 zuò zài tāmen liǎng rén zhōngjiān sit between the two of them 她是我们三人中间最年轻的。 Tā shì wǒmen sān rén zhōngjiān zuì niánqīng de. She is the youngest of us three. 2 centre; middle 中间突破 Zhōngjiān tūpò make a breakthrough at the centre (or in the middle) 中间剥削 zhōngjiān bōxuē middleman's exploitation 中间道路 zhōngjiān dàolù middle road 中间地带 zhōngjiān dìdài intermediate zone 中间分子 zhōngjiān fènzǐ middle (or intermediate) element 中间路线 zhōngjiān lùxiàn middle-of-the-road line; middle road 中间状态 zhōngjiān zhuàngtài intermediate state 从我家到工厂, 中间要换车。 Cóng wǒ jiā dào gōngchǎng, zhōngjiān yào huàn chē. I have to change buses on the way from home to the factory.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>对面</headword>
		<pron tones="dui4mian4"/>
		<defn>1 opposite 他家就在我家对面。 Tā jiā jiù zài wǒ jiā duìmiàn. His house is opposite mine. 2 right in front 对面来了一位解放军。 Duìmiàn lái le yī wèi jiěfàngjūn. A PLA man came towards us. 3 face to face 这事儿得他们本人对面儿谈。 Zhè shìr děi tāmen běnrén duìmiànr tán. They should talk about this face to face. 他俩对面坐着。 Tā liǎ duìmiàn zuò zhe. The two of them sat facing each other.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>薪水</headword>
		<pron tones="xin1shui5"/>
		<defn>salary; pay; wages</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>还是</headword>
		<pron tones="hai2shi5"/>
		<defn>1 adverb still; yet 废物还是可以利用。 Fèiwù háishi kěyǐ lìyòng. Waste materials can still be made use of. 这次还是他做我们的向导。 Zhècì háishi tā zuò wǒmen de xiàngdǎo. He is still our guide for this trip. 她还是会来的。 Tā hái shi huì lái de. She may come yet. 尽管旱情严重, 今年的小麦还是丰收了。 Jǐnguǎn hànqíng yánzhòng, jīnnián de xiǎomài háishi fēngshōu le. Despite the serious drought, the wheat harvest this year was good. 2 adverb (expressing a preference for an alternative) 天冷了, 你还是多穿点儿吧。 Tiān lěng le, nǐ hái shi duō chuān diǎnr ba. It's getting cold, you'd better put on more clothes. 还是你来吧, 我在家等你。 Hái shi nǐ lái ba, wǒ zài jiā děng nǐ. It would be better for you to come; I'll be at home waiting for you. 还是坐飞机快。 Hái shi zuò fēijī kuài. It's much faster to travel by plane after all. 3 adverb (expressing realization or discovery) 这个人还是真了不起。 Zhège rén hái shi zhēn liǎobuqǐ. This chap is really great. 还是利害的人有办法。 Háishi lìhai de rén yǒu bànfǎ. It's the pushing type that gets on. 我没想到这事儿还是真难办。 Wǒ méi xiǎngdào zhè shìr hái shi zhēn nán bàn. I didn't expect it to be so difficult. 4 conjunction or 你去, 还是他去？ Nǐ qù, háishi tā qù？ Are you going or is he? 先去上海还是先去西安没有最后定。 Xiān qù Shànghǎi háishi xiān qù Xī'ān méiyǒu zuìhòu dìng. We haven't decided yet whether we go to Shanghai or Xi'an first. 5 conjunction no matter what, how etc.; whether...or...; regardless of 无论唱歌还是跳舞, 她都行。 Wúlùn chànggē háishi tiàowǔ, tā dōu xíng. Singing or dancing, she is good at them all. 不管刮风还是下雨, 他天天准时到校。 Bùguǎn guāfēng háishi xiàyǔ, tā tiāntiān zhǔnshí dào xiào. He goes to school on time everyday no matter whether it rains or blows.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>不会</headword>
		<pron tones="bu4hui4"/>
		<defn>AUXV cannot</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>明白</headword>
		<pron tones="ming2bai5"/>
		<defn>VERB to understand</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>这么</headword>
		<pron tones="zhe4me5"/>
		<defn>0 tan 1 so; such; this way; like this 他就是∼个人。 Tā jiù shì ∼ ge rén. That's just like him. 那个句子应该∼译。 Nàge jùzi yīnggāi ∼ yì. The sentence should be translated this way. 大家都∼说。 Dàjiā dōu ∼ shuō. So they say. 往∼挪一挪。 Wǎng ∼ nuó yī nuó. Move over this way a little bit. 有∼回事。 Yǒu ∼ huí shì. Yes, that's true.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>急</headword>
		<pron tones="ji2"/>
		<defn>1 impatient; anxious 急着要出发 Jí zhe yào chūfā be impatient to set out 2 worry 你怎么来得这么晚, 真把人急死啦! Nǐ zěnme lái de zhème wǎn, zhēn bǎ rén jí sǐ la! Why are you so late? We were worried to death about you. 3 irritated; annoyed; nettled 你老唠叨他, 会把他弄急的。 Nǐ lǎo láodao tā, huì bǎ tā nòng jí de. If you keep nagging him, you'll make him very annoyed. 我没想到他真急了。 Wǒ méi xiǎngdào tā zhēn jí le. I didn't expect him to get angry. 4 fast; rapid; violent 水流很急。 Shuǐliú hěn jí. The current is swift. or It's a strong current. 雨下得正急。 Yǔ xià de zhèng jí. It's raining hard. 急转弯 jízhuǎnwān make a sharp turn 5 urgent; pressing 事情很急, 必须立即处理。 Shìqing hěn jí, bìxū lìjí chǔlǐ. The matter is pressing (or urgent) and must be dealt with at once. 他走得很急。 Tā zǒu de hěn jí. He left in a hurry. 6 urgency; emergency ▶ 应急 yìngjí 7 be eager to help 急人之难 jírénzhīnàn be eager to help those in need 急病人之所急 jí bìngrén zhī suǒ jí be eager to meet the needs of the patients; put oneself in a patient's position</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>越来越大</headword>
		<pron tones="yue4lai2yue4da4"/>
		<defn>ADJT bigger and bigger</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>收</headword>
		<pron tones="shou1"/>
		<defn>1 receive; accept 请收下作为纪念。 Qǐng shōu xià zuòwéi jìniàn. Please accept this as a souvenir. 学校今年又收了一批研究生。 Xuéxiào jīnnián yòu shōu le yī pī yánjiūshēng. The college has enrolled another group of research students this year. 这本词典共收词六万余条。 Zhè běn cídiǎn gòng shōu cí liùwàn yú tiáo. The dictionary contains over 60,000 entries. 2 put away; take in 收工具 Shōu gōngjù put the tools away 洗的衣服收了没有？ Xǐ de yīfu shōu le méiyǒu？ Have you brought in the washing? 3 collect 收水电费 shōu shuǐ-diànfèi collect water and electricity bills 收税 shōushuì collect taxes 收废品 shōu fèipǐn collect scrap 4 money received; receipts; income ▶ 税收 shuìshōu 5 harvest; gather in 收庄稼 shōu zhuāngjia harvest (or gather in ) crops 一亩稻子收了八百斤。 Yī mǔ dàozi shōu le bābǎi jīn. The rice yield was 800 jin per mu. 6 bring to an end; stop 时间不早了, 今天就收了吧。 Shíjiān bù zǎo le, jīntiān jiù shōu le ba. It's getting late. Let's call it a day. 7 restrain; control 孩子玩得心都收不回来了。 Háizi wán de xīn dōu shōu bù huílai le. The boy can't get his mind off play.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>收发</headword>
		<pron tones="shou1fa1"/>
		<defn>1 receive and dispatch 2 dispatcher</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>耐心地</headword>
		<pron tones="nai4xin1 de5"/>
		<defn>ADVB patiently</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>为</headword>
		<pron tones="wei4"/>
		<defn>1 preposition in the interest of; for 为什么人的问题, 是一个根本的问题, 原则的问题。 Wèishénme rén de wèntí,  shì yī ge gēnběn de wèntí, yuánzé de wèntí. The question of “for whom?” is fundamental; it is a question of principle. 为大多数人谋利益 Wèi dàduōshù rén móu lìyì work in the interests of the vast majority of people 2 preposition because of 为我们的友谊干杯! Wèi wǒmen de yǒuyì gānbēi! A toast to our friendship! 为胜利而欢呼 Wèi shènglì ér huānhū hail a victory 3 preposition for the purpose of; for the sake of 为方便起见 wèi fāngbiàn qǐjiàn for the sake of convenience 不为名, 不为利 bù wèi míng, bù wèi lì seek no personal fame or gain 让我们为实现这一宏伟目标而共同努力。 Ràng wǒmen wèi shíxiàn zhè yī hóngwěi mùbiāo ér gòngtóng nǔlì. Let us strive together to attain this splendid goal. 4 preposition to; towards 他为我送来一份请帖。 Tā wèi wǒ sòng lái yī fèn qǐngtiě. He's sent an invitation to me. 且为诸君言之。 Qiě wèi zhūjūn yán zhī. Now I'll inform you about it. 5 formal stand for; support See 为wéi</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>拿出</headword>
		<pron tones="na2chu1"/>
		<defn>1 to take out 2 to put out 3 to provide 4 to put forward (a proposal) 5 to come up with (evidence)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>急忙</headword>
		<pron tones="ji2mang2"/>
		<defn>in a hurry; in haste; hurriedly; hastily 你干吗这样急急忙忙的？ Nǐ gànmá zhèyàng jíjímángmáng de？ Why are you in such a hurry? 他起晚了, 没吃早饭就急忙向学校跑去。 Tā qǐ wǎn le, méi chī zǎofàn jiù jímáng xiàng xuéxiào pǎo qù. He got up late and hurriedly ran off to school without eating any breakfast.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>赶</headword>
		<pron tones="gan3"/>
		<defn>1 catch up with; overtake 赶先进 gǎn xiānjìn catch up with the advanced 落在后面的人赶上来了。 Luò zài hòumian de rén gǎnshàng lái le. Those who lagged behind have caught up. 要说摘棉花, 可谁也赶不上她。 Yào shuō zhāi miánhua, kě shuí yě gǎn bù shàng tā. Nobody can keep up with her in picking cotton. 她已经赶到大伙儿前头去了。 Tā yǐjing gǎndào dàhuǒr qiántou qù le. She's shot ahead of all the rest of us. 2 try to catch; make a dash for; rush for 赶头班车 Gǎn tóu bānchē catch the first bus 火车七点三十分开,我们赶得及吗？ Huǒchē qī diǎn sānshí fēnkāi, wǒmen gǎndejí ma？ The train leaves at 7∶30. Can we make it? 3 hurry (or rush) through 赶任务 gǎn rènwù rush through one's job 他连夜赶写了一份报告。 Tā liányè gǎn xiě le yī fèn bàogào. He dashed off a report that very night. 赶调了一个团到灾区去帮助救灾。 Gǎn diào le yī ge tuán dào zāiqū qù bāngzhù jiùzāi. A regiment was rushed to the stricken area to help with relief work. 4 drive 赶大车 Gǎn dà chē drive a cart 把羊赶到山上去放。 Bǎ yáng gǎndào shān shàng qù fàng. Herd the sheep up the hill to graze. 5 drive away; expel 把敌人赶走 Bǎ dírén gǎnzǒu drive the enemy away; throw out the enemy 辛亥革命赶跑了一个皇帝, 但是没有摧毁封建统治的基础。 Xīnhài Gémìng gǎnpǎo le yī ge huángdì, dànshì méiyǒu cuīhuǐ fēngjiàn tǒngzhì de jīchǔ. The 1911 Revolution sent an emperor packing, but failed to demolish the foundation of feudal rule. 赶苍蝇 Gǎn cāngying whisk the flies off; brush away a fly 6 happen to; find oneself in (a situation); avail oneself of (an opportunity) 赶上一场雨 gǎnshàng yī cháng yǔ run into a rain 我去了两趟, 正赶上他下厂去了。 Wǒ qù le liǎng tàng, zhèng gǎnshàng tā xià chǎng qù le. I went there twice, but he happened to be away at the factory each time. 得赶这好天把被子晒一晒。 Děi gǎn zhè hǎotiān bǎ bèizi shài yī shài. We should air the bedding while the good weather lasts. 7 preposition till 咱俩的婚事赶年下再办吧。 Zán liǎ de hūnshì gǎn nián xià zài bàn ba. Let's put off our wedding till the Spring Festival. 赶晌午我就走。 Gǎn shǎngwu wǒ jiù zǒu. I'll be leaving at noon. 这事赶以后再谈吧。 Zhè shì gǎn yǐhòu zài tán ba. Let's discuss the matter later.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>刚好</headword>
		<pron tones="gang1hao3"/>
		<defn>adverb 1 just; exactly 我们刚好赶上末班车。 Wǒmen gānghǎo gǎnshàng mòbānchē. We just managed to catch the last bus. 这件上衣你穿着不大不小, 刚好。 Zhè jiàn shàngyī nǐ chuānzhuó bùdàbùxiǎo, gānghǎo. This jacket fits you beautifully. 我体重刚好五十公斤。 Wǒ tǐzhòng gānghǎo wǔshí gōngjīn. I weigh just 50 kilograms, no more, no less. 你们来得刚好。 Nǐmen lái de gānghǎo. You've come in the nick of time. 2 by chance; by coincidence 他们两人刚好编在一个组里。 Tāmen liǎng rén gānghǎo biān zài yī ge zǔ lǐ. The two of them happened to be in the same group. 刚好校长在这儿, 你就跟他谈谈吧。 Gānghǎo xiàozhǎng zài zhèr, nǐ jiù gēn tā tán tán ba. The Chancellor happens to be here. You'd better talk it over with him.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>松了</headword>
		<pron tones="song1 le5"/>
		<defn>VERB to loosen</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>脸</headword>
		<pron tones="lian3"/>
		<defn>1 face (of people or animals) 洗脸 xǐliǎn wash one's face 2 the front part of sth. ▶ 门脸儿 ménliǎnr 3 face (fig.) 脸上下不来 liǎnshàng xiàbulái haven't the face to do sth. 4 facial expression; face 把脸一变 bǎ liǎn yī biàn get angry</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>刷</headword>
		<pron tones="shua1"/>
		<defn>1 a brush 油漆刷 yóuqī shuā paintbrush 2 clean with a brush; brush; scrub 刷鞋 shuāxié brush shoes 刷地板 shuā dìbǎn scrub the floor 刷锅 shuā guō clean (or scour) a pot 3 paint, daub, paste up, etc. with a brush 用石灰浆刷墙 yòng shíhuī jiāng shuā qiáng whitewash a wall 刷标语 shuā biāoyǔ paste up posters 4 informal eliminate; remove 那个队直到半决赛才给刷下来。 Nà ge duì zhídào bànjuésài cái gěi shuā xiàlai. That team was not eliminated until the semifinals. 
onomatope swish; rustle 玉米叶子被风吹得刷刷响。 Yùmǐ yèzi bèi fēng chuī de shuā shuā xiǎng. The corn leaves rustled in the wind. See 刷shuà</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>终于</headword>
		<pron tones="zhong1yu2"/>
		<defn>adverb at (long) last; in the end; finally 她终于到了, 晚了将近半小时。 Tā zhōngyú dào le, wǎn le jiāngjìn bàn xiǎoshí. At long last she arrived, about half an hour late. 中国登山队终于胜利地登上了珠峰。 Zhōngguó dēngshānduì zhōngyú shènglì de dēng shàng le Zhūfēng. The Chinese mountaineering expedition finally succeeded in scaling Mount Qomolangma. 尽管多方医治, 终于还是把他受伤的腿锯了。 Jǐnguǎn duōfāng yīzhì, zhōngyú háishi bǎ tā shòushāng de tuǐ jù le. All the treatments were to no avail and in the end they had to amputate his wounded leg.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>忍</headword>
		<pron tones="ren3"/>
		<defn>1 bear; endure; tolerate; put up with 相忍相安 xiāng rěn xiāng ān be tolerant towards and live in peace with one another 他忍着剧痛, 继续工作。 Tā rěn zhe jùtòng, jìxù gōngzuò. He continued to work despite the intense pain. 你就忍着点吧。 Nǐ jiù rěn zhe diǎn ba. You will just have to put up with it. 忍着眼泪 Rěn zhe yǎnlèi hold back one's tears 2 be hardhearted enough to; have the heart to ▶ 残忍 cánrěn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>醒来</headword>
		<pron tones="xing3lai2"/>
		<defn>to waken</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>本来</headword>
		<pron tones="ben3lai2"/>
		<defn>1 original 本来的意思 běnlái de yìsi original meaning (or intention) 事物本来的辩证法 shìwù běnlái de biànzhèngfǎ the dialectics inherent in things 2 adverb originally; at first 大会本来定星期五举行。 Dàhuì běnlái dìng Xīngqīwǔ jǔxíng. The meeting was originally fixed for Friday. 他本来身体很瘦弱。 Tā běnlái shēntǐ hěn shòuruò. He used to be thin and weak. 3 adverb it goes without saying; of course 本来就该这样办。 Běnlái jiù gāi zhèyàng bàn. Of course it should be handled that way. 你本来用不着着急。 Nǐ běnlái yòngbuzháo zháojí. You needn't have worried about it. 这样的事本来不应该发生。 Zhèyàng de shì běnlái bù yīnggāi fāshēng. Such a thing should never have been allowed to happen in the first place.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>没想到</headword>
		<pron tones="mei2xiang3dao4"/>
		<defn>didn't expect</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>正</headword>
		<pron tones="zheng4"/>
		<defn>0 justamente 1 straight; upright ∼前方 ∼qiánfāng straight ahead ∼东(南、西、北) ∼dōng(nán, xī, běi) due east (south, west, north) 把柱子扶∼ bǎ zhùzi fú ∼ set the post upright 这幅画挂得不∼。 Zhè fú huà guà de bù ∼. This picture is not straight. 2 situated in the middle; main ▶ ∼门 zhèngmén , ∼厅 zhèngtīng 3 punctually; sharp 九点∼ Jiǔ diǎn ∼ at nine o'clock sharp 4 obverse; right 布的这一面是∼的吗？ Bù de zhè yī miàn shì ∼ de ma？ Is this the right side of the cloth? 这件茄克∼穿反穿都可以。 Zhè jiàn jiā kè ∼ chuān fǎn chuān dōu kěyǐ. You can wear this jacket inside out. 5 honest; upright 他作风不∼。 Tā zuòfēng bù ∼. His behaviour is not proper. 6 correct; right 路子走得∼ Lùzi zǒu de ∼ follow a correct path 7 (of colour, flavour, etc.) pure; right ∼黄 ∼ huáng pure yellow 味儿不∼ wèir bù ∼ not the right flavour 8 regular; standard ▶ ∼楷 zhèngkǎi 9 (opp. 副 “secondary, vice-”) principal; chief ∼副主任 ∼-fù zhǔrèn director and deputy director ∼驾驶员 ∼ jiàshǐyuán first pilot (opp. 副驾驶员“copilot”) 10 (of figures, designs, etc.) regular ∼八边形 ∼bābiānxíng regular octagon ∼多面体 ∼ duōmiàntǐ regular polyhedron 11 mathematics positive 12 physics positive; plus ∼晶体 ∼ jīngtǐ positive crystal ∼离子 ∼lízǐ positive ion; cation 13 rectify; straighten; set right 把帽子∼一∼ bǎ màozi ∼ yī ∼ put one's cap straight 把领带∼一∼ bǎ lǐngdài ∼ yī ∼ straighten one's tie 14 make right; correct ▶ ∼误 zhèngwù , ∼音 zhèngyīn 15 adverb just; right; precisely; exactly ∼如上文所述 ∼ rú shàngwén suǒ shù just as mentioned above 大小∼合适 dàxiǎo ∼ héshì just the right size 我∼要谈这个问题。 Wǒ ∼ yào tán zhège wèntí. I'm just coming to that point. 这∼是我想要的。 Zhè ∼shì wǒ xiǎng yào de. This is exactly what I want. 那人∼是张先生。 Nà rén ∼ shì zhāng xiānsheng. It was none other than Mr. Zhang. 到剧场∼赶上开演。 Dào jùchǎng ∼ gǎnshàng kāiyǎn. I got to the theatre just as the performance was starting. ∼是这些人创造了如此伟大的奇迹。 ∼shì zhèxiē rén chuàngzào le rúcǐ wěidà de qíjì. They are the very people who worked such wonders. 16 adverb just (doing sth.); just now 他∼吃着饭呢。 Tā ∼ chī zhe fàn ne. He's eating just now. ∼下着雨呢。 ∼ xià zhe yǔ ne. It's raining. See ∼zhēng</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>端</headword>
		<pron tones="duan1"/>
		<defn>0 llevar 1 end; extremity 两∼ liǎng∼ both ends 岛的南∼ dǎo de nán∼ the southern tip (or end) of the island 2 beginning ▶ 开∼ kāiduān 3 point; item 举其一∼ jǔ qí yī ∼ for instance; just to mention one example 4 reason; cause ▶ 无∼ wú∼ , 借∼ jiè∼ 
1 upright; proper ∼坐 ∼zuò sit up straight 2 hold sth. level with both hands; carry ∼盘子 ∼ pánzi carry a tray ∼饭上菜 ∼ fàn shàng cài serve a meal ∼进两杯茶来 ∼ jìn liǎng bēi chá lái bring in two cups of tea 给病人∼大小便 gěi bìngrén ∼ dàxiǎobiàn carry bedpans for the patients 有什么想法都∼出来。 Yǒu shénme xiǎngfa dōu ∼ chūlai. Whatever you think, come out with it.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>家庭</headword>
		<pron tones="jia1ting2"/>
		<defn>family; household 他有一个美满幸福的家庭。 Tā yǒu yī ge měimǎn xìngfú de jiātíng. He has a happy family. 现在差不多每个家庭都有电冰箱了。 Xiànzài chàbuduō měi ge jiātíng dōu yǒu diànbīngxiāng le. Now almost every household owns a fridge.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>钱包</headword>
		<pron tones="qian2bao1"/>
		<defn>wallet; purse</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>篇</headword>
		<pron tones="pian1"/>
		<defn>1 a piece of writing ▶ 篇章 piānzhāng 2 sheet (of paper, etc.) 歌篇儿 gē piānr song sheet 单篇儿油印材料 dān piānr yóuyìn cáiliào mimeographed sheets 3 measure word (for paper, book leaves, articles, etc.) sheet; leaf; piece 三篇儿纸 sān piānr zhǐ three sheets (or pieces) of paper 一篇文章 yī piān wénzhāng a piece of writing; an article 这本书缺了一篇儿。 Zhè běn shū quē le yī piānr. One leaf is missing from this book.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>衬衣</headword>
		<pron tones="chen4yi1"/>
		<defn>1 underclothes; undergarments 2 shirt</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>否则</headword>
		<pron tones="fou3ze2"/>
		<defn>conjunction otherwise; if not; or else 快点走, 否则要迟到了。 Kuài diǎn zǒu, fǒuzé yào chídào le. Hurry up, or we'll be late. 他一定有要紧事找你, 否则不会接连打三次电话来。 Tā yīdìng yǒu yàojǐn shì zhǎo nǐ, fǒuzé bù huì jiēlián dǎ sān cì diànhuà lái. He must have something urgent to discuss with you, otherwise he wouldn't have phoned you three times. 我们必须加强基础工业的建设, 否则经济发展就没有后劲。 Wǒmen bìxū jiāqiáng jīchǔ gōngyè de jiànshè, fǒuzé jīngjì fāzhǎn jiù méi yǒu hòujìn. Basic industries must be strengthened; otherwise economic development cannot be sustained.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>马路</headword>
		<pron tones="ma3lu4"/>
		<defn>road; street; avenue 逛马路 guàng mǎlù stroll around the streets; go window-shopping</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>考问</headword>
		<pron tones="kao3wen4"/>
		<defn>examine orally; question</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>座位</headword>
		<pron tones="zuo4wei4"/>
		<defn>a place to sit; seat 这个体育馆有一万八千个座位。 Zhège tǐyùguǎn yǒu yīwàn bāqiān ge zuòwèi. The stadium seats 18,000.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>做完了</headword>
		<pron tones="zuo4wan2 le5"/>
		<defn>VERB PHRASE to have finished</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>写完</headword>
		<pron tones="xie3wan2"/>
		<defn>to finish writing</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>看完</headword>
		<pron tones="kan4wan2"/>
		<defn>VERB to finish reading</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>听完</headword>
		<pron tones="ting1wan2"/>
		<defn>VERB to finish listening</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>说完</headword>
		<pron tones="shuo1 wan2"/>
		<defn>VERB to finish speaking</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>吃完</headword>
		<pron tones="chi1wan2"/>
		<defn>to finish eating</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>听见</headword>
		<pron tones="ting1jian4"/>
		<defn>hear 我听见有人敲门。 Wǒ tīng jiàn yǒurén qiāo mén. I heard a knock at the door. 她说的什么你听见了吗？ Tā shuō de shénme nǐ tīng jiàn le ma？ Did you catch what she said? 说话的声音小得几乎听不见 shuōhuà de shēngyīn xiǎo de jīhū tīng bù jiàn speak in a scarcely audible voice 你小点儿声, 我听得见。 Nǐ xiǎo diǎnr shēng, wǒ tīng de jiàn. Lower your voice. I can hear you. 我听了一会儿, 可什么也没听见。 Wǒ tīng le yīhuìr, kě shénme yě méi tīngjiàn. I listened for a while, but heard nothing. 他耳背, 听不见。 Tā ěrbèi, tīng bù jiàn. He's hard of hearing. He can't hear you.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>闻见</headword>
		<pron tones="wen2jian5"/>
		<defn>1 notice by smell; smell 我闻见了花香。 Wǒ wén jian le huāxiāng. I smell the fragrance of a flower. 2 hear</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>看见</headword>
		<pron tones="kan4jian5"/>
		<defn>catch sight of; see 你看见老张了吗？ Nǐ kànjian lǎo zhāng le ma？ Did you see Lao Zhang? 我看了好半天, 可是什么也没看见。 Wǒ kàn le hǎo bàntiān, kě shì shénme yě méi kànjian. I looked for a while but didn't see anything. 他们航行了二十天才看见陆地。 Tāmen hángxíng le èrshí tiān cái kànjian lùdì. They sighted land after being at sea for twenty days. 黑板上的字你看得见吗？ Hēibǎn shàng de zì nǐ kàn de jiàn ma？ Can you see the words on the blackboard?</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>打开</headword>
		<pron tones="da3kai1"/>
		<defn>1 open; unfold 把门打开 Bǎ mén dǎkāi open the door 打开盖子 dǎkāi gàizi take off the lid 打开包袱 dǎkāi bāofu untie a bundle 打开缺口 dǎkāi quēkǒu make a breach 打开眼界 dǎkāi yǎnjiè widen one's horizon 打开局面 dǎkāi júmiàn open up a new prospect; make a breakthrough 2 turn on; switch on 打开收音机(电灯) dǎkāi shōuyīnjī (diàndēng) turn on the radio (light)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>解开</headword>
		<pron tones="jie3kai1"/>
		<defn>untie; undo 解开头巾 Jiěkāi tóujīn untie a kerchief 解开上衣 jiěkāi shàngyī unbutton one's jacket 解开这个谜 jiěkāi zhège mí find a clue to the mystery 解开疑团 jiěkāi yítuán clear up suspicions 解开疙瘩 jiěkāi gēda get rid of a hang-up</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>学会</headword>
		<pron tones="xue2hui4"/>
		<defn>learn; master 你的功课学会了吗？ Nǐ de gōngkè xuéhuì le ma？ Have you learned your lessons? 她学会了游泳。 Tā xuéhuì le yóuyǒng. She's learned to swim. 学会多种外国语 Xuéhuì duōzhǒng wàiguóyǔ master quite a number of foreign languages 
learned society; society; institute 中国人民外交学会 Zhōngguó rénmín wàijiāo xuéhuì the Chinese People's Institute of Foreign Affairs 物理学会 wùlǐxué huì the Physics Society</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>听懂</headword>
		<pron tones="ting1dong3"/>
		<defn>1 to understand (on hearing) 2 to catch (what is spoken)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>看懂</headword>
		<pron tones="kan4dong3"/>
		<defn>to understand what one is reading or watching</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>走到</headword>
		<pron tones="zou3dao4"/>
		<defn>VERB to go to</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>跑到</headword>
		<pron tones="pao3dao4"/>
		<defn>VERB to have run to</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>找到</headword>
		<pron tones="zhao3dao4"/>
		<defn>to find</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>说道</headword>
		<pron tones="shuo1dao4"/>
		<defn>say (the words quoted) 少先队员说道：“我们要向雷锋叔叔学习”。 Shào-Xiān-duì yuán shuōdào ： “wǒmen yào xiàng Léi Fēng shūshu xuéxí”. “We must learn from Uncle Lei Feng,” said the Young Pioneer.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>坐在</headword>
		<pron tones="zuo4 zai4"/>
		<defn>VERB to sit on</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>住在</headword>
		<pron tones="zhu4 zai4"/>
		<defn>VERB to live in</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>睡着</headword>
		<pron tones="shui4zhao2"/>
		<defn>to fall asleep</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>看错</headword>
		<pron tones="kan4cuo4"/>
		<defn>1 a mistake 2 an oversight 3 an error of judgment</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>拿好</headword>
		<pron tones="na2 hao3"/>
		<defn>VERB to hold</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>准备好</headword>
		<pron tones="zhun3bei4 hao3"/>
		<defn>VERB to be ready</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>准备好了</headword>
		<pron tones="zhun3bei4hao3le5"/>
		<defn>to be ready</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>看清楚</headword>
		<pron tones="kan4qing1chu5"/>
		<defn>VERB to see clearly</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>听清楚</headword>
		<pron tones="ting1 qing1chu5"/>
		<defn>VERB to hear clearly</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>吃饱</headword>
		<pron tones="chi1bao3"/>
		<defn>to eat one's fill</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>喝醉</headword>
		<pron tones="he1zui4"/>
		<defn>to get drunk</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>吃坏</headword>
		<pron tones="chi1huai4"/>
		<defn>to get sick because of bad food</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>花掉</headword>
		<pron tones="hua1diao4"/>
		<defn>1 to spend (time, money) 2 to waste</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>爷爷</headword>
		<pron tones="ye2ye5"/>
		<defn>informal 1 (paternal) grandfather 2 grandpa (a respectful form of address for any old man)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>奶奶</headword>
		<pron tones="nai3nai5"/>
		<defn>informal 1 (paternal) grandmother; grandma 2 a respectful form of address for an old woman 3 dialect young mistress of the house</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>外公</headword>
		<pron tones="wai4gong1"/>
		<defn>dialect (maternal) grandfather</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>外婆</headword>
		<pron tones="wai4po2"/>
		<defn>dialect (maternal) grandmother</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>爸爸</headword>
		<pron tones="ba4ba5"/>
		<defn>papa; dad; father</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>哥哥</headword>
		<pron tones="ge1ge5"/>
		<defn>(elder) brother</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>姐姐</headword>
		<pron tones="jie3jie5"/>
		<defn>elder sister; sister</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>我</headword>
		<pron tones="wo3"/>
		<defn>1 I or me 2 we or us 我方 wǒfāng our side; we 我军 wǒjūn our army 3 (used coordinately with 你 in parallel structures) one; anyone 大家你帮我, 我帮你, 很快就把活儿干完了。 Dàjiā nǐ bāng wǒ,  wǒ bāng nǐ, hěn kuài jiù bǎ huór gàn wán le. With each one giving the other a hand, they soon got the job done. 4 self ▶ 自我 zìwǒ , 忘我 wàngwǒ</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>弟弟</headword>
		<pron tones="di4di5"/>
		<defn>younger brother; brother</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>妹妹</headword>
		<pron tones="mei4mei5"/>
		<defn>younger sister; sister</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>嫂子</headword>
		<pron tones="sao3zi5"/>
		<defn>informal elder brother's wife; sister-in-law</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>姐夫</headword>
		<pron tones="jie3fu5"/>
		<defn>elder sister's husband; brother-in-law</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>弟妹</headword>
		<pron tones="di4mei4"/>
		<defn>1 informal younger brother's wife; sister-in-law 2 younger brother and sister</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>妹夫</headword>
		<pron tones="mei4fu5"/>
		<defn>younger sister's husband; brother-in-law</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>女儿</headword>
		<pron tones="nü3er2"/>
		<defn>daughter; girl</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>儿媳</headword>
		<pron tones="er2xi2"/>
		<defn>daughter-in-law</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>女婿</headword>
		<pron tones="nü3xu5"/>
		<defn>1 son-in-law 2 informal husband</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>孙子</headword>
		<pron tones="sun1zi5"/>
		<defn>son's son; grandson</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>孙女</headword>
		<pron tones="sun1nü3"/>
		<defn>son's daughter; granddaughter</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>外孙</headword>
		<pron tones="wai4sun1"/>
		<defn>daughter's son; grandson</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>外孙女</headword>
		<pron tones="wai4sun1nü3"/>
		<defn>daughter's daughter; granddaughter</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>网友</headword>
		<pron tones="wang3you3"/>
		<defn>computing online friend</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>女士</headword>
		<pron tones="nü3shi4"/>
		<defn>(a polite term for a woman, married or unmarried) lady; madam 女士们, 先生们! Nǚshì men, xiānsheng men! Ladies and gentlemen!</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>帮忙</headword>
		<pron tones="bang1mang2"/>
		<defn>help; give (or lend) a hand; do a favour; do a good turn 我要请她帮忙。 Wǒ yào qǐng tā bāngmáng. I'll ask her to help. 他来找人帮忙。 Tā lái zhǎo rén bāngmáng. He came for help. 他帮了大忙。 Tā bāng le dà máng. He's been a great help. or He's given a lot of help. 请你帮个忙。 Qǐng nǐ bāng ge máng. Will you give me a hand? 他帮不上我什么忙。 Tā bāng bù shàng wǒ shénme máng. There's hardly anything he can help me with. 他帮过我们的忙。 Tā bāng guò wǒmen de máng. He once did us a good turn. 帮忙把这封信寄一下好吗？ Bāngmáng bǎ zhè fēng xìn jì yī xià hǎo ma？ Will you do me a favour and mail this letter? 我能帮什么忙吗？ Wǒ néng bāng shénme máng ma？ Can I be of any assistance?</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>遇到</headword>
		<pron tones="yu4dao4"/>
		<defn>run into; encounter; come across 在路上遇到一个老同学 zài lùshang yùdào yī ge lǎo tóngxué run into an old schoolmate on the way 遇到意外的问题 yùdào yìwài de wèntí come across unforeseen problems 遇到埋伏 yùdào máifú run into an ambush</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>群</headword>
		<pron tones="qun2"/>
		<defn>1 crowd; group ▶ 人群 rénqún 2 measure word (for people or animals) group; herd; flock 一群小孩 yī qún xiǎohái a group of children 一群人 yī qún rén a crowd of people 一群牛 yī qún niú a herd of cattle 一群羊 yī qún yáng a flock of sheep 一群狼 yī qún láng a pack of wolves 一群蜜蜂 yī qún mìfēng a swarm of bees</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>旅客</headword>
		<pron tones="lü3ke4"/>
		<defn>hotel guest; traveller; passenger 过往旅客 Guòwǎng lǚkè travellers passing through; transients</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>聊</headword>
		<pron tones="liao2"/>
		<defn>1 to chat 2 to depend upon (literary) 3 temporarily 4 just 5 slightly</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>通过</headword>
		<pron tones="tong1guo4"/>
		<defn>0 a través 1 pass through; get past; traverse 电流∼导线。 Diànliú ∼ dǎoxiàn. Electricity passes through the wires. 路太窄, 汽车∼不∼。 Lù tài zhǎi, qìchē tōng bù guò. The road is too narrow for cars to get by (or pass through). 注意交∼安全, 一慢二看三∼。 Zhùyì jiāotōng ānquán, yī màn èr kàn sān ∼. Pay attention to traffic safety; slow down, look around and then go ahead. 火车∼大桥向南奔去。 Huǒchē ∼ dà qiáo xiàng nán bēn qù. The train was crossing the bridge towards the south. 游击队∼了敌人的封锁线。 Yóujīduì ∼ le dírén de fēngsuǒxiàn. The guerrillas managed to get through the enemy blockade. 代表们∼大厅进入会场。 Dàibiǎo men ∼ dàtīng jìnrù huìchǎng. The delegates went through the lobby and into the assembly hall. or The delegates entered the assembly hall by way of the lobby. 她∼了入学考试。 Tā ∼ le rùxué kǎoshì. She's passed the entrance examination. 我们要打开局面就必须∼这一关。 Wǒmen yào dǎkāi júmiàn jiù bìxū ∼ zhè yī guān. We must overcome this obstacle to open a new phase in our work. 2 adopt; pass; carry ∼宪法 ∼ xiànfǎ adopt a constitution 以压倒多数∼ yǐ yādǎo duōshù ∼ be passed by an overwhelming majority 这个提案已一致∼。 Zhège tí'àn yǐ yīzhì ∼. The motion was carried unanimously. 我认为这议案未必∼得∼。 Wǒ rènwéi zhè yì'àn wèibì tōng de guò. I don't think the bill will get (or go) through. 3 ask the consent or approval of 这个问题要∼群众才能做出决定。 Zhège wèntí yào ∼ qúnzhòng cái néng zuòchū juédìng. No decision can be made on this matter until the masses have been consulted. 
preposition by means of; by way of; by; through ∼什么方式我才能见到他？ ∼ shénme fāngshì wǒ cái néng jiàndào tā？ By what means can I meet him? ∼讨论取得一致 ∼ tǎolùn qǔdé yīzhì reach unanimity through discussion 这位法国教授∼译员同我进行了交谈。 Zhè wèi Fǎguó jiàoshòu ∼ yìyuán tóng wǒ jìnxíng le jiāotán. The French professor and I had a conversation through an interpreter. ∼老张介绍, 我认识了她。 ∼ lǎo zhāng jièshào, wǒ rènshi le tā. I got to know her through Lao Zhang. 植物∼阳光照射, 能把水和二氧化碳制成有机物质。 Zhíwù ∼ yángguāng zhàoshè, néng bǎ shuǐ hé èryǎnghuàtàn zhìchéng yǒujī wùzhì. Plants can turn water and carbon dioxide into organic substance by means of sunshine.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>帖子</headword>
		<pron tones="tie3zi5"/>
		<defn>1 invitation 2 note; card</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>网上</headword>
		<pron tones="wang3shang4"/>
		<defn>computing online</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>改变</headword>
		<pron tones="gai3bian4"/>
		<defn>change; alter; transform 改变主意 gǎibiàn zhǔyì change one's mind 人们的精神面貌改变了。 Rénmen de jīngshén miànmào gǎibiàn le. People's spiritual complexion has changed. 五年不见, 他的样子看来没有多大的改变。 Wǔ nián bù jiàn, tā de yàngzi kànlai méiyǒu duō dà de gǎibiàn. It's been 5 years since I last saw him, but he hasn't changed much. 历史发展的总趋势是不可改变的。 Lìshǐ fāzhǎn de zǒng qūshì shì bùkě gǎibiàn de. The general trend of history is unalterable. 情况变了, 你那计划也该改变改变。 Qíngkuàng biàn le, nǐ nà jìhuà yě gāi gǎibiàn gǎibiàn. The situation has changed, so you should make some changes in your plans.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>互相</headword>
		<pron tones="hu4xiang1"/>
		<defn>adverb mutually; each other 互相依存 hùxiāng yīcún depend on each other for existence; be interdependent 互相排斥 hùxiāng páichì be mutually exclusive 互相配合 hùxiāng pèihé work in coordination 互相利用 hùxiāng lìyòng each using the other for his own ends 互相掣肘 hùxiāng chèzhǒu hold each other back 互相勾结 hùxiāng gōujié work in collusion</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>自由</headword>
		<pron tones="zi4you2"/>
		<defn>1 freedom; liberty 公民自由权 gōngmín zìyóuquán civil liberties 中国公民有言论, 通信, 出版, 集会, 结社, 游行, 示威, 罢工的自由。 Zhōngguó gōngmín yǒu yánlùn,  tōngxìn,  chūbǎn,  jíhuì,  jiéshè,  yóuxíng,  shìwēi, bàgōng de zìyóu. Citizens of China enjoy freedom of speech, correspondence, the press, assembly, association, procession, demonstration and the freedom to strike. 2 philosophy freedom 自由和必然 Zìyóu hé bìrán freedom and necessity 3 free; unrestrained 自由讨论 zìyóu tǎolùn have a free exchange of views 自由选择 zìyóu xuǎnzé be free to choose; have a free choice 自由行动 zìyóu xíngdòng act on one's own 自由发表意见 zìyóu fābiǎo yìjian express one's views unreservedly</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>上网</headword>
		<pron tones="shang4wang3"/>
		<defn>1 computing get on the internet 2 stretch a net (sports)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>对</headword>
		<pron tones="dui4"/>
		<defn>1 answer; reply 无言以对 wúyányǐduì have nothing to say in reply 2 treat; cope with; counter 刀对刀,枪对枪 dāo duì dāo, qiāng duì qiāng sword against sword and spear against spear 上海队对北京队 Shànghǎi duì duì Běijīng duì the Shanghai team versus the Beijing team 3 be trained on; be directed at 枪口对着敌人 qiāngkǒu duì zhe dírén train the gun on the enemy 她的话不是对着你的。 Tā de huà bù shì duì zhe nǐ de. What she said was not directed at you. 4 mutual; face to face 对骂 duìmà call each other names 对坐 duìzuò sit facing each other 对饮 duìyǐn (two people) have a drink together 5 opposite; opposing 对岸 duì'àn the opposite bank; the other side of the river 6 bring (two things) into contact; fit one into the other 对暗号 duì ànhào exchange code words 这个榫头对不上。 Zhège sǔntou duì bù shàng. This tenon won't fit. 7 suit; agree; get along 对心眼儿 duìxīnyǎnr suit one down to the ground 对胃口 duì wèikǒu suit one's taste 8 compare; check; identify 对笔迹 duì bǐjì identify the handwriting 对号码 duì hàomǎ check numbers 9 set; adjust 对表 duì biǎo set one's watch; synchronize watches 对好望远镜的距离 duì hǎo wàngyuǎnjìng de jùlí adjust the focus of a telescope 10 right; correct 猜对了 cāi duìle guess right 这事你做得对。 Zhè shì nǐ zuò de duì. You did the right thing. 你说得很对。 Nǐ shuō de hěn duì. What you say is quite true. 对, 就这么办。 Duì, jiù zhème bàn. All right, just go ahead. 他今天神色不对。 Tā jīntiān shénsè bùduì. He doesn't look himself today. 11 mix; add 茶太浓了, 给我对点儿水。 Chá tài nóng le, gěi wǒ duì diǎnr shuǐ. Add some water to the tea, it's too strong for me. 12 divide into halves 对股劈 duìgǔ pī go halves; split fifty-fifty 13 antithetical couplet; couplet 喜对 xǐ duì wedding couplet 14 measure word pair; couple 一对花瓶 yī duì huāpíng a pair of vases 一对夫妇 yī duì fūfù a married couple 15 preposition with regard to; concerning; to 对敌狠, 对己和 duìdí hěn, duì jǐ hé ruthless to the enemy, kind to one's comrades 对这个问题的不同意见 duì zhège wèntí de bùtóng yìjian different views on this question 对青少年的教育工作 duì qīng-shàonián de jiàoyù gōngzuò educational work among young people 对无产阶级革命事业的必胜信念 duì wúchǎn jiējí gémìng shìyè de bìshèng xìnniàn a firm belief in the ultimate triumph of the proletarian revolution 对犯罪分子实行法律制裁 duì fànzuì fènzǐ shíxíng fǎlǜ zhìcái carry out legal sanctions against criminals 对健康不利 duì jiànkāng bùlì be bad for one's health 他对他父亲很尊敬。 Tā duì tā fùqin hěn zūnjìng. He has a great respect for his father. 这录音机对我来说是够好的了。 Zhè lùyīnjī duì wǒ láishuō shì gòu hǎo de le. This recorder is good enough for me.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>错</headword>
		<pron tones="cuo4"/>
		<defn>1 mistake 2 wrong 3 bad 4 interlocking 5 complex 6 to grind 7 to polish 8 to alternate 9 to stagger 10 to miss 11 to let slip 12 to evade 13 to inlay with gold or silver</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>难</headword>
		<pron tones="nan2"/>
		<defn>1 difficult; hard; troublesome 很难想像 Hěn nán xiǎngxiàng it's hard to imagine 这道题难解。 Zhè dào tí nán jiě. This problem is hard to solve. 山路难走。 Shānlù nán zǒu. Mountain paths are hard to travel. 说起来容易, 做起来难。 Shuō qǐlai róngyì, zuò qǐlai nán. It's easier said than done. 2 put sb. into a difficult position 这问题一下子把我难住了。 Zhè wèntí yīxiàzi bǎ wǒ nán zhù le. The question put me on the spot. 3 hardly possible ▶ 难免 nánmiǎn , 难说 nánshuō 4 bad; unpleasant ▶ 难吃 nánchī , 难看 nánkàn See 难nàn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>容易</headword>
		<pron tones="rong2yi4"/>
		<defn>1 easy 蛙泳容易。 Wāyǒng róngyì. It's easy to do breaststroke. 容易的题先做。 Róngyì de tí xiān zuò. Do the easy problems first. 这台机床容易操作。 Zhè tái jīchuáng róngyì cāozuò. This lathe is easy to operate. 说起来容易做起来难。 Shuō qǐlai róngyì zuò qǐlai nán. It's easier said than done. 这种草药很容易弄到。 Zhèzhǒng cǎoyào hěn róngyì nòng dào. This medicinal herb is easy to come by. 今天的幸福来得不容易。 Jīntiān de xìngfú lái de bù róngyì. The present happy life didn't come about easily. 2 likely; liable; apt 他容易生病。 Tā róngyì shēngbìng. He often gets ill. 这容易引起误会。 Zhè róngyì yǐnqǐ wùhuì. This is liable to cause misunderstanding. 人们容易把这两个问题混淆起来。 Rénmen róngyì bǎ zhè liǎng ge wèntí hùnxiáo qǐlai. People are apt to confuse the two issues.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>快</headword>
		<pron tones="kuai4"/>
		<defn>1 fast; quick; rapid; swift 请别说得那么快。 Qǐng bié shuō de nàme kuài. Please don't speak so fast. 我的表快五分。 Wǒ de biǎo kuài wǔfēn. My watch is five minutes fast. 他学东西快。 Tā xué dōngxi kuài. He learns quickly. 他进步很快。 Tā jìnbù hěn kuài. He has made rapid progress. 快马 kuàimǎ a swift horse 2 speed 这车能跑多快？ Zhè chē néng pǎo duō kuài？ How fast can this car go？ 3 hurry up; make haste 快上车吧! Kuài shàngchē ba! Hurry up and get on the bus! 快点儿, 车要赶不上了! Kuài diǎnr, chē yào gǎn bù shàng le! Come on, or we'll miss the bus! 快跟我走。 Kuài gēn wǒ zǒu. Quick, come with me. 4 adverb soon; before long 他快回来了。 Tā kuài huílai le. He'll be back soon. 这学期快结束了。 Zhè xuéqī kuài jiéshù le. The term will be over before long. 火车快开了。 Huǒchē kuài kāi le. The train is about to leave. 快吃午饭了。 Kuài chī wǔfàn le. It's almost time for lunch. 天快黑了。 Tiān kuài hēi le. It's getting dark. 快半夜了。 Kuài bànyè le. It's going on midnight. 快三十岁的人还没有个对象! Kuài sānshí suì de rén hái méiyǒu ge duìxiàng! The man's going on thirty but still doesn't have a girl friend! 我来了快两年了。 Wǒ lái le kuài liǎng nián le. I've been here for nearly two years. 春节快到了。 Chūnjié kuài dào le. The Spring Festival is drawing near. 5 quick-witted; nimble; clever 他脑子快。 Tā nǎozi kuài. He's quick-witted. or He has a quick mind. 6 (of a knife, sword, etc.) sharp 快刀 kuàidāo a sharp knife 7 straight-forward; forthright; plainspoken ▶ 快人快语 kuàirén-kuàiyǔ 8 pleased; happy; gratified ▶ 不快 bùkuài , 大快人心 dà kuài rénxīn 9 a yamen runner or officer charged with making arrests ▶ 捕快 bǔkuài</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>慢</headword>
		<pron tones="man4"/>
		<defn>1 slow 反应慢 fǎnyìng màn be slow to react 他看书看得慢。 Tā kàn shū kàn de màn. He reads slowly. 他跑得慢。 Tā pǎo de màn. He's a slow runner. 病人恢复得很慢。 Bìngrén huīfù de hěn màn. The patient is making a slow recovery. 火车慢慢地驶进了车站。 Huǒchē mànmàn de shǐ jìn le chēzhàn. Slowly the train pulled into the station. 公共汽车到站时慢了下来。 Gōnggòng qìchē dào zhàn shí màn le xiàlai. The bus slowed down as it approached the stop. 我的表慢五分钟。 Wǒ de biǎo màn wǔ fēnzhōng. My watch is five minutes slow. 这钟一天慢十秒。 Zhè zhōng yī tiān màn shí miǎo. This clock loses 10 seconds a day. 他慢慢会想通的。 Tā mànmàn huì xiǎng tōng de. He'll come round by and by. 慢行 mànxíng Drive Slow (highway sign) 2 (used in imperative sentences, alone or before verbs) 我这就给她打电话去。——慢!等票子拿到了再打。 Wǒ zhè jiù gěi tā dǎ diànhuà qù. —— Màn! Děng piàozi ná dào le zài dǎ. I'm going to ring her right away.--Just a moment! Not until we get the tickets. 你慢点儿吃。 Nǐ màn diǎnr chī. Don't rush through your meal. 慢慢来, 别着急。 Mànmàn lái, bié zháojí. Take your time and don't worry. 这事慢点儿告诉他, 等两天再说。 Zhè shì màn diǎnr gàosu tā, děng liǎng tiān zàishuō. Don't tell him the news just now; wait a couple of days. 
supercilious; rude ▶ 傲慢 àomàn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>胖</headword>
		<pron tones="pang4"/>
		<defn>fat; stout; plump 他胖起来了。 Tā pàng qǐlai le. He's getting fat. or He's putting on weight. See 胖pán</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>硬</headword>
		<pron tones="ying4"/>
		<defn>1 hard; stiff; tough 硬铅笔 Yìng qiānbǐ a hard pencil 硬领 yìnglǐng a stiff collar 硬刷子 yìng shuāzi a stiff brush 这根铁丝太硬, 弯不动。 Zhè gēn tiěsī tài yìng, wān bù dòng. The iron wire is too strong to bend. 2 strong; firm; tough; obstinate 心肠硬 Xīncháng yìng hardhearted 话说得很硬 huà shuō de hěn yìng express oneself in strong terms 硬不承认错误 yìng bù chéngrèn cuòwù obstinately refuse to admit one's error 硬的不行来软的。 Yìng de bùxíng lái ruǎn de. When hard tactics failed, soft methods were used. 3 manage to do sth. with difficulty 硬充好汉 yìng chōng hǎohàn act the hero 硬压住心头怒火 yìng yā zhù xīntóu nùhuǒ choke down one's anger 硬搬别人的经验 yìng bān biéren de jīngyàn copy other people's experience mechanically 4 good (quality); able (person) 货色硬 huòsè yìng goods of high quality 牌子硬 páizi yìng a trademark of high standing; a prestigious trademark</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>紧张</headword>
		<pron tones="jin3zhang1"/>
		<defn>1 nervous; keyed up 神情紧张 Shénqíng jǐnzhāng look nervous 慢慢讲, 别紧张。 Mànmàn jiǎng, bié jǐnzhāng. Speak slowly and don't be nervous. 试验到了关键时刻, 大家都紧张起来。 Shìyàn dào le guānjiàn shíkè, dàjiā dōu jǐnzhāng qǐlai. Everybody was keyed up as the experiment reached a crucial point. 2 tense; intense; strained 紧张局势 jǐnzhāng júshì a tense situation 紧张气氛 jǐnzhāng qìfēn a tense atmosphere 紧张的战斗 jǐnzhāng de zhàndòu intense fighting 两国关系紧张。 Liǎng guó guānxi jǐnzhāng. Relations between the two countries are strained. 紧张而有秩序的工作 Jǐnzhāng ér yǒu zhìxù de gōngzuò intense but orderly work 团结紧张的集体生活 tuánjié jǐnzhāng de jítǐ shēnghuó a collective life marked by solidarity and activity 这场比赛真紧张! Zhè chǎng bǐsài zhēn jǐnzhāng! What an exciting game! 工程正在紧张地进行。 Gōngchéng zhèngzài jǐnzhāng de jìnxíng. Construction was in full swing. 日程安排得太紧张。 Rìchéng ānpái de tài jǐnzhāng. It's rather a tight schedule. 缓和交通运输的紧张状况 Huǎnhé jiāotōng yùnshū de jǐnzhāng zhuàngkuàng relieve the pressure on transport 3 in short supply; tight 这几天鸡蛋供应有点紧张。 Zhè jǐ tiān jīdàn gōngyìng yǒudiǎn jǐnzhāng. Eggs have been in rather short supply for the last few days. or There's been rather a shortage of eggs lately. 这里只有一口井, 用水比较紧张。 Zhèlǐ zhǐ yǒu yī kǒu jǐng, yòng shuǐ bǐjiào jǐnzhāng. There's only one well here and water is in great demand. 目前这里住房相当紧张。 Mùqián zhèlǐ zhùfáng xiāngdāng jǐnzhāng. Accommodation here is pretty tight at present.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>高</headword>
		<pron tones="gao1"/>
		<defn>1 tall; high 这里地势很高。 Zhèlǐ dìshì hěn gāo. The terrain here is very high. 她比小红高一头。 Tā bǐ xiǎo hóng gāo yī tóu. She is a head taller than Xiao Hong. 坝高四十米。 Bà gāo sìshí mǐ. The dam is 40 metres high (or in height). 这片地中间高起一块。 Zhè piàn dì zhōngjiān gāo qǐ yī kuài. There is a mound in the middle of the field. 2 of a high level or degree; above the average 高速度 gāosùdù high speed 高年级 gāoniánjí higher (or senior) grades 高质量 gāo zhìliàng high (or good) quality 体温高 tǐwēn gāo have a fever 他的思想境界比我高。 Tā de sīxiǎng jìngjiè bǐ wǒ gāo. He has nobler thoughts than I. 他的见解比谁都高。 Tā de jiànjiě bǐ shuí dōu gāo. He has more original ideas than others do. 高风格 Gāo fēnggé fine style 高难度动作 gāonándù dòngzuò exceedingly difficult movements; operations of extraordinary difficulty 这主意真高! Zhè zhǔyi zhēn gāo! What a brilliant idea! 3 loud 嗓门高 Sǎngmén gāo have a loud voice 高喊 gāohǎn shout loudly; raise a cry 4 high-priced; dear; expensive 要价太高 yàojià tài gāo ask too high a price 5 honorific your ▶ 高见 gāojiàn 6 chemistry containing one more oxygen atom in an acid or a chemical compound ▶ 高锰酸钾 gāoměngsuānjiǎ 7 (Gāo) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>矮</headword>
		<pron tones="ai3"/>
		<defn>1 short (of stature) 我个子矮。 Wǒ gèzi ǎi. I'm short. 他比他哥哥矮一头。 Tā bǐ tā gēge ǎi yī tóu. He's a head shorter than his brother. 2 low 矮墙 ǎiqiáng a low wall 3 low in rank or grade 她在中学里比我矮一级。 Tā zài zhōngxué lǐ bǐ wǒ ǎi yījí. She was a grade lower than me in middle school.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>长</headword>
		<pron tones="chang2"/>
		<defn>1 (of space or time) long 这条河很长。 Zhè tiáo hé hěn cháng. This is a long river. 夏季昼长夜短。 Xiàjì zhòu chángyè duǎn. In summer the days are long and the nights short. 长长的柳条垂到湖面。 Cháng cháng de liǔtiáo chuí dào húmiàn. The long willow twigs hang low, brushing against the surface of the lake. 2 length 南京长江大桥全长六千七百七十二米。 Nánjīng Cháng Jiāng dà qiáo quáncháng liùqiān qībǎi qīshí'èr mǐ. The overall length of the Changjiang River Bridge at Nanjing is 6,772 metres. 3 strong point; forte 取人之长, 补己之短 Qǔ rén zhī cháng, bǔ jǐ zhī duǎn overcome one's shortcomings by learning from others' strong points 4 be good at; be proficient in 她长于刺绣。 Tā cháng yú cìxiù. She is good at embroidery. or Embroidery is her forte. See 长zhǎng</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>短</headword>
		<pron tones="duan3"/>
		<defn>1 short; brief 她头发剪得短短的。 Tā tóufa jiǎn de duǎnduǎn de. She had her hair cut short. 这条路最短。 Zhè tiáo lù zuì duǎn. This is the shortest way. 冬季日短夜长。 Dōngjì rì duǎn yè cháng. In winter the days are short and the nights long. 我给他写了封短信。 Wǒ gěi tā xiě le fēng duǎn xìn. I dropped him a few lines. 开个短会 Kāi ge duǎn huì have a brief meeting 2 lack; owe 一个月短两天 yī ge yuè duǎn liǎng tiān two days short of a month; a month less two days 别人都来了,就短他一个。 Biéren dōu lái le, jiù duǎn tā yī ge. All the others are here; he's the only one missing. 短你三块钱。 Duǎn nǐ sān kuài qián. I owe you three yuan. 3 weak point; fault ▶ 揭短 jiēduǎn</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>大</headword>
		<pron tones="da4"/>
		<defn>1 big; large; great 大城市 dà chéngshì big city 大眼睛 dà yǎnjing big eyes 大救星 dà jiùxīng great liberator 这张照片不够大。 Zhè zhāng zhàopiàn bù gòu dà. The picture isn't large enough. 2 heavy (rain, etc.); strong (wind, etc.) 雪下得很大。 Xuě xià de hěn dà. The snow is falling heavily. 风太大, 你没法放风筝。 Fēng tài dà, nǐ méi fǎ fàng fēngzheng. The wind is too strong to fly your kite. 外面风大。 Wàimian fēng dà. It's blowing hard. 团结起来力量大。 Tuánjié qǐlai lìliang dà. Unity is strength. 3 loud 声音太大 Shēngyīn tài dà too loud 收音机开大点。 Shōuyīnjī kāi dà diǎn. Turn the radio up a bit louder. 4 general; main; major 大马路 dàmǎlù main street 大问题 dà wèntí major issue; big problem 大手术 dàshǒushù major operation 大反攻 dà fǎngōng general counteroffensive 5 size 那间屋子有这间两个大。 Nà jiān wūzi yǒu zhè jiān liǎng ge dà. That roomis twice the size of this one. 你穿多大的鞋？ Nǐ chuān duō dà de xié？ What size shoes do you wear? 6 age 你的孩子多大了？ Nǐ de háizi duō dà le？ How old is your child? 他大我两岁。 Tā dà wǒ liǎng suì. He's two years my senior. 7 adverb greatly; fully 大长中国人民的志气 Dà zhǎng Zhōngguó rénmín de zhìqi greatly heighten the morale of the Chinese people 大笑 dàxiào laugh heartily 天已大亮。 Tiān yǐ dà liàng. It's already broad daylight. 8 adverb in a big way; on a big (or large) scale; with all-out efforts; vigorously 大删大改 Dà shān dà gǎi do a thorough job in revising 大搞农田水利 dà gǎo nóngtián shuǐlì go all out with irrigation and water conservancy 9 eldest 大哥 dàgē eldest brother 大房 dàfáng senior branch of a family 10 honorific your 大札 dàzhá your letter 大作 dàzuò your writing 11 (used before a time word, etc. to show emphasis) 大清早 dàqīngzǎo early in the morning 12 see 不大 bùdà 
dialect 1 father 2 father's brother; uncle See 大dài</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>小</headword>
		<pron tones="xiao3"/>
		<defn>1 small; little; petty; minor 小屋 xiǎowū a small room or house 小河 xiǎohé a small river 小姑娘 xiǎogūniang a little girl 小国 xiǎoguó a small country 小事 xiǎoshì a small matter 小问题 xiǎo wèntí a minor question 小手术 xiǎoshǒushù a minor operation 那个数量很小。 Nàge shùliàng hěn xiǎo. That's a very small amount. 你的声音太小。 Nǐ de shēngyīn tài xiǎo. Your voice is too soft. 风小些了。 Fēng xiǎo xiē le. The wind has dropped a little. 鞋小了点。 Xié xiǎo le diǎn. These shoes are a bit too tight. 2 young 他还小呢。 Tā hái xiǎo ne. He's still young. 你也不小了。 Nǐ yě bù xiǎo le. You're not young any more. 她比我小。 Tā bǐ wǒ xiǎo. She's younger than I am. 3 of short duration 小坐片刻 xiǎozuòpiànkè sit for a while 4 the last in order of seniority 小儿子 xiǎo'érzi the youngest son 他是我小弟弟。 Tā shì wǒ xiǎo dìdi. He is my youngest brother. 5 (used before names of animals to indicate the young) 小鸡 xiǎojī chick 小鸭 xiǎoyā duckling 小狗 xiǎo gǒu pup; puppy 小猫 xiǎomāo kitten; kitty 小牛 xiǎoniú calf; heifer 小羊 xiǎoyáng lamb; kid 小马 xiǎomǎ pony; foal; colt 小猪 xiǎozhū piggy; piglet; shoat 小鹿 xiǎolù deerlet; fawn 小老虎 xiǎolǎohǔ tiger cub 6 little ones; children 一家大小 yī jiā dà xiǎo the whole family, old and young 上有老, 下有小 shàng yǒu lǎo, xià yǒu xiǎo have the old above and the young below--have parents and children to care for 7 concubine 讨个小 tǎo ge xiǎo take a concubine 8 humble my; our 小女 xiǎonǚ my daughter 小店 xiǎodiàn my store 9 (used before family name, givenname, etc.) 小张 xiǎo zhāng Xiao Zhang 小强 xiǎo qiáng Xiao Qiang 小三儿 xiǎo sānr Xiao Sanr (childhood name for one's third child)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>男</headword>
		<pron tones="nan2"/>
		<defn>1 man; male 男病房 nánbìngfáng men's ward 男护士 nánhùshi male nurse 男主人公 nánzhǔréngōng hero 男学生 nánxuésheng boy student 男佣人 nányòngrén manservant 2 son; boy 长男 zhǎngnán one's eldest son 
baron ▶ 男爵 nánjué</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>年轻</headword>
		<pron tones="nian2qing1"/>
		<defn>young 年轻人 niánqīngrén young people 年轻力壮 niánqīnglìzhuàng young and vigorous 年轻一代 niánqīng yī dài the younger (or rising) generation 干部要年轻化。 Gànbù yào niánqīnghuà. Let the age of our government officials be younger in average.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>老</headword>
		<pron tones="lao3"/>
		<defn>1 old (not young) 老妇人 lǎofùrén an old woman 老马 lǎo mǎ an old horse 老树 lǎoshù an old tree 他父亲很老了。 Tā fùqin hěn lǎo le. His father is very old. 我老了, 走路走不快了。 Wǒ lǎo le, zǒulù zǒu bù kuài le. I'm getting old and can't walk very fast. 他六十多岁了, 可是一点也不显老。 Tā liùshí duō suì le, kěshì yīdiǎn yě bù xiǎn lǎo. He's over sixty, but he doesn't look old at all. 2 old people; a venerable old man 敬老 jìnglǎo show respect for the aged 徐老 xú lǎo our revered Comrade Xu 3 informal euphemistic (followed by 了; usu. of an old person) pass away; die 隔壁前天老了人了。 Gébì qiántiān lǎo le rén le. One of our next-door neighbours (presumably an old person) died the day before yesterday. 4 experienced; veteran 老作家 Lǎo zuòjiā a veteran writer 5 old (not new) 老朋友 lǎopéngyou an old friend 老部下 lǎo bùxia a former subordinate 老厂 lǎo chǎng an old factory 老机器 lǎo jīqì an old machine 老地方 lǎo dìfang the same old place 老习惯 lǎo xíguàn an old habit 一首老歌 yī shǒu lǎo gē an old song 这种纸烟牌子很老了。 Zhèzhǒng zhǐyān páizi hěn lǎo le. This is a very old brand of cigarettes. 这所房子太老了。 Zhè suǒ fángzi tài lǎo le. This house is too old. 6 (of vegetables) overgrown 菠菜不收就老了。 Bōcài bù shōu jiù lǎo le. The spinach will be overgrown if we don't get it in now. 7 (of food) tough; overdone; well-done 牛肉太老。 Niúròu tài lǎo. The beef is too tough. 我喜欢吃老一点的牛排。 Wǒ xǐhuan chī lǎo yīdiǎn de niúpái. I like steak quite well-done. 鸡蛋煮老了。 Jīdàn zhǔ lǎo le. The eggs have been boiled hard. 青菜不要炒得太老。 Qīngcài bùyào chǎo de tài lǎo. Don't overcook the greens. 8 (of certain colours) dark 老绿(红) Lǎo lǜ (hóng) dark green (red) 这件上衣颜色太老了。 Zhè jiàn shàngyī yánsè tài lǎo le. This jacket is too dark. 9 adverb for a long time 老没见你啊。 Lǎo méi jiàn nǐ a. I haven't seen you for ages. 这屋子老不住人, 有股霉味儿。 Zhè wūzi lǎo bù zhù rén, yǒu gǔ méi wèir. This room has been left vacant for a long time, so there is a mouldy smell. 10 adverb always; all the time 他老跟我借钱。 Tā lǎo gēn wǒ jiè qián. He's always borrowing money from me. 他老那么干。 Tā lǎo nàme gàn. He does it all the time. 11 adverb very 老早 lǎozǎo very early 老远 lǎoyuǎn far away 老长的胡子 lǎo cháng de húzi a very long beard 太阳已经老高了。 Tàiyáng yǐjing lǎo gāo le. The sun is already high. 12 informal last born; youngest 老闺女 lǎoguīnü the youngest daughter 老儿子 lǎo'érzi the youngest son 13 (used as a prefix) a (in terms of address before the surnames of acquaintances or friends to indicate intimacy or informality) 老王 lǎo wáng Lao Wang 老李 lǎo lǐ Lao Li b (in kinship terms before numerals to indicate order of seniority) 老大 lǎodà number one (among sons, daughters, brothers, or sisters) 老二 lǎo'èr number two 老三 lǎo sān number three 老幺 lǎoyāo the youngest c (in certain names of animals and plants) ▶ 老虎 lǎohǔ , 老玉米 lǎoyùmi 14 (Lǎo) a surname</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>好</headword>
		<pron tones="hao3"/>
		<defn>1 good; fine; nice 好人 hǎorén a nice person 天气真好。 Tiānqì zhēn hǎo. The weather's really nice. 祖国的好儿子 Zǔguó de hǎo érzi a worthy (or fine) son of our country 庄稼长得真好。 Zhuāngjia zhǎng de zhēn hǎo. The crops are doing well. 2 friendly; kind 好朋友 Hǎo péngyou a good (or great) friend 他们对我真好。 Tāmen duì wǒ zhēn hǎo. They are really kind to me. 这两个孩子又好了。 Zhè liǎng ge háizi yòu hǎo le. The two children are friends again. 3 be in good health; get well 我的病好了。 Wǒ de bìng hǎo le. I'm well (or all right) now. 你好哇! Nǐ hǎo wa! How are you? 4 be ready; done 饭好了。 Fàn hǎo le. The food (or rice) is ready. 5 (used after verbs to indicate finishing or finishing satisfactorily) 这件事他做不好。 Zhè jiàn shì tā zuò bù hǎo. He can't do that job well. 我把他的病治好了。 Wǒ bǎ tā de bìng zhì hǎo le. I cured his illness. 坐好吧, 要开会了。 Zuò hǎo ba, yào kāihuì le. Take your seats, please. The meeting is going to begin. 6 adverb (used before verbs) be good to; be easy to 好喝 hǎohē good to drink 这个问题好回答。 Zhège wèntí hǎo huídá. This question is easy to answer. 这本书可不好买。 Zhè běn shū kě bù hǎo mǎi. This book is not easily available. 暖瓶放在这儿好拿。 Nuǎnpíng fàng zài zhèr hǎo ná. It's handy to have the thermos here. 7 interjection (used at the beginning of a sentence or clause, to express agreement, disapproval, surprise, etc.) 好, 就这么办。 Hǎo, jiù zhème bàn. O.K. , it's settled. 好了, 不要再说了。 Hǎo le, bùyào zài shuō le. All right, no need to say any more. 好, 这下可麻烦了。 Hǎo, zhè xià kě máfan le. Well, we're in for trouble now. 好!那得多少钱! Hǎo! Nà dé duōshao qián! Gosh! How much money will that cost! 我一看, 好, 都走了。 Wǒ yī kàn,  hǎo, dōu zǒu le. I took a look, gosh, everybody has left. 8 adverb the better to; in order to; so that 今儿早点睡, 明儿好早起赶火车。 Jīnr zǎodiǎn shuì, míngr hǎo zǎoqǐ gǎn huǒchē. Let's turn in early, so as to get up early tomorrow to catch the train. 把她的地址告诉我, 我好找她。 Bǎ tā de dìzhǐ gàosu wǒ, wǒ hǎo zhǎo tā. Tell me her address so that I can go and see her. 9 adverb (used before adjectives with exclamatory force) very; quite; so 今天好冷。 Jīntiān hǎo lěng. Today is quite cold. 你好大胆子。 Nǐ hǎo dà dǎnzi. You are so daring. 好大的工程! Hǎo dà de gōngchéng! What a huge project! 10 adverb (used before adjectives in the same way as 多) to what extent; how 火车站离这儿好远？ Huǒchēzhàn lí zhèr hǎo yuǎn？ How far is the railway station from here? 11 adverb (used before indefinite numbers) quite a few 好几个 hǎojǐgè quite a few 好几天 hǎojǐtiān quite a few days 好半天 hǎobàntiān quite a while 12 dialect may; can; should 我好进来吗？ Wǒ hǎo jìnlai ma？ May I come in? 时间不早了, 你好走了。 Shíjiān bù zǎo le, nǐhǎo zǒu le. It's getting late. You ought to get going. See 好hào</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>坏</headword>
		<pron tones="huai4"/>
		<defn>1 bad; harmful 坏习惯 huài xíguàn bad habit 坏透了 huài tòule downright bad; rotten to the core 坏天气 huài tiānqì foul weather 坏书 huài shū a harmful book 2 become or make bad; ruin; spoil 鱼坏了。 Yú huài le. The fish has gone bad. 身体坏 Shēntǐ huài be in poor health 他胃口坏了。 Tā wèikǒu huài le. He has lost his appetite. 看小字会看坏眼睛的。 Kàn xiǎozì huì kàn huài yǎnjing de. Small type hurts the eyes. 雹子把庄稼砸坏了。 Báozi bǎ zhuāngjia zá huài le. The hail damaged the crop. 肚子吃坏了 Dùzi chī huài le have an upset stomach 3 (used after certain verbs or adjectives) extremely 吓坏了 xiàhuài le be badly scared 气坏了 qì huài le be beside oneself with rage 乐坏了 lèhuàile be wild with joy 累坏了 lèi huài le be dead tired; be dog-tired 4 evil idea; dirty trick ▶ 使坏 shǐhuài</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>帅</headword>
		<pron tones="shuai4"/>
		<defn>1 handsome 2 graceful 3 smart 4 commander in chief 5 (coll.) cool! 6 sweet!</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>丑</headword>
		<pron tones="chou3"/>
		<defn>1 ugly; unsightly; hideous 长得不丑 zhǎng de bù chǒu not bad-looking 2 disgraceful; shameful; scandalous 这种事太丑了, 不要说出去。 Zhèzhǒng shì tài chǒu le, bùyào shuō chūqu. This is really disgraceful. Don't breathe a word of it to anyone.</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>软件</headword>
		<pron tones="ruan3jian4"/>
		<defn>computer software</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>硬件</headword>
		<pron tones="ying4jian4"/>
		<defn>computer hardware</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>智能手机</headword>
		<pron tones="zhi4neng2shou3ji1"/>
		<defn>smartphone</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>笔记本电脑</headword>
		<pron tones="bi3ji4ben3dian4nao3"/>
		<defn>notebook computer</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>充电器</headword>
		<pron tones="chong1dian4qi4"/>
		<defn>charger</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>智能电视</headword>
		<pron tones="zhi4neng2dian4shi4"/>
		<defn>Smart TV</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>牌子</headword>
		<pron tones="pai2zi5"/>
		<defn>NOUN brand</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>华为</headword>
		<pron tones="Hua2wei2"/>
		<defn>Huawei (brand)</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>三星</headword>
		<pron tones="san1xing1"/>
		<defn>NOUN Samsung</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>小米</headword>
		<pron tones="Xiao3mi3"/>
		<defn>Xiaomi, Chinese electronics company founded in 2010</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>索尼</headword>
		<pron tones="Suo3ni2"/>
		<defn>Sony</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>博客</headword>
		<pron tones="bo2ke4"/>
		<defn>computing blog; weblog</defn>
	</card>
	<card>
		<headword>邮件</headword>
		<pron tones="you2jian4"/>
		<defn>postal matter; post; mail 挂号邮件 guàhào yóujiàn registered post 航空邮件 hángkōng yóujiàn air mail 小包邮件 xiǎobāo yóujiàn a postal packet 早班邮件几点到？ Zǎobān yóujiàn jǐ diǎn dào？ When does the morning post come in? 末班邮件几点走? Mò bān yóujiàn jǐ diǎn zǒu？ When does the last post go out? 今天的邮件量特别大。 Jīntiān de yóujiàn liàng tèbié dà. There's an unusually heavy post (or mail) today.</defn>
	</card>
</cards>